[
    {
        "question": "5 HR 20 MIN 20 SEC corresponds to a longitude difference of ;\n",
        "answer": "80\u00b005'\n",
        "choiceone": "81\u00b010'\n",
        "choicetwo": "78\u00b045'\n",
        "choicethree": "75\u00b000'\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "265 US-GAL equals ; ( Specific gravity 0.80 )\n",
        "answer": "803 kg.\n",
        "choiceone": "895 kg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "940 kg.\n",
        "choicethree": "862 kg.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "730 ft/min equals ;\n",
        "answer": "3.7 m/sec\n",
        "choiceone": "2.2 m/sec\n",
        "choicetwo": "5.2 m/sec\n",
        "choicethree": "1.6 m/sec\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-1828A and the data for 1215 UTC )\n MN TN\n R348\n 17\u00b0\n 129 NM\n 135 NM\n Annex 061-1828A\n 1215 UTC LAJES VORTAC ( 38\u00b046'N 027\u00b005'W ) RMI reads 178\u00b0 , range 135 NM. Calculate the aircraft position at 1215\nUTC ?\n",
        "answer": "40\u00b055'N 027\u00b055'W\n",
        "choiceone": "41\u00b005'N 027\u00b050'W\n",
        "choicetwo": "41\u00b000'N 028\u00b010'W\n",
        "choicethree": "40\u00b050'N 027\u00b040'W\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-1828A and the data for 1300 UTC )\n True North\n 37\u00b030'N\n W/V\n 360\u00b0/30 kt\n 021\u00b030'W 136\u00b0T\n Birim \u00f6l\u00e7\u00fc = 60 NM\n Annex 061-1828A\n 1300 UTC DR position 37\u00b030'N 021\u00b030'W alter heading PORT SANTO NDB ( 33\u00b003'N 016\u00b023'W ) , TAS 450 kt , Forecast\nW/V 360\u00b0/30 kt. Calculate the ETA at PORT SANTO NDB ?\n",
        "answer": "1348\n",
        "choiceone": "1341\n",
        "choicetwo": "1344\n",
        "choicethree": "1354\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1 : 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 1.5 inches ( one inch equals 2.54 centimetres ) , the\ndistance from A to B in NM is ;\n",
        "answer": "20.6\n",
        "choiceone": "38.1\n",
        "choicetwo": "44.5\n",
        "choicethree": "54.2\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A chart has the scale 1 : 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 3.8 cm , the distance from A to B in NM is ;\n",
        "answer": "20.5\n",
        "choiceone": "44.5\n",
        "choicetwo": "38.1\n",
        "choicethree": "54.2\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A course of 120\u00b0( T ) is drawn between \u201cX\u201d ( 61\u00b030'N ) and \u201cY\u201d ( 58\u00b030'N ) on a Lambert Conformal conic chart with a\nscale of 1 : 1 000 000 at 60\u00b0N. The chart distance between \u201cX\u201d and \u201cY\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "66.7 cm\n",
        "choiceone": "36.0 cm\n",
        "choicetwo": "33.4 cm\n",
        "choicethree": "38.5 cm\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A definition of a Magnetic Track angle is ;\n",
        "answer": "The direction of a line referenced to Magnetic North.\n",
        "choiceone": "The direction of the longitudinal axis of an aircraft referenced to Magnetic North.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The direction of the longitudinal axis of an aircraft referenced to Compass North.\n",
        "choicethree": "The direction of a line referenced to the isogonic line to the Magnetic pole. Compass North.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A direct Mercator graticule is based on a projection that is ;\n",
        "answer": "cylindrical.\n",
        "choiceone": "spherical.\n",
        "choicetwo": "conical.\n",
        "choicethree": "concentric.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A direct reading compass should be swung when ;\n",
        "answer": "there is a large , and permanent , change in magnetic latitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "there is a large change in magnetic longitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the aircraft is stored for a long period and is frequently moved.\n",
        "choicethree": "the aircraft has made more than a stated number of landings.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flight is to be made from \u201cA\u201d 49\u00b0S 180'E/W to \u201cB\u201d 58\u00b0S 180'E/W. The distance in kilometres from \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d is\napproximately ;\n",
        "answer": "1000.\n",
        "choiceone": "804.\n",
        "choicetwo": "540.\n",
        "choicethree": "1222.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A great circle intersects the equator in 030\u00b0W with a great circle direction of 035\u00b0( T ). An aircraft tracking the great circle\nwill reach the maximum Northern/Southern latitude in position ;\n",
        "answer": "( 55\u00b0N , 060\u00b0E ).\n",
        "choiceone": "( 55\u00b0S , 060\u00b0E ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "( 35\u00b0N , 120\u00b0W ).\n",
        "choicethree": "( 35\u00b0S , 120\u00b0W ).\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A great circle on the Earth running from the North Pole to the South Pole is called ;\n",
        "answer": "a meridian.\n",
        "choiceone": "a parallel of latitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a difference of longitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "a longitude.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A great circle track crosses the equator at 30\u00b0W has an initial track of 035\u00b0T. It\u2019s highest or lowest North/South point is ;\n",
        "answer": "55\u00baN 060\u00baE.\n",
        "choiceone": "55\u00baS 060\u00baW.\n",
        "choicetwo": "35\u00baN 150\u00baW.\n",
        "choicethree": "35\u00baS 150\u00baE.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A great circle track joins position A ( 59\u00b0S 141\u00b0W ) and B ( 61\u00b0S 148\u00b0W ). What is the difference between the great circle\ntrack at A and B ?\n",
        "answer": "It increases by 6\u00b0.\n",
        "choiceone": "It decreases by 3\u00b0.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It increases by 3\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "It decreases by 6\u00b0.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ground feature appears 30\u00b0 to the left of the centre line of the CRT of an airborne weather radar. If the heading of the\naircraft is 355\u00b0 ( M ) and the magnetic variation is 15\u00b0 East , the true bearing of the aircraft from the feature is ;\n",
        "answer": "160\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "130\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "310\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "220\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ground feature was observed on a relative bearing of 315\u00b0 and 3 MIN later on a relative bearing of 270\u00b0. The W/V is calm\n, aircraft GS 180 kt. What is the minimum distance between the aircraft and the ground feature ?\n",
        "answer": "9 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "6 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "12 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ground feature was observed on a relative bearing of 325\u00b0 and five minutes later on a relative bearing of 280\u00b0. The aircraft\nheading was 165\u00b0 ( M ) , variation 25\u00b0W , drift 10\u00b0Right and GS 360 kt. When the relative bearing was 280\u00b0 , the distance and true\nbearing of the aircraft from the feature was ;\n",
        "answer": "30 NM and 240\u00b0.\n",
        "choiceone": "30 NM and 060\u00b0.\n",
        "choicetwo": "40 NM and 290\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "40 NM and 110\u00b0.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Lambert conformal conic chart has a constant of the cone of 0.75. The initial course of a straight line track drawn on this\nchart from A ( 40\u00b0N 050\u00b0W ) to B is 043\u00b0( T ) at A , course at B is 055\u00b0( T ). What is the longitude of B ?\n",
        "answer": "34\u00b0W\n",
        "choiceone": "41\u00b0W\n",
        "choicetwo": "36\u00b0W\n",
        "choicethree": "38\u00b0W\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Lambert conformal conic chart has a constant of the cone of 0.80. A straight line course drawn on this chart from A ( 53\u00b0N\n004\u00b0W ) to B is 080\u00b0 at A , course at B is 092\u00b0 ( T ). What is the longitude of B ?\n",
        "answer": "011\u00b0E\n",
        "choiceone": "019\u00b0E\n",
        "choicetwo": "009\u00b036'E\n",
        "choicethree": "008\u00b0E\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Lambert conformal conic projection , with two standard parallels ;\n",
        "answer": "the scale is only correct along the standard parallels.\n",
        "choiceone": "shows all great circles as straight lines.\n",
        "choicetwo": "shows lines of longitude as parallel straight lines.\n",
        "choicethree": "the scale is only correct at parallel of origin.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A line drawn on a chart which joins all points where the value of magnetic variation is zero is called an ;\n",
        "answer": "agonic line.\n",
        "choiceone": "isotach.\n",
        "choicetwo": "aclinic line.\n",
        "choicethree": "isogonal.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Mercator chart has a scale at the equator = 1 : 3 704 000. What is the scale at latitude 60\u00b0 S ?\n",
        "answer": "1 : 1 852 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 3 208 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 7 408 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 185 200\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A nautical mile is ;\n",
        "answer": "1852 metres.\n",
        "choiceone": "1500metres.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1012 metres.\n",
        "choicethree": "1609 metres.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A negative ( westerly ) magnetic variation signifies that ;\n",
        "answer": "True North is East of Magnetic North.\n",
        "choiceone": "Compass North is East of Magnetic North.\n",
        "choicetwo": "True North is West of Magnetic North.\n",
        "choicethree": "Compass North is West of Magnetic North.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A pilot accidently turning OFF the IRS in flight , and then turns it back ON a few moments later. Following this incident ;\n",
        "answer": "it can only be used for attitude reference.\n",
        "choiceone": "everything returns to normal and is usable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the IRS is usable in NAV MODE after a position update.\n",
        "choicethree": "no useful information can be obtained from the IRS.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A rhumb line from a position 86\u00b0N 30\u00b0W has an initial track of 085\u00b0T is it ;\n",
        "answer": "a spiral to the North pole.\n",
        "choiceone": "a random northerly track to the pole.\n",
        "choicetwo": "initially North 86\u00baN and 180\u00ba later South of 86\u00baN.\n",
        "choicethree": "a small circle north of 86\u00baN.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Rhumb line is ;\n",
        "answer": "a line on the surface of the earth cutting all meridians at the same angle.\n",
        "choiceone": "the shortest distance between two points on a Polyconic projection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "any straight line on a Lambert projection.\n",
        "choicethree": "a line convex to the nearest pole on a Mercator projection.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A rhumb line on a Direct Mercator chart appears as a ;\n",
        "answer": "straight line.\n",
        "choiceone": "complex curve.\n",
        "choicetwo": "small circle concave to the nearer pole.\n",
        "choicethree": "curve convex to the nearer pole.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ring laser gyro is ;\n",
        "answer": "a device which measures angular movements.\n",
        "choiceone": "a device which measures the earth rate precession.\n",
        "choicetwo": "used for stabilising the INS platform.\n",
        "choicethree": "an optical accelerometers.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A route is flown from ( 80\u00b0S , 100\u00b0W ) to ( 80\u00b0S , 140\u00b0E ). At 160\u00b0W the Grid Track ( GT ) and True Track ( TT ) on a\nPolar Stereographic chart with a grid orientated on the 180\u00ba meridian are respectively ;\n",
        "answer": "290\u00ba(G) and 270\u00ba(T).\n",
        "choiceone": "270\u00ba(G) and 110\u00ba(T).\n",
        "choicetwo": "270\u00ba(G) and 290\u00ba(T).\n",
        "choicethree": "110\u00ba(G) and 270\u00ba(T).\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A route is flown from ( 80\u00b0S , 100\u00b0W ) to ( 80\u00b0S , 140\u00b0E ). At 180\u00b0E/W the Grid Track ( GT ) and True Track ( TT ) on a\nPolar Stereographic chart , whose grid is aligned with the Greenwich meridian , are respectively ;\n",
        "answer": "110\u00ba(G) and 290\u00ba(T).\n",
        "choiceone": "290\u00ba(G) and 110\u00ba(T).\n",
        "choicetwo": "250\u00ba(G) and 070\u00ba(T).\n",
        "choicethree": "070\u00ba(G) and 250\u00ba(T).\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A route is flown from ( 85\u00b0S , 100\u00b0E ) to ( 85\u00b0S , 140\u00b0W ). At 160\u00b0E the Grid Track ( GT ) and True track ( TT ) on a Polar\nStereographic chart with a grid orientated on the 180\u00ba meridian are respectively ;\n",
        "answer": "070\u00ba(G) and 090\u00ba(T).\n",
        "choiceone": "090\u00ba(G) and 070\u00ba(T).\n",
        "choicetwo": "090\u00ba(G) and 250\u00ba(T).\n",
        "choicethree": "250\u00ba(G) and 090\u00ba(T).\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A route is flown from ( 85\u00b0S , 100\u00b0E ) to ( 85\u00b0S , 140\u00b0W ). At 180\u00b0E/W the Grid Track ( GT ) and True Track ( TT ) on a\nPolar Stereographic chart , whose grid is aligned with the Greenwich meridian , are respectively ;\n",
        "answer": "250\u00ba(G) and 070\u00ba(T).\n",
        "choiceone": "070\u00ba(G) and 250\u00ba(T).\n",
        "choicetwo": "290\u00ba(G) and 110\u00ba(T).\n",
        "choicethree": "110\u00ba(G) and 290\u00ba(T).\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A straight line drawn on a chart measures 4.63 cm and represents 150 NM. The chart scale is ;\n",
        "answer": "1 : 6 000 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 3 000 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 5 000 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 1 000 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A straight line from A ( 53\u00baN , 155\u00baW ) to B ( 53\u00baN , 170\u00baE ) is drawn on a Lambert Conformal conical chart with standard\nparallels at 50\u00baN and 56\u00baN. When passing the meridian 175\u00baE , the True Track is ;\n",
        "answer": "260.0\u00ba\n",
        "choiceone": "100.0\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "102.5\u00ba\n",
        "choicethree": "257.5\u00ba\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A straight line from A ( 53\u00baS , 155\u00baE ) to B ( 53\u00baS , 170\u00baW ) is drawn on a Lambert Conformal conical chart with standard\nparallels at 50\u00baS and 56\u00baS. When passing 175\u00baW , the True Track is ;\n",
        "answer": "078.0\u00ba\n",
        "choiceone": "282.0\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "102.0\u00ba\n",
        "choicethree": "258.0\u00ba\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A straight line from A ( 75\u00baN , 120\u00baE ) to B ( 75\u00baN , 160\u00baE ) is drawn on a Polar Stereographic chart. When passing the\nmeridian 155\u00baE , the True Track is ;\n",
        "answer": "105\u00ba\n",
        "choiceone": "075\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "255\u00ba\n",
        "choicethree": "285\u00ba\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A straight line from A ( 75\u00baS , 120\u00baE ) to B ( 75\u00baS , 160\u00baE ) is drawn on a Polar Stereographic chart. When passing the\nmeridian 155\u00baE , the True Track is ;\n",
        "answer": "075\u00ba\n",
        "choiceone": "105\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "095\u00ba\n",
        "choicethree": "255\u00ba\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A straight line is drawn on a Lamberts conformal conic chart between two positions of different longitude. The angular\ndifference between the initial true track and the final true track of the line is equal to ;\n",
        "answer": "chart convergency.\n",
        "choiceone": "earth convergency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "difference in longitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "conversion angle.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A straight line on a chart 4.89 cm long represents 185 NM. The scale of this chart is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "1 : 7 000 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 3 500 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 6 000 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 5 000 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A straight line on a Lambert Conformal Projection chart for normal flight planning purposes ;\n",
        "answer": "is approximately a Great Circle.\n",
        "choiceone": "is a Rhumb line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is a Loxodromic line.\n",
        "choicethree": "can only be a parallel of latitude.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A useful method of a pilot resolving , during a visual flight , any uncertainty in the aircraft\u2019s position is to maintain visual\ncontact with the ground and ;\n",
        "answer": "set heading towards a line feature such as a coastline , motorway , river or railway.\n",
        "choiceone": "fly the reverse of the heading being flown prior to becoming uncertain until a pinpoint is obtained.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fly expanding circles until a pinpoint is obtained.\n",
        "choicethree": "fly reverse headings and associated timings until the point of departure is regained.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR is situated at position ( N55\u00b026' , W005\u00b042' ). The variation at the VOR is 9\u00b0W. The position of the aircraft is\n( N60\u00b000'N , W010\u00b000' ). The variation at the aircraft-position is 11\u00b0W. The initial TT-angle of the great circle from the aircraft\nposition to the VOR is 101.5\u00b0. Which radial is the aircraft on ?\n",
        "answer": "294 North\n",
        "choiceone": "278\n",
        "choicetwo": "276 Magnetic\n",
        "choicethree": "296 005\u00b042'W\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A VOR is situated at position ( 74\u00baN , 094\u00baW ) , local variation is 50\u00baW. A Polar Stereographic chart supplied with a\nGreenwich grid is used for navigation. To proceed along ( magnetic ) radial 238 inbound an aircraft has to follow a Grid Track of ;\n",
        "answer": "103\u00ba\n",
        "choiceone": "013\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "283\u00ba\n",
        "choicethree": "193\u00ba\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 8 )\n Image 8\n After 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH the aircraft is 3 NM South of the intended track and 2.5 NM ahead\nof the dead reckoning position. To reach destination B from this position , the TH should be ;\n",
        "answer": "292\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "258\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "287\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "280\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "After alignment of the stable platform of an Inertial Navigation System , the output data from the platform is ;\n",
        "answer": "acceleration north/south and east/west , attitude and true heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "latitude , longitude and attitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "acceleration north/south and east/west and true heading.\n",
        "choicethree": "latitude , longitude and true heading.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "After alignment of the stable platform of the Inertial Navigation System , the output data from the INS computer to the\nplatform is ;\n",
        "answer": "rate corrections to the gyros.\n",
        "choiceone": "accelerations from the accelerometers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "latitude and longitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "attitude.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeronautical chart is conformal when ;\n",
        "answer": "at any point the scale over a short distance in the direction of the parallel is equal to the scale in the direction\n of the meridian and the meridians are perpendicular to the parallels.\n",
        "choiceone": "every great circle is represented by a straight line in the map.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the meridians and parallels are perpendicular to each other.\n",
        "choicethree": "the map is an equidistant normal projection.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane flies from A ( 59\u00b0S 142\u00b0W ) to B ( 61\u00b0S 148\u00b0W ) with a TAS of 480 kt. The autopilot is engaged and coupled\nwith an Inertial Navigation System in which AB track is active. On route AB , the true track ;\n",
        "answer": "increases by 5\u00b0. 148\u00b000'W\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases by 6\u00b0. 142\u00b000'W\n",
        "choicetwo": "varies by 10\u00b0. A\n",
        "choicethree": "varies by 4\u00b0. 59\u00b0S\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane is flying at TAS 180 kt on a track of 090\u00b0. The W/V is 045\u00b0 / 50kt. How far can the aeroplane fly out from its\nbase and return in one hour ?\n",
        "answer": "85 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "88 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "176 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "56 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Agonic line is a line that connects ;\n",
        "answer": "positions that have 0\u00b0 variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "points of equal magnetic dip.\n",
        "choicetwo": "positions that have the same variation.\n",
        "choicethree": "points of equal magnetic horizontal field strength.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL120 , IAS 200 kt , OAT \u20135\u00b0 and wind component +30 kt , is required to reduce speed in order to cross a\nreporting point 5 MIN later than planned. Assuming flight conditions do not change , when 100 NM from the reporting point IAS\nshould be reduced to ;\n",
        "answer": "159 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "169 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "165 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "174 kt.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL140 , IAS 210 kt , OAT \u20135\u00b0C and wind component minus 35 kt , is required to reduce speed in order to\ncross a reporting point 5 MIN later than planned. Assuming that flight conditions do not change , when 150 NM from the reporting\npoint the IAS should be reduced by ;\n",
        "answer": "20 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "15 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "30 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "25 kt.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL290 is required to commence descent when 50 NM from a VOR and to cross that VOR at FL80. Mean GS\nduring descent is 271 kt. What is the minimum rate of descent required ?\n",
        "answer": "1900 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "1700 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "1800 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "2000 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL310 , M0.83 , temperature \u201330\u00b0C , is required to reduce speed in order to cross a reporting point five\nminutes later than planned. Assuming that a zero wind component remains unchanged , when 360 NM from the reporting point Mach\nNumber should be reduced to ;\n",
        "answer": "M0.74\n",
        "choiceone": "M0.80\n",
        "choicetwo": "M0.76\n",
        "choicethree": "M0.78\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL330 is required to commence descent when 65 NM from a VOR and to cross the VOR at FL100. The mean\nGS during the descent is 330 kt. What is the minimum rate of descent required ?\n",
        "answer": "1950 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "1750 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "1650 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "1850 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL350 is required to commence descent when 85 NM from a VOR and to cross the VOR at FL80. The mean\nGS for the descent is 340 kt. What is the minimum rate of descent required ?\n",
        "answer": "1800 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "1600 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "1900 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "1700 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL350 is required to cross a VOR/DME facility at FL110 and to commence descent when 100 NM from the\nfacility. If the mean GS for the descent is 335 kt , the minimum rate of descent required is ;\n",
        "answer": "1340 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "1240 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "1290 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "1390 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL350 is required to descend to cross a DME facility at FL80. Maximum rate of descent is 1800 FT/MIN and\nmean GS for descent is 276 kt. The minimum range from the DME at which descent should start is ;\n",
        "answer": "69 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "59 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "79 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "49 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL360 is required to descent to FL120. The aircraft should reach FL120 at 40 NM from the next waypoint. The\nrate of descent is 2000 ft/min. The average GS is 420 kt. The minimum distance from the next waypoint at which descent should start\nis ;\n",
        "answer": "124 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "236 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "166 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "88 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL370 is required to commence descent at 120 NM from a VOR and to cross the facility at FL130. If the mean\nGS for the descent is 288 kt , the minimum rate of descent required is ;\n",
        "answer": "960 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "920 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "890 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "860 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL370 is required to commence descent when 100 NM from a DME facility and to cross the station at FL120.\nIf the mean GS during the descent is 396 kt , the minimum rate of descent required is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "1650 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "1550 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "2400 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "1000 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL370 , M0.86 , OAT \u221244\u00b0C , headwind component 110 kt , is required to reduce speed in order to cross a\nreporting point 5 MIN later than planned. If the speed reduction were to be made 420 NM from the reporting point , what Mach\nNumber is required ?\n",
        "answer": "M0.81\n",
        "choiceone": "M0.73\n",
        "choicetwo": "M0.75\n",
        "choicethree": "M0.79\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at FL390 is required to descend to cross a DME facility at FL70. Maximum rate of descent is 2500 FT/MIN ,\nmean GS during descent is 248 kt. What is the minimum range from the DME at which descent should commence ?\n",
        "answer": "53 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "63 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "58 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "68 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at latitude 02\u00b020'N tracks 180\u00b0( T ) for 685 km. On completion of the flight the latitude will be ;\n",
        "answer": "03\u00b050'S\n",
        "choiceone": "04\u00b010'S\n",
        "choicetwo": "04\u00b030'S\n",
        "choicethree": "09\u00b005'S\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at latitude 10\u00b0North flies south at a groundspeed of 445 km/hr. What will be its latitude after 3 HR ?\n",
        "answer": "02\u00b000'S\n",
        "choiceone": "03\u00b050'S\n",
        "choicetwo": "12\u00b015'S\n",
        "choicethree": "22\u00b000'S\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at latitude 10\u00b0South flies north at a GS of 890 km/hr. What will its latitude be after 1.5 HR ?\n",
        "answer": "02\u00b000'N\n",
        "choiceone": "22\u00b000'N\n",
        "choicetwo": "03\u00b050'N\n",
        "choicethree": "12\u00b015'N\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft at position 60\u00b0N 005\u00b0W tracks 090\u00b0( T ) for 315 km. On completion of the flight the longitude will be ;\n",
        "answer": "000\u00b040'E\n",
        "choiceone": "005\u00b015'E\n",
        "choicetwo": "000\u00b015'E\n",
        "choicethree": "002\u00b010'W\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft departing A ( N40\u00ba00' E080\u00ba00' ) flies a constant true track of 270\u00ba at a ground speed of 120 kt. What are the\ncoordinates of the position reached in 6 HR ?\n",
        "answer": "N40\u00ba00' E064\u00ba20'\n",
        "choiceone": "N40\u00ba00' E070\u00ba30'\n",
        "choicetwo": "N40\u00ba00' E068\u00ba10'\n",
        "choicethree": "N40\u00ba00' E060\u00ba00'\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft departs from position A ( 04\u00b010'S 178\u00b022'W ) and flies northward following the meridian for 2950 NM. It then\nflies westward along the parallel of latitude for 382 NM to position B. The coordinates of position B are ?\n",
        "answer": "45\u00b000'N 172\u00b038'E\n",
        "choiceone": "53\u00b020'N 169\u00b022W\n",
        "choicetwo": "53\u00b020'N 172\u00b038'E\n",
        "choicethree": "45\u00b000'N 169\u00b022W\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft departs from Schiphol airport and flies to Santa Cruz in Bolivia ( South America ) via Miami in Florida. The\ndeparture time ( off blocks ) is 07:45 ST at the 10th of November , taxi time before take off at Schiphol is 25 minutes. The flight time\nto Miami over the Atlantic Ocean is 09 h 20 m. The total taxi time in Miami to and from the gate is 25 minutes. The time spend at the\ngate is 02 h 40 m. From Miami to Santa Cruz the airborne time is 06 h 30 m. Calculate the time and date of touch down in Santa Cruz\nin ST Bolivia if the difference between ST and UTC is 5 hours ;\n",
        "answer": "21:05 10th Nov.\n",
        "choiceone": "07:05 11th Nov.\n",
        "choicetwo": "22:05 10th Nov.\n",
        "choicethree": "09:05 11th Nov.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft equipped with an Inertial Navigation System ( INS ) flies with INS 1 coupled with autopilot 1. Both inertial\nnavigation systems are navigating from way-point A to B. The inertial systems\u201d Central Display Units ( CDU ) shows ;\n \u2212 XTK on INS 1 = 0\n \u2212 XTK on INS 2 = 8L ( XTK = cross track )\n From this information it can be deduced that ;\n",
        "answer": "at least one of the inertial navigation systems is drifting.\n",
        "choiceone": "only inertial navigation system No. 1 is drifting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only inertial navigation system No. 2 is drifting.\n",
        "choicethree": "the autopilot is unserviceable in NAV mode.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flies a great circle track from 56\u00b0N 070\u00b0W to 62\u00b0N 110\u00b0E. The total distance travelled is ?\n",
        "answer": "3720 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "2040 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "5420 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "1788 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flies at FL 250. OAT = \u201345\u00b0C. The QNH , given by a meteorological station with an elevation of 2830 ft , is 1033\nhPa. Calculate the clearance above a mountain ridge with an elevation of 20410 ft ;\n",
        "answer": "4200 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "3000 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "4600 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "3500 ft\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flies from waypoint 7 ( 63\u00b000'N , 073\u00b000'W ) to waypoint 8 ( 62\u00b000'N , 073\u00b000'W ). The aircraft position is\n( 62\u00b000'N , 073\u00b010'W ). The cross track distance in relation to the planned track is ;\n",
        "answer": "4.7 NM R\n",
        "choiceone": "8.8 NM L\n 73\u00b000'W\n",
        "choicetwo": "4.7 NM L\n",
        "choicethree": "8.8 NM R\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft flies the following rhumb line tracks and distances from position 04\u00b000'N 030\u00b000'W 600 NM South , then 600\nNM East , then 600 NM North , then 600 NM West. The final position of the aircraft is ;\n",
        "answer": "04\u00b000'N 029\u00b058'W\n",
        "choiceone": "04\u00b000'N 030\u00b000'W\n",
        "choicetwo": "03\u00b058'N 030\u00b002'W\n",
        "choicethree": "04\u00b000'N 030\u00b002'W\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft follows a great circle in the Northern Hemisphere. At a certain moment the aircraft is in the position on the great\ncircle where the great circle direction is 270\u00b0(T). Continuing on the great circle the ;\n",
        "answer": "track angle will decrease and the latitude will decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "track angle will increase and the latitude will decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "track angle will increase and the latitude will increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "track angle will decrease and the latitude will increase.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft follows a radial to a VOR/DME station. At 10:00 the DME reads 120 NM. At 10:03 the DME reads 105 NM.\nThe estimated time overhead the VOR/DME station is ;\n",
        "answer": "10:24\n",
        "choiceone": "10:18\n",
        "choicetwo": "10:21\n",
        "choicethree": "10:27\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft has to fly over a mountain ridge. The highest obstacle , indicated in the navigation chart , has an elevation of\n9800 ft. The QNH , given by a meteorological station at an elevation of 6200 ft , is 1022 hPa. The OAT = ISA+5\u00baC. Calculate the\napproximate indicated altitude to obtain a clearance of 2000 ft.\n",
        "answer": "Between 11500 ft and 11700 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "Between 11800 ft and 12000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Between 10900 ft and 11100 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "Between 11900 ft and 11200 ft.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft in the northern hemisphere is making an accurate rate one turn to the right. If the initial heading was 135\u00b0 , after\n30 seconds the direct reading magnetic compass should read ;\n",
        "answer": "more than 225\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "more or less than 225\u00b0 depending on the pendulous suspension used\n",
        "choicetwo": "225\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "less than 225\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft in the northern hemisphere makes an accurate rate one turn to the right/starboard. If the initial heading was 330\u00b0 ,\nafter 30 seconds of the turn the direct reading magnetic compass should read ;\n",
        "answer": "less than 060\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "more than 060\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "more or less than 060\u00b0 depending on the pendulous suspension used\n",
        "choicethree": "060\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is at position ( 53\u00baN , 006\u00baW ) and has a landmark at position ( 52\u00ba47'N , 004\u00ba45'W ) , with a relative bearing of\n060\u00ba. Given ;\n Compass Heading = 051\u00ba\n Variation = 16\u00baW\n Deviation = 2\u00baE\n What is the true bearing of the position line to be plotted from the landmark to the aircraft on a Lambert chart with standard\nparallels at 37\u00baN and 65\u00baN ?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "276\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "278\u00ba 006\u00b0W\n",
        "choicethree": "250\u00ba TRUE NORTH\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is 1003 hPa. The TAS is 100 kt , the\nhead wind component is 20 kt and the rate of climb is 500 ft/min. Top of climb is FL 050. At what distance from the airport will this\nbe achived ?\n",
        "answer": "7.2 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "6.6 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "10.8 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "8.8 NMs\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is 1003 hPa. The TAS is 100 kt , the\nhead wind component is 20 kt and the rate of climb is 1000 ft/min. Top of climb is FL 050. At what distance from the airport will this\nbe achived ?\n",
        "answer": "3.6 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "5.4 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "4.0 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "4.4 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is 1003 hPa. The TAS is 100 kt , the\nhead wind component is 20 kt and the rate of climb is 1000 ft/min. Top of climb is FL 100. At what distance from the airport will this\nbe achived ?\n",
        "answer": "10.3 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "11.1 NMs\n",
        "choicetwo": "13.3 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "15.4 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is 1023 hPa. The TAS is 100 kt , the\nhead wind component is 20 kt and the rate of climb is 1000 ft/min. Top of climb is FL 100. At what distance from the airport will this\nbe achieved ?\n",
        "answer": "11.1 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "16.6 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "10.3 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "13.3 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is descending down a 6% slope whilst maintaining a G/S of 300 kt. The rate of descent of the aircraft is\napproximately ;\n",
        "answer": "1800 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "3600 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "10800 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "900 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 5 )\n Image 5\n An aircraft is flying according the flight log at the Annex. After 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH the\naircraft is 3 NM North of the intended track and 2.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position. To reach destination B from this\nposition the TH should be ;\n",
        "answer": "112\u00ba\n",
        "choiceone": "078\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "090\u00ba\n",
        "choicethree": "107\u00ba\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 9 )\n Image 9\n An aircraft is flying according the flight log at the Annex. After 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH the\naircraft is 3 NM North of the intended track and 2.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position. To reach destination B from this\nposition the TH should be ;\n",
        "answer": "258\u00ba\n",
        "choiceone": "292\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "270\u00ba\n",
        "choicethree": "253\u00ba\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL100. The OAT = ISA \u2013 15\u00b0C. The QNH given by a station at an elevation 3000 ft is 1035 hPa.\nCalculate the approximate True Altitude ;\n",
        "answer": "10 200 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "7 200 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 000 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "9 600 ft\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL150 , with an outside air temperature of \u201330\u00b0 , above an airport where the elevation is 1660 ft and\nthe QNH is 993 hPa. Calculate the true altitude ; ( Assume 30 ft = 1 hPa )\n",
        "answer": "13 660 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "15 210 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "14 120 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "17 160 ft\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL180 and the outside air temperature is \u201330\u00b0C. If the CAS is 150 kt , what is the TAS ?\n",
        "answer": "195 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "155 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "115 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL 200. OAT = 0\u00b0C. When the actual air pressure on an airfield at MSL is placed in the subscale of\nthe altimeter the indicated altitude is 19300 ft. Calculate the aircraft\u2019s true altitude ;\n",
        "answer": "21.200 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "19.300 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "20.700 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "20.200 ft\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL200. The QNH , given by a meteorological station at an elevation of 1300 ft is 998.2 hPa.\nOAT = \u201340\u00baC. The elevation of the highest obstacle along the route is 8 000 ft. Calculate the aircraft\u2019s approximate clearance above\nthe highest obstacle on this route ;\n",
        "answer": "10.500 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "20.200 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "11.800 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "9.200 ft\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL250 , OAT = \u201345\u00b0C. The QNH , given by a station at MSL , is 993.2 hPa. Calculate the\napproximate True Altitude ;\n",
        "answer": "23400 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "26100 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "24000 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "25500 ft\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying from A to B a distance of 50 NM. The True course in the flight log is 090\u00ba , the forecast wind is\n225\u00ba(T)/15 kt and the TAS is 120 kt. After 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH the aircraft is 3 NM South of the\nintended track and 2.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position. To reach destination B from this position , the correction angle on\nthe heading should be ;\n",
        "answer": "17\u00ba\n",
        "choiceone": "10\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "5\u00ba\n",
        "choicethree": "12\u00ba\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying from A to B a distance of 50 NM. The True Course in the flight log is 270\u00ba , the forecast wind is\n045\u00ba(T)/15 kt and the TAS is 120 kt. After 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH the aircraft is 3 NM South of the\nintended track and 2.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position. To reach destination B from this position , the correction angle on\nthe heading should be ;\n",
        "answer": "17\u00ba\n",
        "choiceone": "12\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "5\u00ba\n",
        "choicethree": "14\u00ba\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying from A to B. The true course according to the flight log is 090\u00ba , the estimated wind is 225\u00ba(T)/15 kt and\nthe TAS is 120 kt. After 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH the aircraft is 3 NM South of the intended track and 2.5\nNM ahead of the dead reckoning position. The Track angle error ( TKE ) is ;\n",
        "answer": "5\u00baR\n",
        "choiceone": "17\u00baL\n",
        "choicetwo": "12\u00baR\n",
        "choicethree": "6\u00baL\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question see Europe Low Altitude Enroute Chart E(LO) 1A )\n INS R114 20.5 NM\n 28 NM\n ADN R294 10.5 NM\n Europe Low Altitude Enroute Chart E(LO) 1A\n An aircraft is flying from Inverness VORDME ( N57\u00b032.6'' , W004\u00b002.5W ) to Aberdeen VORDME ( N57\u00b018.6'' , W002\u00b0\n16.0''W ). At 1000 UTC the fix of the aircraft is determined by VORDME Inverness ; radial = 114 , DME-distance = 20.5 NM. At\n1006 UTC the fix of the aircraft is determined by VORDME Aberdeen ; radial = 294 , DME-distance = 10.5 NM. What is the average\nGS of the aircraft between 1000 UTC and 1006 UTC ?\n",
        "answer": "280 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "385 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "485 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying from SALCO to BERRY HEAD on Magnetic Track 007\u00ba , TAS 445 kt. The wind is 050\u00ba(T)/40 kt.\nVariation 5\u00baW , deviation +2\u00ba. At 1000 UTC the RB of locator PY is 311\u00ba. At 1003 UTC the RB of locator PY is 266\u00ba. Calculate the\ndistance of the aircraft from locator PY at 1003 UTC ;\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "23 NM TN\n",
        "choicetwo": "21 NM MN\n",
        "choicethree": "22 NM BHD\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying from SALCO to BERRY HEAD on Magnetic Track 007\u00ba , TAS 445 kt. The wind is 050\u00ba(T)/40 kt.\nVariation 5\u00baW , deviation +2\u00ba. At 1000 UTC the RB of locator PY is 311\u00ba. At 1003 UTC the RB of locator PY is 266\u00ba. Calculate the\nTrue bearing of locator PY at 1003 UTC from the aircraft ;\n",
        "answer": "272\u00ba(T) R007\n",
        "choiceone": "268\u00ba(T)\n",
        "choicetwo": "277\u00ba(T) True North\n",
        "choicethree": "275\u00ba(T) Magnetic North\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is flying with the aid of an inertial navigation system ( INS ) connected to the autopilot. The following two points\nhave been entered in the INS computer ;\n WPT 1 : 60\u00b0N 030\u00b0W\n WPT 2 : 60\u00b0N 020\u00b0W\n When 025\u00b0W is passed the latitude shown on the display unit of the inertial navigation system will be ;\n",
        "answer": "60\u00b005.7'N\n",
        "choiceone": "60\u00b011.0'N\n",
        "choicetwo": "60\u00b000.0'N\n",
        "choicethree": "59\u00b049.0'N\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is following a true track of 048\u00b0 at a constant TAS of 210 kt. The wind velocity is 350\u00b0 / 30 kt. The GS and drift\nangle are ;\n",
        "answer": "192 kt , 7\u00b0 right\n",
        "choiceone": "225 kt , 7\u00b0 left\n",
        "choicetwo": "192 kt , 7\u00b0 left\n",
        "choicethree": "200 kt , 3.5\u00b0 right\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is following the 45\u00b0N parallel of latitude. The track followed is a ;\n",
        "answer": "rhumb line.\n",
        "choiceone": "constant-heading track.\n",
        "choicetwo": "great circle.\n",
        "choicethree": "constant-drift track.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is in the position ( 86\u00b0N , 020\u00b0E ). When following a rhumb line track of 085\u00b0( T ) it will ;\n",
        "answer": "fly via a spiral to the North Pole.\n",
        "choiceone": "fly to the north via an arbitrary line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "follow a line which lies at first to the North of the parallel of 86\u00baN but after having passed a DL of 180\u00ba to the\n South of it.\n",
        "choicethree": "follow a small circle which lies to the North of the parallel of 86\u00baN.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is maintaining a 5.2% gradient is at 7 NM from the runway , on a flat terrain , its height is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "2210 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "3640 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "680 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "1890 ft.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is over position HO ( 55\u00b030'N 060\u00b015'W ) , where YYR VOR ( 53\u00b030'N 060\u00b015'W ) can be received. The\nmagnetic variation is 31\u00b0W at HO and 28\u00b0W at YYR. What is the radial from YYR ?\n",
        "answer": "028\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "031\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "208\u00b0 TN\n",
        "choicethree": "332\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is planned to fly from position \u201cA\u201d to position \u201cB\u201d , distance 250 NM at an average GS of 115 kt. It departs \u201cA\u201d\nat 0900 UTC. After flying 75 NM along track from \u201cA\u201d , the aircraft is 1.5 MIN behind planned time. Using the actual GS\nexperienced , what is the revised ETA at \u201cB\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "1115 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "1050 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "1044 UTC 75 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "1110 UTC\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is planned to fly from position \u201cA\u201d to position \u201cB\u201d , distance 320 NM , at an average GS of 180 kt. It departs \u201cA\u201d\nat 1200 UTC. After flying 70 NM along track from \u201cA\u201d , the aircraft is 3 MIN ahead of planned time. Using the actual GS\nexperienced , what is the revised ETA at \u201cB\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "1333 UTC 70 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "1401 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "1347 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "1340 UTC\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft is planned to fly from position \u201cA\u201d to position \u201cB\u201d , distance 480 NM at an average GS of 240 kt. It departs \u201cA\u201d\nat 1000 UTC. After flying 150 NM along track from \u201cA\u201d , the aircraft is 2 MIN behind planned time.Using the actual GS experienced\n, what is the revised ETA at \u201cB\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "1206\n",
        "choiceone": "1203\n",
        "choicetwo": "1153\n",
        "choicethree": "1157\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft must fly 2000 ft above an obstacle of which the elevation is 13 600 ft. The QHN at the nearest airfield is 991 hPa\n, the elevation is 1500 ft and the temperature is \u201320\u00b0C. Calculate the minimum altitude required.\n",
        "answer": "17 400 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "14 080 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 600 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "19 400 ft\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft obtains a relative bearing of 315\u00b0 from an NDB at 0830. At 0840 the relative bearing from the same NDB is 270\u00b0.\nAssuming no drift and a GS of 240 kt , what is the approximate range from the NDB at 0840 ?\n",
        "answer": "40 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "60 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "50 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "30 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft passes position A ( 60\u00b000'N 120\u00b000'W ) on route to position B ( 60\u00b000'N 140\u00b030'W ). What is the great circle\ntrack on departure from A ?\n",
        "answer": "279\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "261\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "270\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "288\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft takes-off from an airport 2 hours before sunset. The pilot flies a track of 090\u00b0 ( T ) , W/V 130\u00b0 / 20 kt , TAS 100\nkt. In order to return to the point of departure before sunset , the furthest distance which may be travelled is ;\n",
        "answer": "97 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "115 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "105 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "84 NM.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft takes off from the aerodrome of BRIOUDE ( altitude 1483 ft , QFE = 963 hPa , temperature = 32\u00b0C ). Five\nminutes later , passing 5 000 ft on QFE , the second altimeter set on 1013 hPa will indicate approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "6 500 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "4 000 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 800 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "6 300 ft.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft travels 2.4 statute miles in 47 seconds. What is its groundspeed ?\n",
        "answer": "160 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "183 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "209 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "131 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft travels 100 statute miles in 20 MIN , how long does it take to travel 215 NM ?\n",
        "answer": "50 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "100 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "80 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "90 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft travels from point A to point B , using the autopilot connected to the aircraft\u2019s inertial system. The coordinates of\nA ( 45\u00b0S 010\u00b0W ) and B ( 45\u00b0S 030\u00b0W ) have been entered. The true course of the aircraft on its arrival at B to the nearest degree , is ;\n",
        "answer": "277\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "263\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "270\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "284\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft was over \u201cA\u201d at 1435 hours flying direct to \u201cB\u201d.\n Given ;\n Distance \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d 2900 NM\n True airspeed 470 kt\n Mean wind component \u201cout\u201d +55 kt\n Mean wind component \u201cback\u201d \u201375 kt\n Safe endurance 9 HR 30 MIN\n The distance from \u201cA\u201d to the Point of Safe Return ( PSR ) \u201cA\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "2141 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "1611 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "2844 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "1759 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft was over \u201cA\u201d at 1435 hours flying direct to \u201cB\u201d. Given ;\n Distance \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d 2900 NM\n True airspeed 470 kt\n Mean wind component \u201cout\u201d +55 kt\n Mean wind component \u201cback\u201d \u201375 kt\n The ETA for reaching the Point of Equal Time ( PET ) between \u201cA\u201d and \u201cB\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "1657\n",
        "choiceone": "1744\n",
        "choicetwo": "1721\n",
        "choicethree": "1846\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft was over \u201cQ\u201d at 1320 hours flying direct to \u201cR\u201d. Given ;\n Distance \u201cQ\u201d to \u201cR\u201d 3016 NM\n True airspeed 480 kt\n Mean wind component \u201cout\u201d \u201390 kt\n Mean wind component \u201cback\u201d +75 kt\n Safe endurance 10:00 HR\n The distance from \u201cQ\u201d to the Point of Safe Return ( PSR ) \u201cQ\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "2290 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "1310 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "2370 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "1510 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aircraft was over \u201cQ\u201d at 1320 hours flying direct to \u201cR\u201d.\n Given ;\n Distance \u201cQ\u201d to \u201cR\u201d 3016 NM\n True airspeed 480 kt\n Mean wind component \u201cout\u201d \u201390 kt\n Mean wind component \u201cback\u201d +75 kt\n The ETA for reaching the Point of Equal Time ( PET ) between \u201cQ\u201d and \u201cR\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "1752\n",
        "choiceone": "1756\n",
        "choicetwo": "1742\n",
        "choicethree": "1820\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An island appears 30\u00b0 to the left of the centre line on an airborne weather radar display. What is the true bearing of the\naircraft from the island if at the time of observation the aircraft was on a magnetic heading ( MH ) of 020\u00b0 with the magnetic variation\n( VAR ) 25\u00b0W ?\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "205\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "195\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "145\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An island appears 30\u00b0 to the left of the centre line on an airborne weather radar display. What is the true bearing of the\naircraft from the island if at the time of observation the aircraft was on a magnetic heading of 276\u00b0 with the magnetic variation\n12\u00b0W ?\n",
        "answer": "054\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "234\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "318\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "038\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An island appears 30\u00b0 to the right of the centre line on an airborne weather radar display. What is the true bearing of the\naircraft from the island if at the time of observation the aircraft was on a magnetic heading ( MH ) of 355\u00b0 with the magnetic variation\n( VAR ) 15\u00b0E ?\n",
        "answer": "220\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "130\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "160\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "190\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An island appears 45\u00b0 to the right of the centre line on an airborne weather radar display. What is the true bearing of the\naircraft from the island if at the time of observation the aircraft was on a magnetic heading ( MH ) of 215\u00b0 with the magnetic variation\n( VAR ) 21\u00b0W ?\n",
        "answer": "059\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "239\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "329\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "101\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An island appears 60\u00b0 to the left of the centre line on an airborne weather radar display. What is the true bearing of the\naircraft from the island if at the time of observation the aircraft was on a magnetic heading ( MH ) of 276\u00b0 with the magnetic variation\n( VAR ) 10\u00b0E ?\n",
        "answer": "046\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "226\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "026\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "086\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An island is observed by weather radar to be 15\u00b0 to the left. The aircraft heading is 120\u00b0 ( M ) and the magnetic variation\n17\u00b0W. What is the true bearing of the aircraft from the island ?\n",
        "answer": "268\u00b0 17\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "302\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "122\u00b0\n TN ( True North )\n",
        "choicethree": "088\u00b0 MN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An island is observed to be 15\u00b0 to the left. The aircraft heading is 120\u00b0 ( M ) , variation 17\u00b0 ( W ). The bearing ( \u00b0T ) from\nthe aircraft to the island is ;\n",
        "answer": "088 TN ( True North )\n",
        "choiceone": "268\n",
        "choicetwo": "302\n",
        "choicethree": "122 MN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An island is observed to be 30\u00b0 to the right of the nose of the aircraft. The aircraft heading is 290\u00b0 ( M ) , variation 10\u00b0 ( E ).\nThe bearing ( \u00b0T ) from the aircraft to the island is ;\n",
        "answer": "330\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "270\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "310\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "250\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An NDB is located at position ( N55\u00b026' , W005\u00b042' ). The variation at the NDB is 9\u00b0W. The position of the aircraft is\n( 56\u00b000'N , 010\u00b000'W ). The variation at the aircraft position is 11\u00b0W. The initial TT of the great circle from the aircraft position to the\nNDB position , is 101.5\u00b0. What is the Magnetic Bearing of the NDB from the aircraft ?\n",
        "answer": "112.5\u00ba\n",
        "choiceone": "108.5\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "110.5\u00ba\n",
        "choicethree": "114.5\u00ba\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An Oblique Mercator projection is used specifically to produce ;\n",
        "answer": "charts of the great circle route between two points.\n",
        "choiceone": "radio navigational charts in equatorial regions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "plotting charts in equatorial regions.\n",
        "choicethree": "topographical maps of large east/ west extent.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An observer is situated on the parallel of 23.5\u00b0S. Which statement about the passage of the apparent sun in relation to this\nposition is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "It passes through the zenith once a year around December 22nd.\n",
        "choiceone": "It passes through the zenith twice a year around March 21st and September 23rd.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It passes through the zenith twice a year around June 21st and December 22nd.\n",
        "choicethree": "It passes through the zenith once a year around March 21st.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approximately how many nautical miles correspond to 12 cm on a map with a scale of 1 : 2 000 000 ?\n",
        "answer": "130\n",
        "choiceone": "150\n",
        "choicetwo": "329\n",
        "choicethree": "43\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "As the INS position of the departure aerodrome , coordinates 35\u00b032.7'N 139\u00b046.3'W are input instead of 35\u00b032.7'N\n139\u00b046.3'E. When the aircraft subsequently passes point 52\u00b0N 180\u00b0W , the longitude value shown on the INS will be ;\n",
        "answer": "099\u00b0 32.6'W\n",
        "choiceone": "080\u00b0 27.4'E\n",
        "choicetwo": "099\u00b0 32.6'E\n",
        "choicethree": "080\u00b0 27.4'W\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assume a Mercator chart. The distance between positions A and B , located on the same parallel and 10\u00b0 longitude apart , is\n6 cm. The scale at the parallel is 1 : 9 260 000. What is the latitude of A and B ?\n",
        "answer": "60\u00b0 N or S\n",
        "choiceone": "45\u00b0 N or S\n",
        "choicetwo": "30\u00b0 N or S\n",
        "choicethree": "0\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-1818A )\n Annex 061-1818A\n Assume a North polar stereographic chart whose grid is aligned with the Greenwich meridian. An aircraft flies from the\ngeographic North pole for a distance of 480 NM along the 110\u00b0E meridian , then follows a grid track of 154\u00b0 for a distance of 300\nNM. Its position is now approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "80\u00b000'N 080\u00b0E\n",
        "choiceone": "78\u00b045'N 087\u00b0E\n",
        "choicetwo": "79\u00b015'N 074\u00b0E\n",
        "choicethree": "70\u00b015'N 080\u00b0E GRID\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming mid-latitudes ( 40\u00b0 to 50\u00b0N/S ). At which time of year is the relationship between the length of day and night , as\nwell as the rate of change of declination of the sun , changing at the greatest rate ?\n",
        "answer": "Spring equinox and autumn equinox.\n",
        "choiceone": "Winter solstice and autumn equinox.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Summer solstice and spring equinox.\n",
        "choicethree": "summer solstice and winter solstice.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming zero wind , what distance will be covered by an aircraft descending 15 000 FT with a TAS of 320 kt and\nmaintaining a rate of descent of 3000 FT/MIN ?\n",
        "answer": "26.7 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "16.0 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "19.2 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "38.4 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At 00:00 Local Mean Time of an observer ;\n",
        "answer": "the mean sun is in transit with the observer\u2019s anti-meridian.\n",
        "choiceone": "the mean sun is in transit with the observer\u2019s meridian.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the apparent sun is in transit with the observer\u2019s meridian.\n",
        "choicethree": "the apparent sun is in transit with the observer\u2019s anti-meridian.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At 0020 UTC an aircraft is crossing the 310\u00b0 radial at 40 NM of a VOR/DME station. At 0035 UTC the radial is 040\u00b0 and\nDME distance is 40 NM. Magnetic variation is zero. The true track and ground speed are ;\n",
        "answer": "085\u00b0 - 226 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "088\u00b0 - 232 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "080\u00b0 - 226 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "090\u00b0 - 232 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At 0422 an aircraft at FL370 , GS 320 kt , is on the direct track to VOR \u201cX\u201d 185 NM distant. The aircraft is required to cross\nVOR \u201cX\u201d at FL80. For a mean rate of descent of 1800 FT/MIN at a mean GS of 232 kt , the latest time at which to commence descent\nis ;\n",
        "answer": "0445\n",
        "choiceone": "0448\n",
        "choicetwo": "0454\n",
        "choicethree": "0451\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At 10:15 the reading from a VOR/DME station is 211\u00b0/ 90 NM , at 10:20 the reading from the same VOR/DME station is\n211\u00b0/120 NM.\n Compass Heading = 200\u00ba\n CN TN\n Variation in the area = 31\u00baW\n Deviation = +1\u00ba 31\u00b0\n TAS = 390 kt MN\n The wind vector ( T ) is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "110\u00ba/70 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "100\u00ba/60 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "120\u00ba/50 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "110\u00ba/40 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At 47\u00b0 North the chart distance between meridians 10\u00b0 apart is 5 inches. The scale of the chart at 47\u00b0 North approximates ;\n",
        "answer": "1 : 6 000 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 3 000 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 8 000 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 2 500 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At 47\u00b0 North the chart distance between meridians 10\u00b0 apart is 12.7 cm. The scale of the chart at 47\u00b0 North approximates ;\n",
        "answer": "1 : 6 000 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 2 500 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 8 000 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 3 000 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At ( 54\u00b0N , 020\u00b0W ) the sun rises on November 28th at 09:01 UTC. At ( 44\u00b0N , 020\u00b0W ) the sun will rise ;\n",
        "answer": "earlier since the latter position lies further South.\n",
        "choiceone": "also at 09:01 UTC since both positions are situated on the same meridian.\n",
        "choicetwo": "later since the latter position lies further South.\n",
        "choicethree": "at 07:41 LMT.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At 60\u00b0 N the scale of a direct Mercator chart is 1 : 3 000 000. What is the scale at the equator ?\n",
        "answer": "1 : 6 000 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 3 000 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 1 500 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 3 500 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At a specific location , the value of magnetic variation ;\n",
        "answer": "varies slowly over time.\n",
        "choiceone": "depends on the magnetic heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "depends on the type of compass installed.\n",
        "choicethree": "depends on the true heading.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At latitude 60\u00b0N the scale of a Mercator projection is 1 : 5 000 000. The length on the chart between \u201cC\u201d N60\u00b0 E008\u00b0 and\n\u201cD\u201d N60\u00b0 W008\u00b0 is ;\n",
        "answer": "17.8 cm\n",
        "choiceone": "35.6 cm\n",
        "choicetwo": "16.2 cm\n",
        "choicethree": "19.2 cm\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 1 )\n TN\n MN 004\u00b0W\n 51\u00b0N\n 242\u00b0T\n TN MH 040\u00b0\n MN\n 8\u00b0 032\u00b0\n 250\u00b0M\n 50\u00b0N\n 030\u00b0\n RB 030\u00b0\n 49\u00b025'N\n 005\u00b0W\n 006\u00b0W\n 49\u00b0N 07\u00b030'W 007\u00b0W\n Image 1\n At reference. Magnetic heading of an aircraft is 040 degrees. On the airborne weather radar ( AWR ) display the relative\nbearing of the distance to the must southerly part of Lands End , ( approximate position : 50 03 N 005 40 W ) are 030 degrees R and\n80 NM. What is the position of the aircraft based on these observations ? The slant range correction and the map convergency\nbetween aircraft position and Lands End may be neglected.\n",
        "answer": "( 49 25 N 007 30 W )\n",
        "choiceone": "( 49 45 N 007 42 W )\n",
        "choicetwo": "( 48 50 N 006 22 W )\n",
        "choicethree": "( 49 35 N 007 35 W )\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the magnetic equator , when accelerating after take off on heading West , a direct reading pivot suspended compass ;\n",
        "answer": "indicates the correct heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "underreads the heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "indicates a turn to the south.\n",
        "choicethree": "overreads the heading.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what approximate date is the earth closest to the sun ( perihelion ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Beginning of January.\n",
        "choiceone": "Beginning of July.\n",
        "choicetwo": "End of June.\n",
        "choicethree": "End of March.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what approximate date is the earth furthest from the sun ( aphelion ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Beginning of July.\n",
        "choiceone": "End of September.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Beginning of January.\n",
        "choicethree": "End of December.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "ATT Mode of the Inertial Reference System ( IRS ) is a back-up mode providing ;\n",
        "answer": "only attitude and heading information.\n",
        "choiceone": "only attitude information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "navigation information.\n",
        "choicethree": "altitude , heading and position information.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Calculate the constant of the cone on a Lambert Chart given chart convergency between 010\u00b0E and 030\u00b0W as being 30\u00b0 ;\n",
        "answer": "0.75\n",
        "choiceone": "0.40\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.64\n",
        "choicethree": "0.50\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Calibrated Airspeed ( CAS ) is Indicated Airspeed ( IAS ) corrected for ;\n",
        "answer": "instrument error and position error.\n",
        "choiceone": "temperature and pressure error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "compressibility error.\n",
        "choicethree": "density.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Compass deviation is defined as the angle between ;\n",
        "answer": "Magnetic North and Compass North.\n",
        "choiceone": "True North and Magnetic North.\n",
        "choicetwo": "True North and Compass North.\n",
        "choicethree": "the horizontal and the total intensity of the earth\u2019s magnetic field.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-9437A )\n 275 268 280 306 0059 1114\n Annex 061-9437A\n Complete line 1 of the \u201cFLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG\u201d , positions \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d. What is the HDG\u00b0 ( M ) and ETA ?\n",
        "answer": "268\u00b0 - 1114 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "282\u00b0 - 1128 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "282\u00b0 - 1114 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "268\u00b0 - 1128 UTC\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-9437A )\n 188 193 228 262 0149 1239\n Annex 061-9437A\n Complete line 2 of the \u201cFLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG\u201d , positions \u201cC\u201d to \u201cD\u201d. What is the HDG\u00b0 ( M ) and ETA ?\n",
        "answer": "HDG 193\u00b0 - ETA 1239 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "HDG 183\u00b0 - ETA 1159 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "HDG 188\u00b0 - ETA 1229 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "HDG 193\u00b0 - ETA 1249 UTC\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-9437A )\n 95 105 490 448 0040 1205\n Annex 061-9437A\n Complete line 3 of the \u201cFLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG\u201d , positions \u201cE\u201d to \u201cF\u201d. What is the HDG\u00b0 ( M ) and ETA ?\n",
        "answer": "HDG 105\u00b0 - ETA 1205 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "HDG 095\u00b0 - ETA 1155 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "HDG 115\u00b0 - ETA 1145 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "HDG 106\u00b0 - ETA 1215 UTC\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-9437A )\n 354 344 470 418 0126 1336\n Annex 061-9437A\n Complete line 4 of the \u201cFLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG\u201d , positions \u201cG\u201d to \u201cH\u201d. What is the HDG\u00b0 ( M ) and ETA ?\n",
        "answer": "HDG 344\u00b0 - ETA 1336 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "HDG 034\u00b0 - ETA 1336 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "HDG 344\u00b0 - ETA 1303 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "HDG 354\u00b0 - ETA 1326 UTC\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-9437A )\n 320 337 173 170 0137 1422\n Annex 061-9437A\n Complete line 5 of the \u201cFLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG\u201d , positions \u201cJ\u201d to \u201cK\u201d. What is the HDG\u00b0 ( M ) and ETA ?\n",
        "answer": "HDG 337\u00b0 - ETA 1422 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "HDG 337\u00b0 - ETA 1322 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "HDG 320\u00b0 - ETA 1432 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "HDG 320\u00b0 - ETA 1412 UTC\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-9437A )\n 064 075 486 446 0107 1502\n Annex 061-9437A\n Complete line 6 of the \u201cFLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG\u201d , positions \u201cL\u201d to \u201cM\u201d. What is the HDG\u00b0 ( M ) and ETA ?\n",
        "answer": "HDG 075\u00b0 - ETA 1502 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "HDG 075\u00b0 - ETA 1452 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "HDG 070\u00b0 - ETA 1459 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "HDG 064\u00b0 - ETA 1449 UTC\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Complete the following statement regarding magnetic variation. The charted values of magnetic variation on earth normally\nchange annually due to ;\n",
        "answer": "magnetic pole movement causing numerical values at all locations to increase or decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "magnetic pole movement causing numerical values at all locations to increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a reducing field strength causing numerical values at all locations to decrease.\n",
        "choicethree": "an increasing field strength causing numerical values at all locations to increase.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Concerning direct reading magnetic compasses , in the northern hemisphere , it can be said that ;\n",
        "answer": "on an Easterly heading , a longitudinal acceleration causes an apparent turn to the North.\n",
        "choiceone": "on an Easterly heading , a longitudinal acceleration causes an apparent turn to the South.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on a Westerly heading , a longitudinal deceleration causes an apparent turn to the North.\n",
        "choicethree": "on a Westerly heading , a longitudinal acceleration causes an apparent turn to the South.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following factors that determine the accuracy of a DR position ;\n 1. The flight time since the last position update.\n 2. The accuracy of the forecasted wind.\n 3. The accuracy of the TAS.\n 4. The accuracy of the steered heading.\n Using the list above which of the following contains the most complete answer ?\n",
        "answer": "1 , 2 , 3 and 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 and 2.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 , 2 and 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 , 2 and 3.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the positions ( 00\u00baN/S , 000\u00baE/W ) and ( 00\u00baN/S , 180\u00baE/W ) on the ellipsoid. Which statement about the distances\nbetween these positions is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The route via the North Pole is shorter than the route along the equator.\n",
        "choiceone": "The route via the equator is shorter than the route via the South Pole.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The route via either pole and the route via the equator are of equal length.\n",
        "choicethree": "The route via the South Pole is shorter than the route via the North Pole.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Contour lines on aeronautical maps and charts connect points ;\n",
        "answer": "having the same elevation above sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "of equal latitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "having the same longitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "with the same variation.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deviation applied to magnetic heading gives ;\n",
        "answer": "compass heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "true heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic course.\n",
        "choicethree": "magnetic track.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deviation on the standby compass is ;\n",
        "answer": "dependent on the heading of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "independent of the latitude of the aircraft\u2019s position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "positive if the Compass North is to the west of Magnetic North.\n",
        "choicethree": "zero on the magnetic equator.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Double integration of the output from the east/west accelerometer of an inertial navigation system ( INS ) in the NAV\nMODE give ;\n",
        "answer": "distance east/west.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance north/south.\n",
        "choicetwo": "vehicle longitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "velocity east/west.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a low level flight 2 parallel roads that are crossed at right angles by an aircraft. The time between these roads can be\nused to check the aircraft ;\n",
        "answer": "groundspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "drift.\n",
        "choicethree": "track.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During approach the following data are obtained ;\n DME 12.0 NM , altitude 3000 ft\n DME 9.8 NM , altitude 2400 ft\n TAS = 160 kt , GS = 125 kt\n The rate of descent is ;\n",
        "answer": "570 ft/min\n",
        "choiceone": "730 ft/min\n",
        "choicetwo": "600 ft/min\n",
        "choicethree": "700 ft/min\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the initial alignment of an inertial navigation system ( INS ) the equipment ;\n",
        "answer": "will not accept a 10\u00b0 error in initial latitude but will accept a 10\u00b0 error in initial longitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "will not accept a 10\u00b0 error in initial latitude or initial longitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "will accept a 10\u00b0 error in initial latitude but will not accept a 10\u00b0 error in initial longitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "will accept a 10\u00b0 error in initial latitude and initial longitude.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a distance of 1860 NM between Q and R , a ground speed \u201cout\u201d of 385 kt , a ground speed \u201cback\u201d of 465 kt and an\nendurance of 8 HR ( excluding reserves ) the distance from Q to the point of safe return ( PSR ) is ;\n",
        "answer": "1685 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "1532 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "1865 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "930 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a landing on runway 23 ( 227\u00b0 magnetic ) surface W/V reported by the ATIS is 180 / 30 kt. VAR is 13\u00b0E. Calculate the\ncross wind component ;\n",
        "answer": "22 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "20 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "26 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "15 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "From Rakovnik ( 50\u00b0 05.9' N , 013\u00b0 41.5' E ) to Frankfurt FFM ( 50\u00b0 05.9' N , 008\u00b0 38.3' E ) the True Track of departure\nalong the straight line is 272.0\u00b0. The constant of the cone of this Lambert conformal projection is ;\n",
        "answer": "0.79\n 008\u00b038.3'E 013\u00b041.5'E\n",
        "choiceone": "0.40\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.20\n",
        "choicethree": "0.77\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "From the departure point , the distance to the point of equal time is ;\n",
        "answer": "inversely proportional to the sum of ground speed out and ground speed back.\n",
        "choiceone": "proportional to the sum of ground speed out and ground speed back.\n",
        "choicetwo": "inversely proportional to ground speed back.\n",
        "choicethree": "inversely proportional to the total distance to go.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Fuel flow per HR is 22 US-GAL , total fuel on board is 83 IMP GAL. What is the endurance ?\n",
        "answer": "4 HR 32 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "2 HR 15 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 HR 53 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "3 HR 12 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Geodetic latitude and geocentric latitude coincide ;\n",
        "answer": "at the Poles and on the equator.\n",
        "choiceone": "at 45\u00b0N/S.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only at the Poles.\n",
        "choicethree": "only on the equator.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n A polar stereographic chart whose grid is aligned with the zero meridian.\n Grid track 344\u00b0\n Longitude 115\u00b000'W\n Calculate the true course ?\n",
        "answer": "229\u00b0 Grid North\n",
        "choiceone": "279\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "049\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "099\u00b0 180\u00b0E/W\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n ETA to cross a meridian is 2100 UTC\n GS is 441 kt\n TAS is 491 kt\n At 2010 UTC , ATC requests a speed reduction to cross the meridian at 2105 UTC. The reduction to TAS will be\napproximately ;\n",
        "answer": "40 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "60 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "75 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "90 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n An aircraft is flying a track of 255\u00b0( M )\n 2254 UTC , it crosses radial 360\u00b0 from a VOR station\n 2300 UTC , it crosses radial 330\u00b0 from the same station\n At 2300 UTC , the distance between the aircraft and the station is ;\n",
        "answer": "the same as it was at 2254 UTC.\n",
        "choiceone": "less than it was at 2254 UTC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "randomly different than it was at 2254 UTC.\n",
        "choicethree": "greater than it was at 2254 UTC.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Aircraft height 2500 ft\n ILS GP angle 3\u00b0\n At what approximate distance from THR can you expect to capture the GP ?\n",
        "answer": "8.3 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "14.5 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "13.1 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "7.0 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n An aircraft is flying at FL100\n OAT = ISA \u2013 15\u00baC\n The QNH given by a meteorological station with an elevation of 100 ft below MSL is 1032 hPa\n 1 hPa = 27 ft\n Calculate the approximate True Altitude of this aircraft ;\n",
        "answer": "9.900 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "10.600 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "9.400 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "11.200 ft\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True course 300\u00b0\n drift 8\u00b0R CN\n variation 10\u00b0W TN\n deviation \u20134\u00b0\n Calculate the compass heading ; MN\n",
        "answer": "306\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "322\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "278\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "294\u00b0 4\u00b0 10\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n true track 070\u00b0\n variation 30\u00b0W\n deviation +1\u00b0\n CN TN\n drift 10\u00b0R\n Calculate the compass heading ;\n",
        "answer": "089\u00b0 MN\n",
        "choiceone": "100\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "091\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "101\u00b0 30\u00b0 HDG 306\u00baC\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n true track 352\u00b0\n variation 11\u00b0 W CN\n deviation is \u20135\u00b0 TN\n drift 10\u00b0R MN\n Calculate the compass heading ?\n",
        "answer": "358\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "025\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "018\u00b0 11\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "346\u00b0 5\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True course from A to B = 090\u00b0\n TAS = 460 kt\n W/V = 360 / 100 kt\n Average variation = 10\u00b0E\n Deviation = \u20132\u00b0\n Calculate the compass heading and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "070\u00b0 - 450 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "068\u00b0 - 460 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "078\u00b0 - 450 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "070\u00b0 - 453 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Runway direction 210\u00b0 ( M )\n Surface W/V 230\u00b0 ( M ) / 30 kt\n Calculate the cross-wind component ;\n",
        "answer": "10 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "19 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "13 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "16 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Runway direction 305\u00b0 ( M )\n Surface W/V 260\u00b0 ( M ) / 30 kt\n Calculate the cross-wind component ?\n",
        "answer": "21 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "18 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "24 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "27 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Pressure Altitude 29000 ft\n OAT \u201355\u00b0C\n Calculate the Density Altitude ?\n",
        "answer": "27500 ft.\n",
        "choiceone": "33500 ft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "31000 ft.\n",
        "choicethree": "26000 ft.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True Track 245\u00b0\n Drift 5\u00b0 right CN\n Variation 3\u00b0E\n Compass Hdg 242\u00b0 TN\n Calculate the deviation ;\n",
        "answer": "5\u00b0W\n",
        "choiceone": "1\u00b0E 5\u00b0 MN\n",
        "choicetwo": "11\u00b0E\n",
        "choicethree": "5\u00b0E 3\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 95 kt\n HDG ( T ) = 075\u00b0\n W/V = 310 / 20 kt\n Calculate the drift and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "9R - 108 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "8R - 104 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "10L - 104 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "9L - 105 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 140 kt\n HDG ( T ) = 005\u00b0\n W/V = 265 / 25kt\n Calculate the drift and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "10R - 146 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "9R - 140 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "11R - 140 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "11R - 142 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 190 kt\n HDG ( T ) = 355\u00b0\n W/V = 165 / 25kt\n Calculate the drift and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "1L - 215 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "1R - 175 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "1R - 165 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "1L - 225 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 205 kt\n HDG ( T ) = 180\u00b0\n W/V = 240 / 25 kt\n Calculate the drift and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "6L - 194 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "4L - 195 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "3L - 190 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "7L - 192 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 230 kt\n HDG ( T ) = 250\u00b0\n W/V = 205 / 10 kt\n Calculate the drift and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "2R - 223 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "1L - 225 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "1R - 221 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "2L - 224 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 250 kt\n HDG ( T ) = 029\u00b0\n W/V = 035 / 45 kt\n Calculate the drift and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "1L - 205 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "1L - 265 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "1R - 295 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "1R - 205 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 440 kt\n HDG ( T ) = 349\u00b0\n W/V = 040 / 40 kt\n Calculate the drift and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "4L - 415 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "5L - 385 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "2L - 420 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "6L - 395 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 465 kt\n HDG ( T ) = 124\u00b0\n W/V = 170 / 80 kt\n Calculate the drift and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "8L - 415 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "4L - 400 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "6L - 400 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "3L - 415 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Magnetic heading = 255\u00b0\n VAR = 40\u00b0W\n GS = 375 kt\n W/V = 235\u00b0( T ) / 120 kt\n Calculate the drift angle ?\n",
        "answer": "6\u00b0 left\n",
        "choiceone": "6\u00b0 right\n",
        "choicetwo": "3\u00b0 left\n",
        "choicethree": "9\u00b0 left\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 132 kt\n True HDG = 257\u00b0\n W/V = 095\u00b0 ( T ) / 35 kt\n Calculate the drift angle and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "4\u00b0R - 165 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "3\u00b0L - 166 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "2\u00b0R - 166 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "4\u00b0L - 167 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 140 kt\n True HDG = 302\u00b0\n W/V = 045\u00b0( T ) / 45 kt\n Calculate the drift angle and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "16\u00b0L - 156 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "9\u00b0R - 143 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "18\u00b0R - 146 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "9\u00b0L - 146 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 190 kt\n True HDG = 085\u00b0\n W/V = 110\u00b0( T ) / 50 kt\n Calculate the drift angle and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "8\u00b0L - 146 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0L - 145 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00b0L - 168 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "7\u00b0L - 156 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 235 kt\n HDG ( T ) = 076\u00b0\n W/V = 040 / 40kt\n Calculate the drift angle and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "7R - 204 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "5R - 207 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "5L - 255 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "7L - 269 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 270 kt\n True HDG = 145\u00b0\n Actual wind = 205\u00b0 ( T ) / 30 kt\n Calculate the drift angle and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "6\u00b0L - 256 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "6\u00b0R - 259 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "8\u00b0R - 261 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "6\u00b0R - 251 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 270 kt\n True HDG = 270\u00b0\n Actual wind 205\u00b0( T ) / 30 kt\n Calculate the drift angle and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "6\u00b0R - 259 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "6\u00b0R - 251 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "8\u00b0R - 259 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "6\u00b0L - 256 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 290 kt\n True HDG = 171\u00b0\n W/V = 310\u00b0( T ) / 30 kt\n Calculate the drift angle and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "4\u00b0L - 314 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0R - 310 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00b0R - 314 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "4\u00b0L - 310 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 470 kt\n True HDG = 317\u00b0\n W/V = 045\u00b0( T ) / 45 kt\n Calculate the drift angle and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "5\u00b0L - 470 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "5\u00b0R - 475 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "5\u00b0L - 475 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "3\u00b0R - 470 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 472 kt\n True HDG = 005\u00b0\n W/V = 110\u00b0( T ) / 50 kt\n Calculate the drift angle and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "6\u00b0L - 490 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "6\u00b0R - 462 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "6\u00b0L - 402 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "6\u00b0R - 490 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 485 kt\n True HDG = 226\u00b0\n W/V = 110\u00b0( T ) / 95 kt\n Calculate the drift angle and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "9\u00b0R - 533 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "8\u00b0L - 435 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "7\u00b0R - 531 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "9\u00b0R - 433 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Runway direction 230\u00b0( T )\n Surface W/V 280\u00b0( T ) / 40 kt\n Calculate the effective cross-wind component ; 280\u00b0\n",
        "answer": "31 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "21 kt WW\n",
        "choicetwo": "26 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "36 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Runway direction 083\u00b0( M )\n Surface W/V 035 / 35 kt\n Calculate the effective headwind component ;\n",
        "answer": "24 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "34 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "31 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "27 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 220 kt\n Magnetic course = 212 \u00ba\n W/V 160\u00ba( M ) / 50kt\n Calculate the GS ?\n",
        "answer": "186 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "290 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "246 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "250 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True Heading = 090\u00b0\n TAS = 200 kt\n W/V = 220\u00b0 / 30 kt\n Calculate the GS ?\n",
        "answer": "220 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "230 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "200 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True Heading = 180\u00b0\n TAS = 500 kt\n W/V 225\u00b0 / 100 kt\n Calculate the GS ?\n",
        "answer": "435 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "600 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "450 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "535 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 130 kt\n Track ( T ) = 003\u00b0\n W/V = 190 / 40 kt\n Calculate the HDG ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "001 - 170 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "357 - 168 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "002 - 173 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "359 - 166 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 155 kt\n Track ( T ) = 305\u00b0\n W/V = 160 / 18 kt\n Calculate the HDG ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "301 - 169 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "309 - 170 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "305 - 169 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "309 - 141 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 200 kt\n Track ( T ) = 073\u00b0\n W/V = 210 / 20 kt\n Calculate the HDG ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "077 - 214 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "075 - 213 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "079 - 211 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "077 - 210 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 200 kt\n Track ( T ) = 110\u00b0\n W/V = 015 / 40 kt\n Calculate the HDG ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "099 - 199 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "121 - 199 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "121 - 207 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "097 - 201 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 227 kt\n Track ( T ) = 316\u00b0\n W/V = 205 / 15 kt\n Calculate the HDG ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "312 - 232 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "311 - 230 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "310 - 233 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "313 - 235 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 270 kt\n Track ( T ) = 260\u00b0\n W/V = 275 / 30 kt\n Calculate the HDG ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "262 - 241 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "264 - 241 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "264 - 237 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "262 - 237 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 465 kt\n Track ( T ) = 007\u00b0\n W/V = 300 / 80 kt\n Calculate the HDG ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "358 - 428 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "017 - 490 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "001 - 435 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "357 - 502 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n FL250\n OAT \u201315 \u00baC\n TAS 250 kt\n Calculate the Mach No. ?\n",
        "answer": "0.40\n",
        "choiceone": "0.39\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.44\n",
        "choicethree": "0.42\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 485 kt\n OAT = ISA +10\u00b0C\n FL 410\n Calculate the Mach Number ?\n",
        "answer": "0.825\n",
        "choiceone": "0.87\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.90\n",
        "choicethree": "0.85\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS 487 kt , FL 330 , Temperature ISA + 15\n Calculate the MACH Number ?\n",
        "answer": "0.81\n",
        "choiceone": "0.76\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.78\n",
        "choicethree": "0.84\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True Track 245\u00b0\n Drift 5\u00b0 right TN\n Variation 3\u00b0 E\n Compass Hdg 242\u00b0 MN\n Calculate the Magnetic Heading ; CN\n",
        "answer": "237\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "253\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "247\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "243\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Maximum allowable crosswind component is 20 kt\n Runway 06 , RWY QDM 063\u00b0( M )\n Wind direction 100\u00b0( M )\n Calculate the maximum allowable wind speed ;\n",
        "answer": "33 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "26 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "37 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "25 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Maximum allowable tailwind component for landing 10 kt.\n Planned runway 05 ( 047\u00b0 magnetic )\n The direction of the surface wind reported by ATIS 210\u00b0\n Variation is 17\u00b0E\n Calculate the maximum allowable wind speed that can be accepted without exceeding the tailwind limit ;\n",
        "answer": "10 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "8 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "18 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "15 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n For take-off an aircraft requires a headwind component of at least 10 kt and has a cross-wind\n limitation of 35 kt\n The angle between the wind direction and the runway is 60\u00b0\n Calculate the minimum and maximum allowable wind speeds ;\n",
        "answer": "20 kt and 40 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "12 kt and 38 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 kt and 43 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "18 kt and 50 kt.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 90 kt\n HDG ( T ) = 355\u00b0\n W/V = 120 / 20 kt\n Calculate the Track ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "346 - 102 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "006 - 95 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "358 - 101 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "359 - 102 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 132 kt\n HDG ( T ) = 053\u00b0\n W/V = 205 / 15 kt\n Calculate the Track ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "050 - 145 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "051 - 144 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "052 - 143 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "057 - 144 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 135 kt\n HDG ( \u00b0T ) = 278\n W/V = 140 / 20 kt\n Calculate the Track ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "283 - 150 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "279 - 152 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "275 - 150 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "272 - 121 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 155 kt\n HDG ( T ) = 216\u00b0\n W/V = 090 / 60 kt\n Calculate the Track ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "231 - 196 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "224 - 175 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "226 - 186 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "222 - 181 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 170 kt\n HDG ( T ) = 100\u00b0\n W/V = 350 / 30 kt\n Calculate the Track ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "109 - 182 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "103 - 178 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "098 - 178 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "091 - 183 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 198 kt\n HDG ( \u00b0T ) = 180\n W/V = 359 / 25\n Calculate the Track ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "180 - 223 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "180 - 183 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "181 - 180 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "179 - 220 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 225 kt\n HDG ( \u00b0T ) = 123\u00b0\n W/V = 090 / 60kt\n Calculate the Track ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "134 - 178 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "128 - 180 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "120 - 190 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "134 - 188 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 480 kt\n HDG ( \u00b0T ) = 040\u00b0\n W/V = 090 / 60kt\n Calculate the Track ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "034 - 445 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "032 - 425 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "036 - 435 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "028 - 415 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 485 kt\n HDG ( T ) = 168\u00b0\n W/V = 130 / 75 kt\n Calculate the Track ( \u00b0T ) and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "174 - 428 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "175 - 432 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "175 - 420 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "173 - 424 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Course required = 085\u00b0( T )\n Forecast W/V 030 / 100 kt\n TAS = 470 kt\n Distance = 265 NM\n Calculate the true HDG and flight time ;\n",
        "answer": "075\u00b0 , 39 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "076\u00b0 , 34 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "095\u00b0 , 31 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "096\u00b0 , 29 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 125 kt\n True HDG = 355\u00b0\n W/V = 320\u00b0( T ) / 30kt\n Calculate the true track and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "005 - 102 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "002 - 98 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "345 - 100 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "348 - 102 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 370 kt\n True HDG = 181\u00b0\n W/V = 095\u00b0( T ) / 35 kt\n Calculate the true track and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "186 - 370 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "189 - 370 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "192 - 370 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "176 - 370 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 375 kt\n True HDG = 124\u00b0\n W/V = 130\u00b0( T ) / 55 kt\n Calculate the true track and GS ;\n",
        "answer": "123 - 320 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "125 - 322 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "125 - 318 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "126 - 320 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n M 0.80\n OAT \u201350\u00b0C\n FL 330\n GS 490 kt\n VAR 20\u00b0W\n Magnetic heading 140\u00b0\n Drift is 11\u00b0 Right\n Calculate the true W/V ?\n",
        "answer": "020\u00b0 / 95 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "200\u00b0 / 95 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "025\u00b0 / 47 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "025\u00b0 / 45 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Magnetic track = 075\u00b0\n HDG = 066\u00b0( M )\n VAR = 11\u00b0E\n TAS = 275 kt\n Aircraft flies 48 NM in 10 MIN\n Calculate the true W/V ?\n",
        "answer": "340\u00b0 / 45 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "210\u00b0 / 15 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "320\u00b0 / 50 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "180\u00b0 / 45 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Magnetic track = 210\u00b0\n Magnetic HDG = 215\u00b0\n VAR = 15\u00b0E\n TAS = 360 kt\n Aircraft flies 64 NM in 12 MIN\n Calculate the true W/V ?\n",
        "answer": "265\u00b0 / 50 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "195\u00b0 / 50 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "300\u00b0 / 30 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "235\u00b0 / 50 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n FL 350 , Mach 0.80 , OAT \u201355\u00b0C\n Calculate the values for TAS and local speed of sound ( LSS ) ?\n",
        "answer": "461 kt , LSS 576 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "461 kt , LSS 296 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "237 kt , LSS 296 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "490 kt , LSS 461 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True track 180\u00b0 TN\n MN\n Drift 8\u00b0R CN\n Compass heading 195\u00b0\n Deviation \u20132\u00b0 21\u00b0\n Calculate the variation ;\n",
        "answer": "21\u00b0W\n",
        "choiceone": "9\u00b0W\n",
        "choicetwo": "25\u00b0W\n",
        "choicethree": "5\u00b0W\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True Track 239\u00b0 , True Heading 229\u00b0 , TAS 555 kt , G/S 577 kt\n Calculate the wind velocity ;\n",
        "answer": "130\u00b0 / 100 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "165\u00b0 / 100 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "300\u00b0 / 100 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "310\u00b0 / 100 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True HDG = 002\u00b0 , TAS = 130 kt , Track ( T ) = 353\u00b0 , GS = 132 kt\n Calculate the W/V ;\n",
        "answer": "095 / 20 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "090 / 20 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "095 / 25 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "090 / 15 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True HDG = 035\u00b0\n TAS = 245 kt\n Track ( T ) = 046\u00b0\n GS = 220 kt\n Calculate the W/V ;\n",
        "answer": "340 / 50 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "335 / 55 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "335 / 45 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "340 / 45 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True HDG = 054\u00b0\n TAS = 450 kt\n Track ( T ) = 059\u00b0\n GS = 416 kt\n Calculate the W/V ;\n",
        "answer": "010 / 50 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "005 / 50 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "010 / 45 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "010 / 55 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True HDG = 074\u00b0\n TAS = 230 kt\n Track ( T ) = 066\u00b0\n GS = 242 kt\n Calculate the W/V ;\n",
        "answer": "180 / 35 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "185 / 35 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 / 40 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "180 / 30 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True Heading = 090\u00b0\n TAS = 180 kt\n GS = 180 kt\n Drift 5\u00b0 right\n Calculate the W/V ;\n",
        "answer": "005\u00b0 / 15 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "185\u00b0 / 15 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "355\u00b0 / 15 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "190\u00b0 / 15 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True HDG = 133\u00b0\n TAS = 225 kt\n Track ( T ) = 144\u00b0\n GS = 206 kt\n Calculate the W/V ;\n",
        "answer": "070 / 45 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "075 / 45 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "075 / 50 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "070 / 40 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True HDG = 145\u00b0\n TAS = 240 kt\n Track (T) = 150\u00b0\n GS = 210 kt\n Calculate the W/V ;\n",
        "answer": "115 / 35 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "360 / 35 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 / 35 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "295 / 35 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True HDG = 206\u00b0\n TAS = 140 kt\n Track ( T ) = 207\u00b0\n GS = 135 kt\n Calculate the W/V ;\n",
        "answer": "180 / 05 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "180 / 10 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "000 / 10 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "000 / 05 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True HDG = 233\u00b0\n TAS = 480 kt\n Track ( T ) = 240\u00b0\n GS = 523 kt\n Calculate the W/V ;\n",
        "answer": "110 / 75 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "105 / 75 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "115 / 70 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "110 / 80 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True HDG = 307\u00b0\n TAS = 230 kt\n Track ( T ) = 313\u00b0\n GS = 210 kt\n Calculate the W/V ;\n",
        "answer": "260 / 30 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "257 / 35 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "265 / 30 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "255 / 25 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True heading = 310\u00b0\n TAS = 200 kt\n GS = 176 kt\n Drift angle 7\u00b0 right.\n Calculate the W/V ?\n",
        "answer": "270\u00b0 / 33 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "090\u00b0 / 33 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "360\u00b0 / 33 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "180\u00b0 / 33 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True Track = 095\u00b0\n TAS = 160 kt\n True Heading = 087\u00b0\n GS = 130 kts\n Calculate W/V ;\n",
        "answer": "057\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "124\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "307\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "237\u00b0/36 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Magnetic track = 315 \u00ba\n HDG = 301 \u00ba ( M )\n VAR = 5\u00baW\n TAS = 225 kt\n The aircraft flies 50 NM in 12 MIN\n Calculate the W/V ( \u00b0T ) ?\n",
        "answer": "190\u00ba / 63 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "355\u00ba / 15 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "195\u00ba / 63 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "195\u00ba / 61 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Hdg 265\u00b0\n TAS 290 kt\n W/V 210\u00b0/35 kt\n Calculate Track and Groundspeed ;\n",
        "answer": "271\u00ba and 272 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "259\u00ba and 305 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "260\u00ba and 315 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "259\u00ba and 272 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Variation is 6\u00b0W\n Isogonic lines Jan 2002\n Average annual increase 10'\n Calculate : Variation in 2005 ;\n",
        "answer": "6.5\u00baW\n",
        "choiceone": "6.3\u00baW\n",
        "choicetwo": "5.5\u00baE\n",
        "choicethree": "5.5\u00baW\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Chart scale is 1 : 1 850 000.\n The chart distance between two points is 4 centimetres\n Earth distance is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "40 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "100 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "74 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "4 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Half way between two reporting points the navigation log gives the following information ;\n TAS 360 kt\n W/V 330\u00b0 / 80 kt\n Compass heading 237\u00b0\n Deviation on this heading \u20135\u00b0\n Variation 19\u00b0W\n What is the average ground speed for this leg ?\n",
        "answer": "403 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "360 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "354 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "373 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n An aircraft is on final approach to runway 32R ( 322\u00b0 )\n The wind velocity reported by the tower is 350\u00b0/20 kt\n TAS on approach is 95 kt\n In order to maintain the centre line , the aircraft\u2019s heading ( \u00b0M ) should be ;\n",
        "answer": "328\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "326\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "322\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "316\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Course 040\u00b0( T )\n TAS is 120 kt\n Wind speed 30 kt\n Maximum drift angle will be obtained for a wind direction of ;\n",
        "answer": "130\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "145\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "120\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "115\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Position A 45\u00b0N , ? \u00b0E\n Position B 45\u00b0N , 45\u00b015'E\n Distance A-B = 280 NM\n B is to the East of A\n Required ; longitude of position A ?\n",
        "answer": "38\u00b039'E\n",
        "choiceone": "40\u00b033'E\n",
        "choicetwo": "49\u00b057'E\n",
        "choicethree": "51\u00b051'E\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n The coordinates of the heliport at Issy les Moulineaux are N48\u00b050' E002\u00b016.5'. What are the coordinates of the position\ndirectly on the opposite side of the earth ?\n",
        "answer": "S48\u00b050' W177\u00b043.5'\n",
        "choiceone": "S48\u00b050' E177\u00b043.5'\n",
        "choicetwo": "S41\u00b010' E177\u00b043.5'\n",
        "choicethree": "S41\u00b010' W177\u00b043.5'\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d 1973 NM\n Groundspeed \u201cout\u201d 430 kt\n Groundspeed \u201cback\u201d 385 kt\n Safe endurance 7 hr 20 min\n The distance from \u201cA\u201d to the Point of Safe Return ( PSR ) \u201cA\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "1490 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "1664 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "1698 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "1422 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d 2484 NM\n Mean groundspeed \u201cout\u201d 420 kt\n Mean groundspeed \u201cback\u201d 500 kt\n Safe endurance 08 hr 30 min\n The distance from \u201cA\u201d to the Point of Safe Return ( PSR ) \u201cA\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "1940 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "1630 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "1908 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "1736 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance \u201cQ\u201d to \u201cR\u201d 1760 NM\n Groundspeed \u201cout\u201d 435 kt\n Groundspeed \u201cback\u201d 385 kt\n Safe endurance 9 HR\n The distance from \u201cQ\u201d to the Point of Safe Return ( PSR ) between \u201cQ\u201d and \u201cR\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "1838 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "1642 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "1467 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "1313 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Lambert conformal conical projection , scale 1: 1 234 000\n Standard parallels 36\u00b0N and 60\u00b0N , A ( 53\u00b0N , 010\u00b0W ) , B ( 53\u00b0N , 020\u00b0W )\n The distance on the map between position A and position B measured along the rhumb line ;\n",
        "answer": "is less than 54.19 cm.\n",
        "choiceone": "is more than 57.13 cm.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is 55.66 cm.\n",
        "choicethree": "is between 54.19 cm and 57.13 cm.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Position NDB ( 55\u00b010'N , 012\u00b055'E )\n DR Position ( 54\u00b053'N , 009\u00b058'E )\n NDB on the RMI reads 090\u00b0\n Magnetic variation = 10\u00b0W\n The position line has to be plotted on a Lamberts conformal chart with standard parallels at 40\u00b0N and 48\u00b0N. Calculate the\ndirection ( T ) of the bearing to be plotted from the NDB ;\n",
        "answer": "262\u00ba TN\n",
        "choiceone": "265\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "272\u00ba\n 10\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "258\u00ba\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d 1973 NM\n Groundspeed \u201cout\u201d 430 kt\n Groundspeed \u201cback\u201d 385 kt\n The time from \u201cA\u201d to the Point of Equal Time ( PET ) between \u201cA\u201d and \u201cB\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "130 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "162 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "145 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "181 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d 2346 NM\n Groundspeed \u201cout\u201d 365 kt\n Groundspeed \u201cback\u201d 480 kt\n The time from \u201cA\u201d to the Point of Equal Time ( PET ) between \u201cA\u201d and \u201cB\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "219 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "167 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "197 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "290 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d 2484 NM\n Groundspeed \u201cout\u201d 420 kt\n Groundspeed \u201cback\u201d 500 kt\n The time from \u201cA\u201d to the Point of Equal Time ( PET ) between \u201cA\u201d and \u201cB\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "193 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "183 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "173 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "163 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d 3623 NM\n Groundspeed \u201cout\u201d 370 kt\n Groundspeed \u201cback\u201d 300 kt\n The time from \u201cA\u201d to the Point of Equal Time ( PET ) between \u201cA\u201d and \u201cB\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "263 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "323 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "238 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "288 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d 2346 NM\n Groundspeed \u201cout\u201d 365 kt\n Groundspeed \u201cback\u201d 480 kt\n Safe endurance 8 HR 30 MIN\n The time from \u201cA\u201d to the Point of Safe Return ( PSR ) \u201cA\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "290 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "219 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "197 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "209 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance \u201cQ\u201d to \u201cR\u201d 1760 NM\n Groundspeed \u201cout\u201d 435 kt\n Groundspeed \u201cback\u201d 385 kt\n The time from \u201cQ\u201d to the Point of Equal Time ( PET ) between \u201cQ\u201d and \u201cR\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "114 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "106 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "110 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "102 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n A is N55\u00b0 000\u00b0\n B is N54\u00b0 E010\u00b0\n The average true course of the great circle is 100\u00b0\n The true course of the rhumbline at point A is ;\n",
        "answer": "100\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "107\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "096\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "104\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Position \u201cA\u201d N60 W020\n Position \u201cB\u201d N60 W021\n Position \u201cC\u201d N59 W020\n What are , respectively , the distances from A to B and from A to C ?\n",
        "answer": "30 NM and 60 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "52 NM and 60 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 NM and 52 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "60 NM and 30 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Required course 045\u00b0( M )\n Variation is 15\u00b0E\n W/V is 190\u00b0( T ) / 30 kt\n CAS is 120 kt at FL 55 in standard atmosphere.\n What are the heading ( \u00b0M ) and GS ?\n",
        "answer": "055\u00b0 and 147 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "056\u00b0 and 137 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "052\u00b0 and 154 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "036\u00b0 and 151 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d is 325 NM\n Planned GS 315 kt\n ATD 1130 UTC\n 1205 UTC - fix obtained 165 NM along track\n What GS must be maintained from the fix in order to achieve planned ETA at \u201cB\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "355 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "335 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "395 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "375 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d is 475 NM\n Planned GS 315 kt\n ATD 1000 UTC\n 1040 UTC - fix obtained 190 NM along track\n What GS must be maintained from the fix in order to achieve planned ETA at \u201cB\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "340 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "320 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "360 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "300 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d is 90 NM\n Fix obtained 60 NM along and 4 NM to the right of course\n What heading alteration must be made to reach \u201cB\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "12\u00b0 Left\n",
        "choiceone": "8\u00b0 Left\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00b0 Left\n",
        "choicethree": "16\u00b0 Left\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d is 100 NM\n Fix obtained 40 NM along and 6 NM to the left of course\n What heading alteration must be made to reach \u201cB\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "15\u00b0 Right\n",
        "choiceone": "9\u00b0 Right\n",
        "choicetwo": "18\u00b0 Right\n",
        "choicethree": "6\u00b0 Right\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance A to B = 120 NM\n After 30 NM aircraft is 3 NM to the left of course\n What heading alteration should be made in order to arrive at point \u201cB\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "8\u00b0 right\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00b0 right\n",
        "choicetwo": "6\u00b0 right\n",
        "choicethree": "8\u00b0 left\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-11993A )\n Annex 061-11993A\n Given ;\n TAS is120 kt\n ATA \u201cX\u201d 1232 UTC\n ETA \u201cY\u201d 1247 UTC\n ATA \u201cY\u201d is 1250 UTC.\n What is ETA \u201cZ\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "1302 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "1303 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "1257 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "1300 UTC\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n CON VOR ( N5354.8 W00849.1 ) DME 30 NM\n CRN VOR ( N5318.1 W00856.5 ) DME 25 NM\n Aircraft heading 270\u00b0 ( M )\n Both DME distances decreasing\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5330 W00820\n",
        "choiceone": "N5337 W00820\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5335 W00925\n",
        "choicethree": "N5343 W00925\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n CRN VOR ( N5318.1 W00856.5 ) DME 18 NM\n SHA VOR ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) DME 30 NM\n Aircraft heading 270\u00b0 ( M )\n Both DME distances decreasing\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5310 W00830\n",
        "choiceone": "N5252 W00923\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5355 W00825\n",
        "choicethree": "N5307 W00923\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n CRN VOR ( N5318.1 W00856.5 ) DME 34 NM\n SHA VOR ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) DME 26 NM\n Aircraft heading 090\u00b0 ( M )\n Both DME distances increasing\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5255 W00815\n",
        "choiceone": "N5310 W00820\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5305 W00930\n",
        "choicethree": "N5250 W0030\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) DME 41 NM\n CRK VOR ( N5150.4 W00829.7 ) DME 30 NM\n Aircraft heading 270\u00b0 ( M )\n Both DME distances decreasing\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5215 W00805\n",
        "choiceone": "N5215 W00915\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5205 W00915\n",
        "choicethree": "N5225 W00810\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) DME 50 NM\n CRK VOR ( N5150.4 W00829.7 ) DME 41 NM\n Aircraft heading 270\u00b0 ( M )\n Both DME distances increasing\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5200 W00935\n",
        "choiceone": "N5215 W00745\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5235 W00750\n",
        "choicethree": "N5215 W00940\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) radial 120\u00b0\n CRK VOR ( N5150.4 W00829.7 ) radial 033\u00b0\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5230 W00800\n",
        "choiceone": "N5240 W00750\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5225 W00805\n",
        "choicethree": "N5220 W00750\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) radial 129\u00b0\n CRK VOR ( N5150.4 W00829.7 ) radial 047\u00b0\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5220 W00750\n",
        "choiceone": "N5205 W00755\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5215 W00755\n",
        "choicethree": "N5210 W00750\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) radial 143\u00b0\n CRK VOR ( N5150.4 W00829.7 ) radial 050\u00b0\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5210 W00800\n",
        "choiceone": "N5205 W00805\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5200 W00800\n",
        "choicethree": "N5155 W00810\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) radial 205\u00b0\n CRK VOR ( N5150.4 W00829.7 ) radial 317\u00b0\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5210 W00910\n",
        "choiceone": "N5118 W00913\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5205 W00915\n",
        "choicethree": "N5215 W00917\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) radial 223\u00b0\n CRK VOR ( N5150.4 W00829.7 ) radial 322\u00b0\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5220 W00920\n",
        "choiceone": "N5230 W00910\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5210 W00930\n",
        "choicethree": "N5210 W00910\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR/DME ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) radial 025\u00b0/49 NM\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5330 W00830\n",
        "choiceone": "N5328 W00820\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5155 W00915\n",
        "choicethree": "N5200 W0925\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR/DME ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) radial 048\u00b0/22 NM\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5300 W0830\n",
        "choiceone": "N5225 W00917\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5228 W00920\n",
        "choicethree": "N5258 W00825\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR/DME ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) radial 120\u00b0/35 NM\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5230 W00800\n",
        "choiceone": "N5250 W00950\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5300 W00945\n",
        "choicethree": "N5225 W00805\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR/DME ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) radial 165\u00b0/36 NM\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5210 W00830\n",
        "choiceone": "N5317 W00908\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5208 W00840\n",
        "choicethree": "N5315 W00915\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR/DME ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) radial 232\u00b0/32 NM\n What is the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "N5220 W00930\n",
        "choiceone": "N5303 W00810\n",
        "choicetwo": "N5305 W00815\n",
        "choicethree": "N5228 W00935\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Airport elevation is 1000 ft\n QNH is 988 hPa\n What is the approximate airport pressure altitude ? ( Assume 1 hPa = 27 ft )\n",
        "answer": "1675 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "320 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "680 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "-320 ft\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Direct Mercator chart with a scale of 1 : 200 000 at equator\n Chart length from \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d , in the vicinity of the equator , 11 cm.\n What is the approximate distance from \u201cA\u201d to \u201cB\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "12 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "14 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "22 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "21 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n ILS GP angle = 3.5 DEG\n GS = 150 kt\n What is the approximate rate of descent ?\n",
        "answer": "900 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "700 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "1000 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "800 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n TAS = 197 kt\n True course = 240\u00b0\n W/V = 180 / 30 kt\n Descent is initiated at FL 220 and completed at FL 40\n Distance to be covered during descent is 39 NM\n What is the approximate rate of descent ?\n",
        "answer": "1400 FT/MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "1500 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "950 FT/MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "800 FT/MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n true track is 348\u00b0\n drift 17\u00b0 left TH = 005\u00b0T\n variation 32\u00b0W TN\n CN\n deviation 4\u00b0E\n What is the compass heading ?\n",
        "answer": "033\u00b0 MN\n",
        "choiceone": "337\u00b0 32\u00b0W\n",
        "choicetwo": "007\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "359\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n CON VOR/DME ( N5354.8 W00849.1 )\n Abbey Shrule aerodrome ( N5335 W00739 )\n What is the CON radial and DME distance when overhead Abbey Shrule aerodrome ?\n",
        "answer": "123\u00b0 - 46 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "116\u00b0 - 47 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "304\u00b0 - 47 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "296\u00b0 - 46 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n CON VOR/DME ( N5354.8 W00849.1 )\n Castlebar aerodrome ( N5351 W00917 )\n What is the CON radial and DME distance when overhead Castlebar aerodrome ?\n",
        "answer": "265\u00b0 - 17 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "257\u00b0 - 17 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "077\u00b0 - 18 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "086\u00b0 - 18 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n CRK VOR/DME ( N5150.4 W00829.7 )\n Kerry aerodrome ( N5210.9 W00931.4 )\n What is the CRK radial and DME distance when overhead Kerry aerodrome ?\n",
        "answer": "307\u00b0 - 43 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "299\u00b0 - 42 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "119\u00b0 - 44 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "127\u00b0 - 45 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n A ( 56\u00b0N , 145\u00b0E )\n B ( 57\u00b0N , 165\u00b0W )\n What is the difference in longitude between A and B ?\n",
        "answer": "050\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "020\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "001\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "130\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Distance A to B is 360 NM\n Wind component A - B is \u201315 kt\n Wind component B - A is +15 kt\n TAS is 180 kt\n What is the distance from the equal-time-point to B ?\n",
        "answer": "165 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "195 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "180 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "170 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True course A to B = 250\u00b0\n Distance A to B = 315 NM\n TAS = 450 kt\n W/V = 200\u00b0 / 60 kt\n ETD A = 0650 UTC\n What is the ETA at B ?\n",
        "answer": "0736 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "0716 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "0810 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "0730 UTC\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Magnetic heading 311\u00b0\n Drift angle 10\u00b0 left MN\n Relative bearing of NDB 270\u00b0\n 41\u00b0\n What is the magnetic bearing of the NDB measured from the aircraft ? 49\u00b0\n",
        "answer": "221\u00b0 HDG 311\u00b0M\n",
        "choiceone": "211\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "208\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "180\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Position \u201cA\u201d is N00\u00b0 E100\u00b0\n Position \u201cB\u201d is 240\u00b0( T ) , 200 NM from \u201cA\u201d 100\u00b0E\n What is the position of \u201cB\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "S01\u00b040' E097\u00b007' C\n 30\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "S01\u00b040' E101\u00b040'\n",
        "choicetwo": "N01\u00b040' E097\u00b007' A\n",
        "choicethree": "N01\u00b040' E101\u00b040' 00\u00b0N\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Value for the flattening of the Earth is 1/298.\n Earth\u2019s semi-major axis , as measured at the equator , equals 6378.4 km.\n What is the semi-minor axis ( km ) of the earth at the axis of the poles ?\n",
        "answer": "6357.0\n",
        "choiceone": "6378.4\n",
        "choicetwo": "6367.0\n",
        "choicethree": "6399.9\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR/DME ( N5243.3 W00853.1 )\n Birr aerodrome ( N5304 W00754 )\n What is the SHA radial and DME distance when overhead Birr aerodrome ?\n",
        "answer": "068\u00b0 - 41 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "248\u00b0 - 42 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "240\u00b0 - 41 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "060\u00b0 - 42 Nm\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR/DME ( N5243.3 W00853.1 )\n Connemara aerodrome ( N5314 W00928 )\n What is the SHA radial and DME distance when overhead Connemara aerodrome ?\n",
        "answer": "333\u00b0 - 37 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "154\u00b0 - 38 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "326\u00b0 - 37 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "146\u00b0 - 38 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n CAS 120 kt\n FL 80\n OAT +20\u00b0C\n What is the TAS ?\n",
        "answer": "141 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "120 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "102 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "132 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n True altitude 9000 ft\n OAT \u201332\u00b0C\n CAS 200 kt\n What is the TAS ?\n",
        "answer": "220 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "200 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "210 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "215 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n GS = 95 kt\n Distance from A to B = 480 NM\n What is the time from A to B ?\n",
        "answer": "5 HR 03 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "5 HR 00 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 HR 08 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "4 HR 59 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n GS = 105 kt\n Distance from A to B = 103 NM\n What is the time from A to B ?\n",
        "answer": "00 HR 59 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "01 HR 01 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "00 HR 58 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "00 HR 57 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n GS = 120 kt\n Distance from A to B = 84 NM\n What is the time from A to B ?\n",
        "answer": "00 HR 42 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "00 HR 44 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "00 HR 43 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "00 HR 45 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n GS = 122 kt\n Distance from A to B = 985 NM\n What is the time from A to B ?\n",
        "answer": "8 HR 04 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "7 HR 49 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "8 HR 10 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "7 HR 48 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n GS = 135 kt\n Distance from A to B = 433 NM\n What is the time from A to B ?\n",
        "answer": "3 HR 12 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "3 HR 19 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 HR 25 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "3 HR 20 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n GS = 236 kt\n Distance from A to B = 354 NM\n What is the time from A to B ?\n",
        "answer": "1 HR 30 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "1 HR 40 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 HR 09 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "1 HR 10 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n GS = 345 kt\n Distance from A to B = 3560 NM\n What is the time from A to B ?\n",
        "answer": "10 HR 19 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "11 HR 00 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "11 HR 02 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "10 HR 05 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n GS = 435 kt\n Distance from A to B = 1920 NM\n What is the time from A to B ?\n",
        "answer": "4 HR 25 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "4 HR 10 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 HR 26 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "3 HR 25 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n GS = 480 kt\n Distance from A to B = 5360 NM\n What is the time from A to B ?\n",
        "answer": "11 HR 10 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "11 HR 06 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "11 HR 15 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "11 HR 07 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n GS = 510 kt\n Distance A to B = 43 NM\n What is the time ( MIN ) from A to B ?\n",
        "answer": "5\n",
        "choiceone": "7\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\n",
        "choicethree": "6\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Aircraft at FL 150 overhead an airport\n Elevation of airport 720 ft\n QNH is 1003 hPa\n OAT at FL150 \u20135\u00b0C\n What is the true altitude of the aircraft ? ( Assume 1 hPa = 27 ft )\n",
        "answer": "15 300 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "14 160 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "14 720 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "15 840 ft\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Compass Heading = 233\u00b0\n CN\n True Track = 256\u00b0\n Drift Angle = 10\u00b0R 16\u00b0 MN\n TN\n Deviation = \u20133\u00b0\n What is the variation ?\n",
        "answer": "16\u00b0E\n",
        "choiceone": "20\u00b0W\n",
        "choicetwo": "10\u00b0W\n",
        "choicethree": "36\u00b0E\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n FL120 , OAT is ISA standard , CAS is 200 kt\n Track is 222\u00b0( M ) , Heading is 215\u00b0( M ) , Variation is 15\u00b0W\n Time to fly 105 NM is 21 MIN\n What is the W/V ?\n",
        "answer": "050\u00b0( T ) / 70 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "040\u00b0( T ) / 105 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "055\u00b0( T ) / 105 kt .\n",
        "choicethree": "065\u00b0( T ) / 70 kt.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Waypoint 1. 60\u00b0S 030\u00b0W , Waypoint 2. 60\u00b0S 020\u00b0W\n What will be the approximate latitude shown on the display unit of an inertial navigation system at longitude 025\u00b0W ?\n",
        "answer": "060\u00b006'S\n",
        "choiceone": "060\u00b011'S\n",
        "choicetwo": "059\u00b049'S\n",
        "choicethree": "060\u00b000'S\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n AD = Air distance\n GD = Ground distance\n TAS = True Airspeed\n GS = Groundspeed\n Which of the following is the correct formula to calculate ground distance ( GD ) gone ?\n",
        "answer": "GD = ( AD x GS ) / TAS\n",
        "choiceone": "GD = TAS / ( GS x AD )\n",
        "choicetwo": "GD = AD x ( GS \u2013 TAS ) / GS\n",
        "choicethree": "GD = ( AD \u2013 TAS ) / TAS\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR N5243.3 W00853.1\n CON VOR N5354.8 W00849.1\n Aircraft position N5330 W00800\n Which of the following lists two radials that are applicable to the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "SHA 042\u00b0\n CON 138\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "SHA 221\u00b0\n CON 318\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHA 213\u00b0\n CON 310\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "SHA 033\u00b0\n CON 130\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR N5243.3 W00853.1\n CRK VOR N5150.4 W00829.7\n Aircraft position N5230 W00820\n Which of the following lists two radials that are applicable to the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "SHA 131\u00b0\n CRK 017\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "SHA 304\u00b0\n CRK 189\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHA 124\u00b0\n CRK 009\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "SHA 312\u00b0\n CRK 197\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR N5243.3 W00853.1\n CRK VOR N5150.4 W00829.7\n Aircraft position N5220 W00910\n Which of the following lists two radials that are applicable to the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "SHA 214\u00b0\n CRK 330\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "SHA 205\u00b0\n CRK 321\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHA 033\u00b0\n CRK 149\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "SHA 025\u00b0\n CRK 141\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR N5243.3 W00853.1\n CRK VOR N5150.4 W00829.7\n Aircraft position N5230 W00930\n Which of the following lists two radials that are applicable to the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "SHA 248\u00b0\n CRK 325\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "SHA 068\u00b0\n CRK 145\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHA 240\u00b0\n CRK 137\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "SHA 060\u00b0\n CRK 138\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Given ;\n SHA VOR N5243.3 W00853.1\n CON VOR N5354.8 W00849.1\n Aircraft position N5320 W00950\n Which of the following lists two radials that are applicable to the aircraft position ?\n",
        "answer": "SHA 325\u00b0\n CON 235\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "SHA 317\u00b0\n CON 226\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "SHA 145\u00b0\n CON 055\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "SHA 137\u00b0\n CON 046\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Compass Heading 090\u00b0\n Deviation 2\u00b0W\n Variation 12\u00b0E\n TAS 160 kt\n Whilst maintaining a radial 070\u00b0 from a VOR station , the aircraft flies a ground distance of 14 NM in 6 MIN. What is the\nW/V\u00b0( T ) ?\n",
        "answer": "160\u00b0 / 50 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "340\u00b0 / 98 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "340\u00b0 / 25 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "155\u00b0 / 25 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given the following ;\n True track : 192\u00b0\n Magnetic variation : 7\u00b0E\n Drift angle : 5\u00b0 left\n What is the magnetic heading required to maintain the given track ?\n",
        "answer": "190\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "180\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "194\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "204\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given the following ;\n Magnetic heading : 060\u00b0\n Magnetic variation : 8\u00b0W\n Drift angle : 4\u00b0 right\n What is the true track ?\n",
        "answer": "056\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "072\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "064\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "048\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Grid heading is 299\u00b0 , grid convergency is 55\u00b0 West and magnetic variation is 90\u00b0 West. What is the corresponding magnetic\nheading ?\n",
        "answer": "084\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "154\u00b0 180\u00b0E/W\n",
        "choicetwo": "334\u00b0 GRID NORTH\n",
        "choicethree": "264\u00b0\n 070\u00b0N\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Gyrocompassing of an inertial reference system ( IRS ) is accomplished with the mode selector switched to ;\n",
        "answer": "ALIGN\n",
        "choiceone": "ON\n",
        "choicetwo": "STBY\n",
        "choicethree": "ATT/REF\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does the chart convergency change with latitude in a Lambert Conformal projection ?\n",
        "answer": "It is constant and does not change with latitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "It changes with sine of latitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It changes with cosine of latitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "It increases with increase of latitude.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does the convergency of any two meridians on the Earth change with varying latitude ?\n",
        "answer": "It changes as sine of latitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "It changes as cosine of latitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is of constant value and does not change with latitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "It increases with decrease of latitude.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does the scale vary in a Direct Mercator chart ?\n",
        "answer": "The scale increases with increasing distance from the Equator.\n",
        "choiceone": "The scale decreases with increasing distance from the Equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The scale increases south of the Equator and decreases north of the Equator.\n",
        "choicethree": "The scale is constant.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How is the radio position determined by the FMC in the B737-400 Electronic Flight Instrument System ?\n",
        "answer": "DME/DME or VOR/DME.\n",
        "choiceone": "VOR/DME range and bearing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "DME ranges and/ or VOR/ADF bearings.\n",
        "choicethree": "VOR/VOR or ADF bearings.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long will it take to fly 5 NM at a groundspeed of 269 Kt ?\n",
        "answer": "1 MIN 07 SEC\n",
        "choiceone": "0 MIN 34 SEC\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 MIN 55 SEC\n",
        "choicethree": "2 MIN 30 SEC\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many degrees has the mean sun moved along the celestial equator in 8 hours and 8 minutes ?\n",
        "answer": "122\u00ba\n",
        "choiceone": "18\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "148\u00ba\n",
        "choicethree": "56\u00ba\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many NM would an aircraft travel in 1 MIN 45 SEC if GS is 135 kt?\n",
        "answer": "3.94\n",
        "choiceone": "2.36\n",
        "choicetwo": "39.0\n",
        "choicethree": "3.25\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many small circles can be drawn between any two points on a sphere ?\n",
        "answer": "An unlimited number.\n",
        "choiceone": "None.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Two.\n",
        "choicethree": "One.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aeroplane was to circle around the Earth following parallel 60\u00b0N at a ground speed of 480 kt. In order to circle around\nthe Earth along the equator in the same amount of time , it should fly at a ground speed of ;\n",
        "answer": "960 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "550 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "480 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "240 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the acceleration of an aircraft is zero , its velocity ;\n",
        "answer": "is constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "will decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is always zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "will increase.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the chart scale is 1 : 500 000 , what earth distance would be represented by 7 cm on the chart ?\n",
        "answer": "35 000 m\n",
        "choiceone": "0.35 km\n",
        "choicetwo": "3.5 km\n",
        "choicethree": "35 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Compass Heading is 265\u00b0 , variation is 33\u00b0W and deviation is 3\u00b0E , what is the True Heading ?\n",
        "answer": "235\u00b0\n CN\n",
        "choiceone": "295\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "229\u00b0 TN\n",
        "choicethree": "301\u00b0 MN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are flying along a parallel of latitude , you are flying ;\n",
        "answer": "a rhumb line track.\n",
        "choiceone": "a great circle track.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on a north - south track.\n",
        "choicethree": "on a track which is constantly changing direction.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 8 hours and 8 minutes the mean sun has moved how many degrees ( \u00b0 ) along the celestial equator ?\n",
        "answer": "122\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "18\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "56\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "148\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a Flight Management System ( FMS ) , control Display Units ( CDUs ) are used preflight to ;\n",
        "answer": "manually initialize the IRSs and FMC with dispatch information.\n",
        "choiceone": "manually initialise the IRSs , FMC and Air Data Computer with dispatch information.\n",
        "choicetwo": "manually initialize the Flight Director System and FMC with dispatch information.\n",
        "choicethree": "automatically initialize the IRSs and FMC with dispatch information.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a navigation chart a distance of 49 NM is equal to 7 cm. The scale of the chart is approximately:\n",
        "answer": "1 : 1 300 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 700 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 7 000 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 130 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a remote indicating compass system the amount of deviation caused by aircraft magnetism and electrical circuits may be\nminimised by ;\n",
        "answer": "mounting the detector unit ( flux valve ) in the wingtip.\n",
        "choiceone": "using a vertically mounted gyroscope instead of a horizontally mounted one.\n",
        "choicetwo": "positioning the gyroscope in the centre of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicethree": "mounting the flux valve in the cockpit.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a sunrise/sunset table given for the 28th of June at a certain latitude , sunrise is given as 0239 and sunset is given as 2127.\nWhat is the latitude ?\n",
        "answer": "60\u00baN\n",
        "choiceone": "00\u00baN/S\n",
        "choicetwo": "55\u00baS\n",
        "choicethree": "80\u00baN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an Inertial Navigation System ( INS ) , Ground Speed ( GS ) is calculated ;\n",
        "answer": "by integrating measured acceleration.\n",
        "choiceone": "from TAS and W/V from RNAV data.\n",
        "choicetwo": "by integrating gyro precession in N/S and E/W directions respectively.\n",
        "choicethree": "from TAS and W/V from Air Data Computer ( ADC ).\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an Inertial Reference System , accelerations are measured in relation to ;\n",
        "answer": "aircraft axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "the direction of true north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "local vertical at the aircraft position.\n",
        "choicethree": "WGS 84 Earth co-ordinates.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In northern hemisphere , during an acceleration in an easterly direction , the magnetic compass will indicate ;\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "an apparent turn to the South.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a heading of East.\n",
        "choicethree": "an increase in heading.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to fly from position A ( 10\u00b000'N , 030\u00b000'W ) to position B ( 30\u00b000'N , 050\u00b000'W ) , maintaining a constant true\ncourse , it is necessary to fly ;\n",
        "answer": "a rhumb line track.\n",
        "choiceone": "a straight line plotted on a Lambert chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the great-circle route.\n",
        "choicethree": "the constant average drift route.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to maintain an accurate vertical using a pendulous system , an aircraft inertial platform incorporates a device ;\n",
        "answer": "with damping and a period of 84.4 MIN.\n",
        "choiceone": "with damping and a period of 84.4 SEC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "without damping and a period of 84.4 MIN.\n",
        "choicethree": "without damping and a period of 84.4 SEC.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere the rhumb line track from position A to B is 230\u00b0 , the covergency is 6\u00b0 and the difference in\nlongitude is 10\u00b0. What is the initial rhumb line track from B to A ?\n",
        "answer": "050\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "056\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "053\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "047\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which occasions does the rhumb line track and the great circle track coincide on the surface of the Earth ?\n",
        "answer": "On tracks directly North - South and on East - West tracks along the Equator.\n",
        "choiceone": "On East - West tracks in the northern hemisphere north of the magnetic equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On high latitude tracks directly East - West.\n",
        "choicethree": "On East - West tracks in polar areas.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which statement is the \u201cMean Sun\u201d best described ?\n",
        "answer": "The mean sun is a fictitious sun coinciding each year with the apparent sun at the Spring Equinox and\n travelling along the celestial equator at uniform speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "The mean sun is a fictitious sun the orbit of which coincides with that of the apparent sun , but is corrected\n for mean astronomicaland atmospheric refraction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The mean sun is a fictitious sun coinciding each year with the apparent sun at the Spring Equinox and\n travelling along the ecliptic at uniform speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "The mean sun is a fictitious sun the orbit of which coincides with that of the apparent sun , but is corrected\n for mean dfference in hour angle.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which two months of the year is the difference between the transit of the Apparent Sun and Mean Sun across the\nGreenwich Meridian the greatest ?\n",
        "answer": "February and November.\n",
        "choiceone": "June and December.\n",
        "choicetwo": "April and August.\n",
        "choicethree": "March and September.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Inertial Reference System sensors include ;\n",
        "answer": "accelerometers , and laser gyros , mounted in the direction of the aircraft axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "laser gyros mounted in the direction of the aircraft axis.\n",
        "choicetwo": "accelerometers mounted in the direction of the aircraft axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "one east-west and one north-south gyro , one east-west and one north-south accelerometer.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Isogonals are lines of equal ;\n",
        "answer": "magnetic variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "compass deviation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "wind velocity.\n",
        "choicethree": "pressure.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Isogonic lines connect positions that have ;\n",
        "answer": "the same variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "the same elevation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same angle of magnetic dip.\n",
        "choicethree": "0\u00b0 variation.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Isogrives are lines that connect positions that have ;\n",
        "answer": "the same grivation.\n",
        "choiceone": "the same variation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "0\u00b0 magnetic dip.\n",
        "choicethree": "the same horizontal magnetic field strength.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Keplar\u2019s second law states ;\n",
        "answer": "each planet revolves so that the radius vector , sun to earth , sweeps out equal area in equal intervals of time.\n",
        "choiceone": "the area swept out by the radius vector of each planet , sun to earth , per hour , increasing with increasing\n length of the radius vector.\n",
        "choicetwo": "each planet\u2019s radius vector , sun to earth , moves at a constant angular speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "the length of the radius vector , sun to earth , is proportional to the square root of its angular speed.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Kepler\u2019s second law states that ;\n",
        "answer": "the radius vector sun-earth sweeps out equal areas in equal time.\n",
        "choiceone": "the length of the radius vector sun-earth is directly proportional to the square root of its angular speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the area swept out by the radius vector sun-earth per hour increases with increasing length of the radius\n vector.\n",
        "choicethree": "the radius vector sun-earth moves at constant angular speed\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Location A is at 50\u00baN 030\u00baW and location B is at 50\u00baS 030\u00baW. On 27th November it is noted that ;\n",
        "answer": "Sunrise will be later at A than it is at B and sunset will be earlier at A than it is at B.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sunrise will be earlier at A than it is at B and sunset will be later at A than it is at B.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sunrise will be earlier at A than it is at B and sunset will be earlier at A than it is at B.\n",
        "choicethree": "Sunrise and sunset will be at the same time at A and B.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Magnetic compass calibration is carried out to reduce ;\n",
        "answer": "deviation.\n",
        "choiceone": "variation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "parallax error.\n",
        "choicethree": "acceleration errors.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Morning Civil twilight begins when ;\n",
        "answer": "the centre of the sun is 6\u00b0 below the celestial horizon.\n",
        "choiceone": "the sun\u2019s upper edge is tangential to the celestial horizon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the centre of the sun is 18\u00b0 below the celestial horizon.\n",
        "choicethree": "the centre of the sun is 12\u00b0 below the celestial horizon.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mu\u2019a , Tonga Islands , is situated at ( 21\u00b011'S , 175\u00b007'W ). In the Air Almanac the standard time of Tonga Islands is listed\nas UTC +13. For August 21st the sunrise table in the Air Almanac shows ; 20\u00b0S: 06:18 ; 30\u00b0S: 06:28. What is the Standard Time of\nsunrise at Mu\u2019a ?\n",
        "answer": "06:59 on August 22nd.\n",
        "choiceone": "07:39 on August 22nd.\n",
        "choicetwo": "06:59 on August 21st.\n",
        "choicethree": "07:39 on August 21st.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Near the magnetic pole ;\n",
        "answer": "the horizontal component of the earth\u2019s magnetic field is too small to permit the use of a magnetic compass.\n",
        "choiceone": "the vertical component of the earth\u2019s magnetic field is too small to permit the use of a magnetic compass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the angle of dip is minimal whereby a freely suspended compass needle will be almost fully vertically\n aligned.\n",
        "choicethree": "the angle of dip is minimal whereby a freely suspended compass needle will be almost fully horizontally\n aligned.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a chart a straight line is drawn between two points and has a length of 4.63 cm. What is the chart scale if the line\nrepresents 150 NM ?\n",
        "answer": "1 : 6 000 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 3 000 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 1 000 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 5 000 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a chart , the distance along a meridian between latitudes 45\u00b0N and 46\u00b0N is 6 cm. The scale of the chart is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "1 : 1 850 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 185 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 18 500 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 1 000 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Direct Mercator chart a great circle will be represented by a ;\n",
        "answer": "curve concave to the equator.\n",
        "choiceone": "complex curve.\n",
        "choicetwo": "curve convex to the equator.\n",
        "choicethree": "straight line.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Direct Mercator chart , a rhumb line appears as a ;\n",
        "answer": "straight line.\n",
        "choiceone": "curve convex to the nearer pole.\n",
        "choicetwo": "spiral curve.\n",
        "choicethree": "small circle concave to the nearer pole.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Direct Mercator chart at latitude 15\u00b0S , a certain length represents a distance of 120 NM on the earth. The same length\non the chart will represent on the earth , at latitude 10\u00b0N , a distance of ;\n",
        "answer": "122.3 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "124.2 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "118.2 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "117.7 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Direct Mercator chart at latitude 45\u00b0N , a certain chart length along 45\u00b0N represents a distance of 90 NM on the surface\nof the earth. The same length on a chart along latitude 30\u00b0N will represent a distance on the earth of ;\n",
        "answer": "110 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "73.5 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "45 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "78 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Direct Mercator chart at latitude of 45\u00b0N , a certain length represents a distance of 90 NM on the earth. The same length\non the chart will represent on the earth , at latitude 30\u00b0N , a distance of ;\n",
        "answer": "110 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "73.5 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "45 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "78 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Direct Mercator chart , meridians are ;\n",
        "answer": "parallel , equally spaced , vertical straight lines.\n",
        "choiceone": "parallel , unequally spaced , vertical straight lines.\n",
        "choicetwo": "inclined , unequally spaced , curved lines that meet at the nearer pole.\n",
        "choicethree": "inclined , equally spaced , straight lines that meet at the nearer pole.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Direct Mercator projection a particular chart length is measured at 30\u00b0N. What earth distance will the same chart length\nbe if measured at 60\u00b0N ?\n",
        "answer": "A smaller distance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Twice the distance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The same distance.\n",
        "choicethree": "A larger distance.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a direct Mercator projection , at latitude 45\u00b0 North , a certain length represents 70 NM. At latitude 30\u00b0 North , the same\nlength represents approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "86 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "70 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "57 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "81 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a direct Mercator projection , the distance measured between two meridians spaced 5\u00b0 apart at latitude 60\u00b0N is 8 cm. The\nscale of this chart at latitude 60\u00b0N is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "1 : 3 500 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 7 000 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 4 750 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 6 000 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Direct Mercator , rhumb lines are ;\n",
        "answer": "straight lines.\n",
        "choiceone": "curves concave to the equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "curves convex to the equator.\n",
        "choicethree": "ellipses.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Lambert chart ( standard parallels 37\u00b0N and 65\u00b0N ) , with respect to the straight line drawn on the map between A\n( N49\u00b0 W030\u00b0 ) and B ( N48\u00b0 W040\u00b0 ) , the ;\n",
        "answer": "great circle and rhumb line are to the south.\n",
        "choiceone": "great circle is to the north , the rhumb line is to the south.\n",
        "choicetwo": "rhumb line is to the north , the great circle is to the south.\n",
        "choicethree": "great circle and rhumb line are to the north.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Lambert Conformal chart the distance between meridians 5\u00b0 apart along latitude 37\u00b0 North is 9 cm. The scale of the\nchart at that parallel approximates ;\n",
        "answer": "1 : 5 000 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 6 000 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 2 000 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 3 750 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Lambert Conformal Conic chart earth convergency is most accurately represented at the ;\n",
        "answer": "parallel of origin.\n",
        "choiceone": "north and south limits of the chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "standard parallels.\n",
        "choicethree": "Equator.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Lambert Conformal Conic chart great circles that are not meridians are ;\n",
        "answer": "curves concave to the parallel of origin.\n",
        "choiceone": "curves concave to the pole of projection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "straight lines regardless of distance.\n",
        "choicethree": "straight lines within the standard parallels.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Lambert conformal conic chart the convergence of the meridians ;\n",
        "answer": "is the same as earth convergency at the parallel of origin.\n",
        "choiceone": "is zero throughout the chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "equals earth convergency at the standard parallels.\n",
        "choicethree": "varies as the secant of the latitude.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Lambert conformal conic chart , the distance between parallels of latitude spaced the same number of degrees apart ;\n",
        "answer": "is smaller between the standard parallels than outside them.\n",
        "choiceone": "is constant throughout the chart.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is larger between the standard parallels and in smaller outside them.\n",
        "choicethree": "is constant between the standard parallels and is greater outside them.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Lambert conformal conic chart , the distance between parallels of latitude spaced the same number of degrees apart ;\n",
        "answer": "reduces between , and expands outside , the standard parallels.\n",
        "choiceone": "expands between , and reduces outside , the standard parallels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is constant throughout the chart.\n",
        "choicethree": "is constant between , and expands outside , the standard parallels.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Lambert conformal conic chart , with two standard parallels , the quoted scale is correct ;\n",
        "answer": "along the two standard parallels.\n",
        "choiceone": "along the prime meridian.\n",
        "choicetwo": "along the parallel of origin.\n",
        "choicethree": "in the area between the standard parallels.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Mercator chart , at latitude 60\u00b0N , the distance measured between W002\u00b0 and E008\u00b0 is 20 cm. The scale of this chart at\nlatitude 60\u00b0N is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "1 : 2 780 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 5 560 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 556 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 278 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Mercator\u2019s projection the distance between ( 17\u00b0N , 035\u00b0E ) and ( 17\u00b0N , 040\u00b0E ) is 5 cm. The scale at 57\u00b0N is\napproximately ;\n",
        "answer": "1 : 6 052 030\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 18 658 470\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 10 626 460\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 5 556 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Polar Stereographic chart , the initial great circle course from A 70\u00b0N 060\u00b0W to B 70\u00b0N 060\u00b0E is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "330\u00b0( T )\n",
        "choicetwo": "030\u00b0( T ) 180\u00b0E/W\n",
        "choicethree": "150\u00b0( T )\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a polar stereographic projection chart showing the South Pole , a straight line joins position A ( 70\u00b0S 065\u00b0E ) to position\nB ( 70\u00b0S 025\u00b0W ). The true course on departure from position A is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "225\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "250\u00b0 025\u00b0W\n",
        "choicetwo": "315\u00b0 000\u00b0E/W\n",
        "choicethree": "135\u00b0 B\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a Transverse Mercator chart , scale is exactly correct along the ;\n",
        "answer": "meridian of tangency.\n",
        "choiceone": "prime meridian and the equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "datum meridian and meridian perpendicular to it.\n",
        "choicethree": "Equator , parallel of origin and prime vertical.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a transverse Mercator chart , the scale is exactly correct along the ;\n",
        "answer": "meridians of tangency.\n",
        "choiceone": "equator and parallel of origin.\n",
        "choicetwo": "meridian of tangency and the parallel of latitude perpendicular to it.\n",
        "choicethree": "prime meridian and the equator.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a transverse Mercator chart , with the exception of the Equator , parallels of latitude appear as ;\n",
        "answer": "ellipses.\n",
        "choiceone": "straight lines.\n",
        "choicetwo": "parabolas.\n",
        "choicethree": "hyperbolic lines.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a True Heading of 090\u00b0 the aircraft experiences drift of 5\u00b0S. On a True Heading of 180\u00b0 the aircraft experiences no drift.\nOn both headings the TAS is 200 kt and it is assumed that the wind is the same. What is the experienced wind speed and direction ?\n",
        "answer": "360\u00b0 / 17 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "180\u00b0 / 17 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "360\u00b0 / 34 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "180\u00b0 / 34 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an oblate spheroid representing the earth\u2019s shape ;\n",
        "answer": "1 minute of arc along the equator measures a greater distance than 1 minute of arc along the meridian at a\n latitude of 45\u00baN/S.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 minute of arc along the equator measures the same distance as 1 minute of arc along the meridian at a\n latitude of 45\u00baN/S.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 minute of arc along the meridian at low latitudes measures a greater distance than 1 minute of arc along the\n meridian at high latitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 minute of arc along the meridian at 0\u00baN/S measures the same distance as 1 minute of arc at 90\u00baN/S.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On the 27th of February , at 52\u00b0S and 040\u00b0E , the sunrise is at 0243 UTC. On the same day , at 52\u00b0S and 035\u00b0W , the sunrise\nis at ;\n",
        "answer": "0743 UTC\n",
        "choiceone": "2143 UTC\n",
        "choicetwo": "0243 UTC\n",
        "choicethree": "0523 UTC\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On the earth\u2019s ellipsoid one degree of latitude near the equator is ;\n",
        "answer": "less than 60 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "more than 60 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "more than 60 NM but less than 61 NM.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which of the following chart projections is it NOT possible to represent the north or south poles ?\n",
        "answer": "Direct Mercator.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lambert\u2019s conformal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transverse Mercator.\n",
        "choicethree": "Polar stereographic.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the errors inherent in a ring laser gyroscope occurs at low input rotation rates tending towards zero when a\nphenomenon known as \u201clock-in\u201d is experienced. What is the name of the technique , effected by means of a piezo-electric motor , that\nis used to correct this error ?\n",
        "answer": "Dither\n",
        "choiceone": "Cavity rotation\n",
        "choicetwo": "Beam lock\n",
        "choicethree": "Zero drop\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "One purpose of a compass calibration is to reduce the difference , if any , between ;\n",
        "answer": "compass north and magnetic north.\n",
        "choiceone": "compass north and the lubber line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "true north and magnetic north.\n",
        "choicethree": "compass north and true north.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "One purpose of compass calibration is to determine the deviation ;\n",
        "answer": "on any heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "on a given heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on N , S , E and W only.\n",
        "choicethree": "at any latitude.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Parallels of latitude , except the equator , are ;\n",
        "answer": "Rhumb lines.\n",
        "choiceone": "are neither Rhumb lines nor Great circles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "both Rhumb lines and Great circles.\n",
        "choicethree": "Great circles.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Parallels of latitude on a Direct Mercator chart are ;\n",
        "answer": "parallel straight lines unequally spaced.\n",
        "choiceone": "straight lines converging above the pole.\n",
        "choicetwo": "arcs of concentric circles equally spaced.\n",
        "choicethree": "parallel straight lines equally spaced.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Permanent magnetism in aircraft arises chiefly from ;\n",
        "answer": "hammering , and the effect of the earth\u2019s magnetic field , whilst under construction.\n",
        "choiceone": "the combined effect of aircraft electrical equipment and the earth\u2019s magnetic field.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the effect of internal wiring and exposure to electrical storms.\n",
        "choicethree": "exposure to the earth's magnetic field during normal operation.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Position A = ( 30\u00b000.0''N , 175\u00b023.2''W ) Position B = ( 30\u00b000.0''N , 173\u00b048.1''E ). For the route from A to B the ;\n",
        "answer": "rhumb line distance is 578 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "great circle direction at B is 092.7\u00ba.\n",
        "choicetwo": "rhumb line distance is 648.7 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "great circle direction at A is 275.4\u00ba.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Position A = ( 56\u00b000.0''S , 163\u00b057.2''E ) Position B = ( 56\u00b000.0''S , 171\u00b047.4''W ). For the route from A to B the ;\n",
        "answer": "great circle direction at B is 080.7\u00ba.\n",
        "choiceone": "rhumb line distance is 1455.4 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "great circle direction at B is 100.1\u00ba.\n",
        "choicethree": "rhumb line distance is 1206.6 NM.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Position A is ( 31\u00ba00'S , 176\u00ba17'W ). Rhumb line track ( T ) from A to B is 270\u00ba. Initial great circle track ( T ) from A to B is\n266.2\u00ba. The Approximate position of B is ;\n",
        "answer": "( 31\u00b000'S , 168\u00b058'E )\n",
        "choiceone": "( 31\u00b000'S , 161\u00b032'W )\n",
        "choicetwo": "( 31\u00b000'S , 173\u00b024'E )\n",
        "choicethree": "( 31\u00b000'S , 173\u00b024'W )\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Position A is located on the equator at longitude 130\u00b000E. Position B is located 100 NM from A on a bearing of 225\u00b0(T).\nThe coordinates of position B are ;\n",
        "answer": "01\u00b011'S 128\u00b049'E\n",
        "choiceone": "01\u00b011'N 131\u00b011'E\n",
        "choicetwo": "01\u00b011'N 128\u00b049'E\n",
        "choicethree": "01\u00b011'S 131\u00b011'E\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Position \u201cElephant Point\u201d is situated at ( 58\u00b000'N , 135\u00b030'W ). Standard time for this location is listed in the Air Almanac as\nUTC \u2013 8. If sunset occurs at 00:57 UTC on 21st January , what is the time of Sunset in LMT ?\n",
        "answer": "15:55 on January 20th.\n",
        "choiceone": "09:59 on January 21st.\n",
        "choicetwo": "08:57 on January 21st.\n",
        "choicethree": "16:57 on January 20th.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Route \u201cA\u201d ( 44\u00b0N 026\u00b0E ) to \u201cB\u201d ( 46\u00b0N 024\u00b0E ) forms an angle of 35\u00b0 with longitude 026\u00b0E. Variation at A is 3\u00b0E. What is\nthe initial magnetic track from A to B ?\n",
        "answer": "322\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "038\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "032\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "328\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Route A - B is drawn on a Polar Stereographic chart with the grid aligned with the Greenwich meridian. The true track of the\nstraight line at A is 060\u00b0. When passing the meridian 100\u00b0E , the true track is 090\u00b0. The grid track of this route on the chart is ;\n",
        "answer": "350\u00ba(G)\n",
        "choiceone": "060\u00ba(G)\n",
        "choicetwo": "130\u00ba(G)\n",
        "choicethree": "010\u00ba(G)\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Route A - B is drawn on a Polar Stereographic chart with the grid aligned with the Greenwich meridian. The true track of the\nstraight line at A ( 75\u00b0N , 010\u00b0W ) is 080\u00b0. What is the Grid Track when passing the meridian 050\u00b0E ?\n",
        "answer": "090\u00ba(G)\n",
        "choiceone": "150\u00ba(G)\n",
        "choicetwo": "070\u00ba(G)\n",
        "choicethree": "110\u00ba(G)\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Route A - B is drawn on a Polar Stereographic chart with the grid aligned with the Greenwich meridian. The true track of the\nstraight line at A ( 75\u00b0S , 010\u00b0W ) is 080\u00b0. What is the Grid Track when passing the meridian of 050\u00b0E ?\n",
        "answer": "070\u00ba(G)\n",
        "choiceone": "110\u00ba(G)\n",
        "choicetwo": "330\u00ba(G)\n",
        "choicethree": "090\u00ba(G)\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Route A - B is drawn on a Southern Polar Stereographic chart whose grid is aligned with the Greenwich meridian. The true\ntrack of the straight line at A is 120\u00b0. When passing the meridian of 100\u00b0E the true track is 090\u00b0. The grid track of this route on the\nchart is ;\n",
        "answer": "190\u00ba(G)\n",
        "choiceone": "350\u00ba(G)\n",
        "choicetwo": "030\u00ba(G)\n",
        "choicethree": "120\u00ba(G)\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Seasons are due to the ;\n",
        "answer": "inclination of the polar axis with the ecliptic plane.\n",
        "choiceone": "Earth\u2019s rotation on its polar axis.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Earth\u2019s elliptical orbit around the Sun.\n",
        "choicethree": "variable distance between Earth and Sun.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Some inertial reference and navigation systems are known as \u201cstrapdown\u201d. This means that ;\n",
        "answer": "the gyroscopes and accelerometers become part of the unit\u2019s fixture to the aircraft structure.\n",
        "choiceone": "only the gyros , and not the accelerometers , become part of the unit\u2019s fixture to the aircraft structure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "gyros and accelerometers need satellite information input to obtain a vertical reference.\n",
        "choicethree": "gyros and accelerometers are mounted on a stabilised platform in the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Standard time for some areas is listed in the Air Almanac as UTC +13 instead of UTC \u201311. The reason for this is ;\n",
        "answer": "keeping the same date as the political and or economical entity to which they belong.\n",
        "choiceone": "the setup of the sunrise/sunset tables.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the fact that they are keeping daylight saving time.\n",
        "choicethree": "the sense of earth rotation.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The accuracy of the manually calculated DR-position of an aircraft is , among other things , affected by ;\n",
        "answer": "the accuracy of the forecasted wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "the accuracy of the adjustment of the position lines for the motion of the aircraft between the last fix and the\n DR-position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the accuracy of the adjustment of the position lines for the motion of the aircraft between the last fix and the\n new DR-position.\n",
        "choicethree": "the accuracy of the actual wind.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The accuracy of the manually calculated DR-position of an aircraft is , among other things , affected by ;\n",
        "answer": "the flight time since the last position update.\n",
        "choiceone": "the accuracy of the adjustment of the position lines for the motion of the aircraft between the last and the new\n DR-position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the accuracy of the adjustment of the position lines for the motion of the aircraft between the last fix and the\n DR-position.\n",
        "choicethree": "the accuracy of the actual wind.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The alignment time , at mid-latitudes , for an Inertial Reference System using laser ring gyros is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "10 MIN.\n",
        "choiceone": "20 MIN.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 MIN.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 MIN.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle between Magnetic North and Compass North is called ;\n",
        "answer": "compass deviation.\n",
        "choiceone": "alignment error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "magnetic variation.\n",
        "choicethree": "compass error.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle between the plane of the ecliptic and the plane of equator is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "23.5\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "25.3\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "66.5\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "27.5\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle between the true great-circle track and the true rhumb-line track joining the following points ; A ( 60\u00b0S 165\u00b0W ) B\n( 60\u00b0S 177\u00b0E ) , at the place of departure A , is ;\n",
        "answer": "7.8\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "5.2\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "15.6\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "9\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle between True North and Magnetic North is called ;\n",
        "answer": "variation.\n",
        "choiceone": "deviation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "compass error.\n",
        "choicethree": "drift.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The annunciator of a remote indicating compass system is used when ;\n",
        "answer": "synchronising the magnetic and gyro compass elements.\n",
        "choiceone": "setting the \u201cheading\u201d pointer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "setting local magnetic variation.\n",
        "choicethree": "compensating for deviation.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The automatic flight control system ( AFCS ) in an aircraft is coupled to the guidance outputs from an inertial navigation\nsystem ( INS ) and the aircraft is flying from waypoint No. 2 ( 60\u00b000'S 070\u00b000'W ) to No. 3 ( 60\u00b000'S 080\u00b000'W ). Comparing the\ninitial track ( \u00b0T ) at 070\u00b000'W and the final track ( \u00b0T ) at 080\u00b000'W , the difference between them is that the initial track is\napproximately ;\n",
        "answer": "9\u00b0 less than the final one. 80\u00b000'W 70\u00b000'W\n",
        "choiceone": "9\u00b0 greater than the final one.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5\u00b0 greater than the final one.\n",
        "choicethree": "5\u00b0 less than the final one. Rhumb Line Track\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The automatic flight control system ( AFCS ) in an aircraft is coupled to the guidance outputs from an inertial navigation\nsystem ( INS ). The aircraft is flying between inserted waypoints No. 3 ( 55\u00b000'N 020\u00b000'W ) and No.4 ( 55\u00b000'N 030\u00b000'W ). With\nDSRTK/STS selected on the CDU , to the nearest whole degree , the initial track read-out from waypoint No. 3 will be ;\n",
        "answer": "274\u00b0 30\u00b000'W 20\u00b000'W\n",
        "choiceone": "270\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "278\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "266\u00b0 55\u00b000'N 270\u00b0T\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The automatic flight control system ( AFCS ) in an aircraft is coupled to the guidance outputs of an inertial navigation\nsystem ( INS ). The aircraft is flying between waypoints No. 4 ( 45\u00b000'N 040\u00b000'W ) and No.5 ( 45\u00b000'N 030\u00b000'W ). If a constant\ndrift angle were experienced between the two waypoints , on arrival over waypoint No. 5 the track has ;\n",
        "answer": "increased by less than 10\u00b0. 40\u00b000'W 30\u00b000'W\n",
        "choiceone": "decreased by less than 10\u00b0.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreased by more than 10\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "remained unchanged.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The automatic flight control system ( AFCS ) in an aircraft is coupled to the guidance outputs of an inertial navigation\nsystem ( INS ). The aircraft is flying between waypoints No. 4 ( 45 00''N 040 00''W ) and No.5 ( 45 00''N 030 00''W ). On arrival over\nwaypoint No. 5 , compared to the TT at waypoint No.4 , the TT has ;\n",
        "answer": "",
        "choiceone": "increased by less than 10\u00ba.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreased by less than 10\u00ba.\n",
        "choicethree": "remained unchanged. 40\u00b000'W 30\u00b000'W\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The automatic flight control system is coupled to the guidance outputs from an inertial navigation system. Which pair of\nlatitudes will give the greatest difference between initial track read-out and the average true course given , in each case , a difference\nof longitude of 10\u00b0 ?\n",
        "answer": "60\u00b0N to 60\u00b0N\n",
        "choiceone": "30\u00b0S to 25\u00b0S\n",
        "choicetwo": "30\u00b0S to 30\u00b0N\n",
        "choicethree": "60\u00b0N to 50\u00b0N\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The chart distance between meridians 10\u00b0 apart at latitude 65\u00b0 North is 3.75 inches. The chart scale at this latitude\napproximates ;\n",
        "answer": "1 : 5 000 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 2 500 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 6 000 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 3 000 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The chart distance between meridians 10\u00b0 apart at latitude 65\u00b0 North is 9.5 cm. The chart scale at this latitude approximates ;\n",
        "answer": "1 : 5 000 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 2 500 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 6 000 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 3 000 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The chart that is generally used for navigation in polar areas is based on a ;\n",
        "answer": "Stereographical projection.\n",
        "choiceone": "Gnomonic projection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Lambert conformal projection.\n",
        "choicethree": "Direct Mercator projection.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The circumference of the earth is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "21600 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "43200 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "5400 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "10800 NM.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The circumference of the parallel of latitude at 60\u00b0N is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "10 800 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "34 641 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "18 706 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "20 000 NM.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The constant of cone of a Lambert conformal conic chart is quoted as 0.3955. At what latitude on the chart is earth\nconvergency correctly represented ?\n",
        "answer": "23\u00b018'\n",
        "choiceone": "66\u00b042'\n",
        "choicetwo": "21\u00b035'\n",
        "choicethree": "68\u00b025'\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The constant of the cone in a Lambert chart is 0.8666500. The angle between the north directions of the meridian in position\nA ( 65\u00b000'N , 018\u00b000'W ) and the meridian of position B ( 75\u00b000'N , 023\u00b000'W ) on the chart is ;\n",
        "answer": "4.3\u00ba\n",
        "choiceone": "5.0\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "5.8\u00ba\n",
        "choicethree": "10.0\u00ba\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The constant of the cone , on a Lambert chart where the convergence angle between longitudes 010\u00b0E and 030\u00b0W is 30\u00b0 , is ;\n",
        "answer": "0.75\n",
        "choiceone": "0.64\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.50\n",
        "choicethree": "0.40\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The convergence factor of a Lambert conformal conic chart is quoted as 0.78535. At what latitude on the chart is earth\nconvergency correctly represented ?\n",
        "answer": "51\u00b045'\n",
        "choiceone": "80\u00b039'\n",
        "choicetwo": "52\u00b005'\n",
        "choicethree": "38\u00b015'\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The data that needs to be inserted into an Inertial Reference System in order to enable the system to make a successful\nalignment for navigation is ;\n",
        "answer": "aircraft position in latitude and longitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "aircraft heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the position of an in-range DME.\n",
        "choicethree": "airport ICAO identifier.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The declination of the sun is defined as ;\n",
        "answer": "the angular distance of the sun north or south of the Celestial equator.\n",
        "choiceone": "the arc from the celestial horizon to the sun measured along a vertical lin perpendicular on the horizon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the arc of the meridian of the sun measured from the nearest pole to the sun.\n",
        "choicethree": "the arc along the celestial sphere from zenith to the sun.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The definition of True North for any observer is ;\n",
        "answer": "the direction of the observer\u2019s meridian to the North Pole.\n",
        "choiceone": "the direction of the observer\u2019s Magnetic North corrected for local variation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the direction of the Greenwich meridia to the North Pole.\n",
        "choicethree": "the reading of the observe\u2019s compass corrected fr deviation and local variation.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u201cdeparture\u201d between positions 60\u00b0N 160\u00b0E and 60\u00b0N \u201cx\u201d is 900 NM. What is the longitude of \u201cx\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "170\u00b0W\n",
        "choiceone": "145\u00b0E\n",
        "choicetwo": "140\u00b0W\n",
        "choicethree": "175\u00b0E\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The diameter of the Earth is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "12 700 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "18 500 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "6 350 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "40 000 km.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The direct reading magnetic compass is made aperiodic ( dead beat ) by ;\n",
        "answer": "keeping the magnetic assembly mass close to the compass point and by using damping wires.\n",
        "choiceone": "using long magnets.\n",
        "choicetwo": "using the lowest acceptable viscosity compass liquid.\n",
        "choicethree": "pendulous suspension of the magnetic assembly.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The direction \u201cmagnetic north\u201d at a position on the earth is ;\n",
        "answer": "the direction of the horizontal component of the earth\u2019s magnetic field at that position.\n",
        "choiceone": "the isogonal to the magnetic North pole.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the great circle between the position and the magnetic north pole.\n",
        "choicethree": "the compass North at that position corrected for variation.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The direction of Magnetic North at a certain position coincides with the direction of ;\n",
        "answer": "the horizontal component of the Earth\u2019s magnetic field.\n",
        "choiceone": "the isoclinic line to the Magnetic North pole.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the great circle to the Magnetic North pole.\n",
        "choicethree": "the isogonic line to the Magnetic North pole.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Directive Force ;\n",
        "answer": "is the component of the Earth\u2019s magnetic field which aligns the compass needle.\n",
        "choiceone": "is about twice as strong on 60\u00baN/S as on the Equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is zero over the geographical poles.\n",
        "choicethree": "equals the vertical component of the Earth\u2019s magnetic field.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The distance along a meridian between 63\u00b055'N and 13\u00b047'S is ;\n",
        "answer": "4662 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "7702 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "5008 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "3008 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The distance between A and B is 90 NM. At a distance of 15 NM from A the aircraft is 4 NM right of course. To reach\ndestination B , the correction angle on the heading should be ;\n",
        "answer": "19\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "21\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "16\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "3\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The distance between A and B is 90 NM. At a distance of 75 NM from A the aircraft is 4 NM right of course. The track\nangle error ( TKE ) is ;\n",
        "answer": "3\u00b0R\n",
        "choiceone": "6\u00b0R\n",
        "choicetwo": "22\u00b0R\n",
        "choicethree": "19\u00b0R\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The distance between point of departure and destination is 340 NM and wind velocity in the whole area is 100\u00b0 / 25 kt. TAS\nis 140kt , True Track is 135\u00b0 and safe endurance 3 hr and 10 min. How long will it take to reach the Point of Safe Return ?\n",
        "answer": "1 hr and 49 min\n",
        "choiceone": "5 hr and 30 min\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 hr and 37 min\n",
        "choicethree": "1 hr and 21 min\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The distance between positions A and B is 180 NM. An aircraft departs position A and after having travelled 60 NM , its\nposition is pinpointed 4 NM left of the intended track. Assuming no change in wind velocity , what alteration of heading must be\nmade in order to arrive at position B ?\n",
        "answer": "6\u00b0 Right\n",
        "choiceone": "2\u00b0 Left\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00b0 Right\n",
        "choicethree": "8\u00b0 Right\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The distance between two waypoints is 200 NM. To calculate compass heading , the pilot used 2\u00b0E magnetic variation\ninstead of 2\u00b0W. Assuming that the forecast W/V applied , what will the off track distance be at the second waypoint ?\n",
        "answer": "14 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "0 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "21 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "7 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The distance measured between two points on a navigation map is 42 mm ( millimetres ). The scale of the chart is\n1:1 600 000. The actual distance between these two point is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "36.30 NM.\n",
        "choiceone": "3.69 NM.\n",
        "choicetwo": "67.20 NM.\n",
        "choicethree": "370.00 NM.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The drift of the azimuth gyro on an inertial unit induces an error in the position given by this unit. \u201ct\u201d being the elapsed time.\nThe total error is ;\n",
        "answer": "proportional to t.\n",
        "choiceone": "sinusoidal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "proportional to t/2.\n",
        "choicethree": "proportional to the square of time , t2.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The duration of civil twilight is the time ;\n",
        "answer": "between sunset and when the centre of the sun is 6\u00ba below the celestial horizon.\n",
        "choiceone": "needed by the sun to move from the apparent height of 0\u00ba to the apparent height of 6\u00ba.\n",
        "choicetwo": "agreed by the international aeronautical authorities which is 12 minutes.\n",
        "choicethree": "between sunset and when the centre of the sun is 12\u00ba below the celestial horizon.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The duration of civil twilight is the time ;\n",
        "answer": "between sunset and when the centre of the sun is 6\u00b0 below the true horizon.\n",
        "choiceone": "agreed by the international aeronautical authorities which is 12 minutes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "needed by the sun to move from the apparent height of 0\u00b0 to the apparent height of 6\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "between sunset and when the centre of the sun is 12\u00b0 below the true horizon.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The equivalent of 70 m/sec is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "136 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "145 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "210 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "35 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The first law of Kepler states ;\n",
        "answer": "Planets move in elliptic orbits with the sun in one of the foci.\n",
        "choiceone": "All planets orbit around the sun at the same speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Planets move around the sun in a circular orbit.\n",
        "choicethree": "The angular speed of the planet in the orbit around the sun is constant.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 10 )\n Image 10\n The fix of the aircraft position is determined by radials from three VOR-stations. The measurements contain small random\nerrors , known systematic errors and unknown systematic errors. The measured radials are corrected for known systematic errors and\nare plotted on a navigation chart. The result is shown at the reference. What is the most probable position of the aircraft ?\n",
        "answer": "1\n",
        "choiceone": "4\n",
        "choicetwo": "2\n",
        "choicethree": "3\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flight log gives the following data ; \u201cTrue track , Drift , True heading , Magnetic variation , Magnetic heading , Compass\ndeviation , Compass heading\u201d. The right solution, in the same order , is ;\n",
        "answer": "119\u00b0 , 3\u00b0L , 122\u00b0 , 2\u00b0E , 120\u00b0 , +4\u00b0 , 116\u00b0.\n",
        "choiceone": "115\u00b0 , 5\u00b0R , 120\u00b0 , 3\u00b0W , 123\u00b0 , +2\u00b0 , 121\u00b0.\n",
        "choicetwo": "125\u00b0 , 2\u00b0R , 123\u00b0 , 2\u00b0W , 121\u00b0 , -4\u00b0 , 117\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "117\u00b0 , 4\u00b0L , 121\u00b0 , 1\u00b0E , 122\u00b0 , -3\u00b0 , 119\u00b0.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following information is displayed on an Inertial Navigation System ;\n GS 520 kt\n True HDG 090\u00b0\n Drift angle 5\u00b0 right\n TAS 480 kt.\n SAT ( static air temperature ) \u201351\u00b0C\n The W/V being experienced is ;\n",
        "answer": "320\u00b0 / 60 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "220\u00b0 / 60 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "225\u00b0 / 60 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "325\u00b0 / 60 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flight log gives the following data ; \u201cTrue track , Drift , True heading , Magnetic variation , Magnetic heading , Compass\ndeviation , Compass heading\u201d. The right solution , in the same order , is ;\n",
        "answer": "119\u00ba , 3\u00baL , 122\u00ba , 2\u00baE , 120\u00ba , +4\u00ba , 116\u00ba.\n",
        "choiceone": "115\u00ba , 5\u00baR , 120\u00ba , 3\u00baW , 123\u00ba , +2\u00ba , 121\u00ba.\n",
        "choicetwo": "117\u00ba , 4\u00baL , 121\u00ba , 1\u00baE , 122\u00ba , \u20133\u00ba , 119\u00ba.\n",
        "choicethree": "125\u00ba , 2\u00baR , 123\u00ba , 2\u00baW , 121\u00ba , \u20134\u00ba , 117\u00ba.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following points are entered into an inertial navigation system ( INS ) ;\n WPT 1 : 60\u00b0N 30\u00b0W\n WPT 2 : 60\u00b0N 20\u00b0W\n WPT 3 : 60\u00b0N 10\u00b0W\n The inertial navigation system is connected to the automatic pilot on route ( 1-2-3 ). The track change when passing WPT 2\nwill be approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "a 9\u00b0 decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "a 4\u00b0 decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "a 9\u00b0 increase.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The force acting on the needle of a direct reading compass varies ;\n",
        "answer": "directly with the horizontal component of the earth\u2019s magnetic field.\n",
        "choiceone": "directly with the vertical component of the earth\u2019s magnetic field.\n",
        "choicetwo": "inversely with the horizontal component of the earth\u2019s magnetic field.\n",
        "choicethree": "inversely with both vertical and horizontal components of the earth\u2019s magnetic field.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The full alignment of the stable platform of an Inertial Navigation System ;\n",
        "answer": "is only possible on the ground when the aircraft is at a complete stop.\n",
        "choiceone": "may be carried out at any time so long as an accurate position is inserted into the system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "may be carried out during any phase of flight.\n",
        "choicethree": "may be carried out on the ground or when in straight and level flight.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 6 )\n Image 6\n The GMT of Morning Civil Twilight at ( 66\u00ba48'N , 095\u00ba26'W ) on 27th of January is ?\n",
        "answer": "1436 GMT\n",
        "choiceone": "0814 GMT\n",
        "choicetwo": "1541 GMT\n",
        "choicethree": "0927 GMT\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 6 )\n Image 6\n The GMT of Sunrise at ( 66\u00ba48'N , 095\u00ba26'W ) on 27th of January is ?\n",
        "answer": "1549 GMT\n",
        "choiceone": "0814 GMT\n",
        "choicetwo": "1541 GMT\n",
        "choicethree": "0927 GMT\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Great Circle bearing from A ( 70\u00b0S 030\u00b0W ) to B ( 70\u00b0S 060\u00b0E ) is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "132\u00b0( T )\n",
        "choiceone": "312\u00b0( T )\n",
        "choicetwo": "048\u00b0( T )\n",
        "choicethree": "090\u00b0( T )\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The great circle bearing of position B from position A in the Northern Hemisphere is 040\u00b0. If the Conversion Angle is 4\u00b0 ,\nwhat is the great circle bearing of A from B ?\n",
        "answer": "228\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "220\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "224\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "212\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The great circle distance between position A ( 59\u00b034.1'N 008\u00b008.4'E ) and B ( 30\u00b025.9'N 171\u00b051.6'W ) is ;\n",
        "answer": "5400 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "10800 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "10800 km\n",
        "choicethree": "2700 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The great circle track measured at A ( 45\u00b000'N 010\u00b000'W ) from A to B ( 45\u00b000'N 019\u00b000'W ) is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "273\u00ba\n",
        "choiceone": "090\u00ba\n",
        "choicetwo": "270\u00ba\n",
        "choicethree": "093\u00ba 019\u00b000'W 010\u00b000'W\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The horizontal component of the earth\u2019s magnetic field ;\n",
        "answer": "is very small close to the magnetic poles.\n",
        "choiceone": "is maximum at the magnetic poles.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is minimum at the magnetic equator.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase with an increase of the magnetic latitude.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The horizontal component of the earth\u2019s magnetic field ;\n",
        "answer": "is stronger closer to the magnetic equator.\n",
        "choiceone": "weakens with increasing distance from the nearer magnetic pole.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is approximately the same at all magnetic latitudes less than 60\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "weakens with increasing distance from the magnetic poles.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ICAO definition of ETA is the ;\n",
        "answer": "estimated time of arrival at destination.\n",
        "choiceone": "estimated time of arrival at an en-route point or fix.\n",
        "choicetwo": "estimated time en route.\n",
        "choicethree": "actual time of arrival at a point or fix.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The initial great circle track from A to B is 080\u00b0 and the rhumb line track is 083\u00b0. What is the initial great circle track from B\nto A and in which Hemisphere are the two positions located ?\n",
        "answer": "266\u00b0 and in the northern hemisphere. True North\n",
        "choiceone": "260\u00b0 and in the southern hemisphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "266\u00b0 and in the southern hemisphere.\n",
        "choicethree": "260\u00b0 and in the northern hemisphere.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The length of the apparent solar day varies continuously throughout a year. This is caused by ;\n",
        "answer": "the tilt of the earth\u2019s axis and the elliptical orbit of the earth around the sun.\n",
        "choiceone": "the fact that the earth is closest to the sun around the 1st of January.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the equation of time.\n",
        "choicethree": "the fact that the eart is closest to the sun around the 1st of July.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lines on the earth\u2019s surface that join points of equal magnetic variation are called ;\n",
        "answer": "isogonals.\n",
        "choiceone": "isotachs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "isogrives.\n",
        "choicethree": "isoclines.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The local hour angle of the mean sun at 1200 LMT is ;\n",
        "answer": "000\n",
        "choiceone": "180\n",
        "choicetwo": "270\n",
        "choicethree": "090\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Local Mean Time at longitude 095\u00b020'W , at 0000 UTC , is ;\n",
        "answer": "1738:40 previous day.\n",
        "choiceone": "0621:20 previous day.\n",
        "choicetwo": "0621:20 same day.\n",
        "choicethree": "1738:40 same day.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The long term periodic change in the Earth\u2019s Magnetic Field ;\n",
        "answer": "is reflected in the slow movement of the magnetic poles.\n",
        "choiceone": "affects mainly the compass deviation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is caused by sunspot activity.\n",
        "choicethree": "is caused by the westerly movement of the geographic North Pole.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason for mounting the detector unit of a remote reading compass in the wingtip of an aeroplane is ;\n",
        "answer": "to minimise the amount of deviation caused by aircraft magnetism and electrical circuits.\n",
        "choiceone": "to maximise the units exposure to the earth\u2019s magnetic field.\n",
        "choicetwo": "by having detector units on both wingtips , to cancel out the deviation effects caused by the aircraft structure.\n",
        "choicethree": "to ensure that the unit is in the most accessible position on the aircraft for ease of maintenance.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason for the occurrence of seasons on earth is ;\n",
        "answer": "the inclination of the earth axis with regard to the plane of the ecliptic.\n",
        "choiceone": "the distance between the sun and the earth.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the length of the day as stated by the second law of Kepler.\n",
        "choicethree": "the elliptical form of the orbit of the earth around the sun.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason for usually mounting the detector unit of a remote indicating compass in the wingtip of an aeroplane is to ;\n",
        "answer": "reduce the amount of deviation caused by aircraft magnetism and electrical circuits.\n",
        "choiceone": "place it where it will not be subjected to electrical or magnetic interference from the aircraft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "facilitate easy maintenance of the unit and increase its exposure to the Earth\u2019s magnetic field.\n",
        "choicethree": "place it in a position where there is no electrical wiring to cause deviation errors.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main reason that day and night , throughout the year , have different duration , is due to the ;\n",
        "answer": "inclination of the ecliptic to the equator.\n",
        "choiceone": "earth\u2019s rotation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "gravitational effect of the sun and moon on the speed of rotation of the earth.\n",
        "choicethree": "relative speed of the sun along the ecliptic.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum difference between geocentric and geodetic latitude occurs at about ;\n",
        "answer": "45\u00b0 North and South.\n",
        "choiceone": "90\u00b0 North and South.\n",
        "choicetwo": "60\u00b0 North and South.\n",
        "choicethree": "0\u00b0 North and South ( equator ).\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum difference in distance when proceeding along the great circle between two positions , in stead of the rhumb\nline , will occur ;\n",
        "answer": "on East-West tracks at high latitudes.\n",
        "choiceone": "on East-West tracks at low latitudes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on North-South tracks at high latitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "on North-South tracks at low latitudes.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The nominal scale of a Lambert conformal conic chart is the ;\n",
        "answer": "scale at the standard parallels.\n",
        "choiceone": "mean scale between pole and equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "scale at the equator.\n",
        "choicethree": "mean scale between the parallels of the secant cone.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The north and south magnetic poles are the only positions on the earth\u2019s surface where ;\n",
        "answer": "a freely suspended compass needle would stand vertical.\n",
        "choiceone": "a position where the horizontal component of the earth\u2019s magnetic field is a maximum.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the value of magnetic variation equals 90\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "a freely suspended compass needle will stand horizontal.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The outer marker of an ILS with a 3\u00b0 glide slope is located 4.6 NM from the threshold. Assuming a glide slope height of 50\nFT above the threshold , the approximate height of an aircraft passing the outer marker is ;\n",
        "answer": "1450 FT 3\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "1400 FT\n",
        "choicetwo": "1350 FT\n",
        "choicethree": "1300 FT\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The parallels on a Lambert Conformal Conic chart are represented by ;\n",
        "answer": "arcs of concentric circles.\n",
        "choiceone": "parabolic lines.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hyperbolic lines.\n",
        "choicethree": "straight lines.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The platform of an inertial navigation system ( INS ) is maintained at right angles to the local vertical by applying\ncorrections for the effects of ;\n",
        "answer": "aircraft manoeuvres , earth rotation , transport wander and coriolis.\n",
        "choiceone": "gyroscopic inertia , earth rotation and real drift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "vertical velocities , earth precession, centrifugal forces and transport drift.\n",
        "choicethree": "movement in the yawing plane , secondary precession and pendulous oscillation.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The positions A ( 30\u00b000'N , 017\u00b030'E ) and B at longitude ( 30\u00b000'N , 023\u00b030'E ) are plotted on a Lambert chart with a\nconstant of the cone of 0.5. A and B are connected by a straight line. The True Track measured at A is 088.5\u00b0. What is the True Track\nmeasured at B ?\n",
        "answer": "091.5\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "094.5\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "082.5\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "085.5\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The principle of \u201cSchuler Tuning\u201d as applied to the operation of Inertial Navigation Systems/ Inertial Reference Systems is\napplicable to ;\n",
        "answer": "both gyro-stabilised platform and \u201cstrapdown\u201d systems.\n",
        "choiceone": "only to \u201cstrapdown\u201d laser gyro systems.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only gyro-stabilised systems.\n",
        "choicethree": "both gyro-stabilised and laser gyro systems but only when operating in the non \u201cstrapdown\u201d mode.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of the TAS input , from the air data computer , to the Inertial Navigation System is for ;\n",
        "answer": "the calculation of wind velocity.\n",
        "choiceone": "position update in Attitude mode.\n",
        "choicetwo": "position update in Navigation mode.\n",
        "choicethree": "the calculation of drift.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The QNH , given by a station at 2500 ft , is 980 hPa.The elevation of the highest obstacle along a route is 8000 ft and the\nOAT = ISA-10\u00b0C. When an aircraft , on route has to descend the minimum indicated altitude ( QNH on the subscale of the altimeter )\nto maintain a clearance of 2000 ft , will be ;\n",
        "answer": "10.400 ft\n",
        "choiceone": "10.000 ft\n",
        "choicetwo": "11.200 ft\n",
        "choicethree": "9.700 ft\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reason that the solar day lasts longer than the sidereal day is that ;\n",
        "answer": "both the direction of rotation of the Earth around its axis and its orbital rotation around the sun are the same.\n",
        "choiceone": "the orbital track of the earth around the sun is an ellipse.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the orbital speed of the earth around its axis diminishes slowly.\n",
        "choicethree": "the sun has an own movement through the universe opposite to the movement of the earth due to the\n gravitational forces of celestial bodies.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reported surface wind from the Control Tower is 240\u00b0/35 kt. Runway 30 ( 300\u00b0 ). What is the cross-wind component ?\n",
        "answer": "30 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "24 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "27 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "21 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The resultant of the first integration from the north/south accelerometer of an inertial navigation system ( INS ) in the NAV\nMODE is ;\n",
        "answer": "velocity along the local meridian.\n",
        "choiceone": "change latitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "groundspeed.\n",
        "choicethree": "latitude.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The resultant of the first integration of the output from the east/west accelerometer of an inertial navigation system ( INS ) in\nNAV MODE is ;\n",
        "answer": "velocity along the local parallel of latitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "vehicle longitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "change of longitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "departure.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rhumb-line distance between points A ( 60\u00b000'N 002\u00b030'E ) and B ( 60\u00b000'N 007\u00b030'W ) is ;\n",
        "answer": "300 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "150 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "600 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "450 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rhumb line track between position A ( 45\u00b000'N , 010\u00b000'W ) and position B ( 48\u00b030'N , 015\u00b000'W ) is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "315\n",
        "choiceone": "330\n",
        "choicetwo": "300\n",
        "choicethree": "345\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The scale on a Lambert conformal conic chart ;\n",
        "answer": "is constant along a parallel of latitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "varies slightly as a function of latitude and longitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is constant along a meridian of longitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "is constant across the whole map.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sensors of an INS measure ;\n",
        "answer": "acceleration.\n",
        "choiceone": "precession.\n",
        "choicetwo": "velocity.\n",
        "choicethree": "the horizontal component of the earth\u2019s rotation.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The SR/SS table for the 23rd of February at latitude 40\u00baN gives ; SR = 06:44 , SS = 17:44. At 12:00 Central European Time\n( UTC+1 ) at 40\u00baN ;\n",
        "answer": "the sun rises 64\u00baW.\n",
        "choiceone": "the sun rises at 79\u00baW.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the sun sets at 86\u00baE.\n",
        "choicethree": "the sun sets at 116\u00baE.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The standard parallels of a Lambert chart are 26\u00b0N and 48\u00b0N and the stated scale is 1 : 2 500 000. Which statement is\ncorrect ?\n",
        "answer": "The scale at 28\u00b0N is smaller than the scale at 24\u00b0N.\n",
        "choiceone": "The scale at 37\u00b0N is larger than the scale at 20\u00b0N.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The scale at 46\u00b0N is larger than the scale at 50\u00b0N.\n",
        "choicethree": "The scale at 30\u00b0N is smaller than the scale at 37\u00b0N.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The standard parallels of a Lambert\u2019s conical orthomorphic projection are 07\u00b040'N and 38\u00b020' N. The constant of the cone\nfor this chart is ;\n",
        "answer": "0.39\n",
        "choiceone": "0.60\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.42\n",
        "choicethree": "0.92\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term drift refers to the wander of the axis of a gyro in ;\n",
        "answer": "the horizontal plane.\n",
        "choiceone": "the vertical and horizontal plane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the vertical plane.\n",
        "choicethree": "any plane.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The time difference in Local Mean Time between sunset at positions A ( 50\u00b0N , 120\u00b0E ) and B ( 50\u00b0S , 120\u00b0E ) on the 21st\nof November is ;\n",
        "answer": "some hours and the sun rises earlier in B than in A.\n",
        "choiceone": "some hours and the sun rises earlier in A than in B.\n",
        "choicetwo": "negligible small because A and B are located at the same meridian.\n",
        "choicethree": "negligible small because A and B are located symmetrically to the equator.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The time interval between sunrise and sunset is dependent on ;\n",
        "answer": "The declination of the sun and the latitude of the observer.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date and the longitude of the observer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The latitude and the longitude of the observer.\n",
        "choicethree": "The inclination of the axis of the earth and the longitude of the observer.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The total length of the 53\u00b0N parallel of latitude on a direct Mercator chart is 133 cm. What is the approximate scale of the\nchart at latitude 30\u00b0S ?\n",
        "answer": "1 : 26 000 000\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : 21 000 000\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : 18 000 000\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : 30 000 000\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The True course in the flight log is 270\u00ba, the forecast wind is 045\u00ba(T)/15kt and the TAS is 120 kt. After 15 minutes of flying\nwith the planned TAS and TH the aircraft is 3 NM South of the intended track and 2.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position. The\nTrack angle error ( TKE ) is ;\n",
        "answer": "5\u00b0L\n",
        "choiceone": "6\u00b0R\n",
        "choicetwo": "3\u00b0R\n",
        "choicethree": "2\u00b0L\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The two standard parallels of a conical Lambert projection are at N10\u00b040' and N41\u00b020'. The cone constant of this chart is\napproximatively ;\n",
        "answer": "0.44\n",
        "choiceone": "0.66\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.18\n",
        "choicethree": "0.90\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-2304A )\n Annex 061-2304A\n The UTC of sunrise on 6 December at WINNIPEG ( Canada ) ( 49\u00b050'N 097\u00b030'W ) is ;\n",
        "answer": "1413\n",
        "choiceone": "0930\n",
        "choicetwo": "0113\n",
        "choicethree": "2230\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The value of magnetic variation ;\n",
        "answer": "has a maximum of 180\u00b0.\n",
        "choiceone": "varies between a maximum of 45\u00b0 East and 45\u00b0 West.\n",
        "choicetwo": "must be 0\u00b0 at the magnetic equator.\n",
        "choicethree": "cannot exceed 90\u00b0.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thule VOR is located at ( 76\u00b032'N , 68\u00b015'W ). A Polar Stereographic chart with the grid aligned with the Greenwich\nmeridian is to be used. The local variation is 75\u00b0W. Which grid track must be maintained to track radial 210 ( M ) inbound ?\n",
        "answer": "023\u00b0(G)\n",
        "choiceone": "323\u00b0(G)\n",
        "choicetwo": "203\u00b0(G)\n",
        "choicethree": "285\u00b0(G)\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Transverse Mercator projections are used for ;\n",
        "answer": "maps of large north/south extent.\n",
        "choiceone": "radio navigation charts in equatorial areas.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maps of large east/west extent in equatorial areas.\n",
        "choicethree": "plotting charts in equatorial areas.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "True Heading of an aircraft is 265\u00b0 and TAS is 290 kt. If W/V is 210\u00b0 / 35kt , what is True Track and GS ?\n",
        "answer": "271\u00b0 and 272 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "260\u00b0 and 315 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "259\u00b0 and 305 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "259\u00b0 and 272 kt\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use Europe Low Altitude Enroute Chart E(LO) 1A )\n Europe Low Altitude Enroute Chart E(LO) 1A\n Two consecutive waypoints of a flight plan are Stornoway VORDME ( N58\u00b012.4' , W006\u00b011.0' ) and Glasgow VORDME\n( N55\u00b052.2' , W 004\u00b026.7' ). During the flight the Actual Time Over Stornoway is 11:15 UTC and the Estimated Time Over Glasgow\nis 11:38 UTC. At 11:21 UTC the fix of the aircraft is exactly over reporting point RONAR. What is the Revised UTC over Glasgow ,\nbased on this last fix ?\n",
        "answer": "11:36\n",
        "choiceone": "11:33\n",
        "choicetwo": "11:38\n",
        "choicethree": "11:34\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two places are situated on the same parallel in the Southern Hemisphere. The great circle , rhumb line and the straight line\nbetween these places are drawn on a Polar Stereographic Projection. Which statement is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The great circle is situated between the parallel and the straight line , because the concave side of the great\n circle is always pointed towards the pole.\n",
        "choiceone": "The great circle is situated between the parallel and the straight line , because the concave side of the great\n circle is always pointed towards the equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The rhumb line is situated between the great circle and the straight line because the shortest distance between\n to places on Earth is the great circle.\n",
        "choicethree": "The correct sequence from North to South is ; Great circle , straight line , rhumb line.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two places on the parallel of 47\u00baS lie 757.8 km apart. Calculate the difference in longitude ;\n",
        "answer": "10\u00ba00'\n",
        "choiceone": "4\u00ba51'\n",
        "choicetwo": "4\u00ba39'\n",
        "choicethree": "9\u00ba19'\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two points A and B are 1000 NM apart TAS = 490 kt. On the flight between A and B the equivalent headwind is \u201320 kt. On\nthe return leg between B and A , the equivalent headwind is +40 kt. What distance from A , along the route A to B , is the Point of\nEqual Time ( PET ) ?\n",
        "answer": "530 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "455 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "470 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "500 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two positions plotted on a polar stereographic chart , A ( 80\u00b0N 000\u00b0 ) and B ( 70\u00b0N 102\u00b0W ) are joined by a straight line\nwhose highest latitude is reached at 035\u00b0W. At point B , the true course is ;\n",
        "answer": "203\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "247\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "023\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "305\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Variation at an NDB is 9W. Variation at the aircraft is 11W. The true track of the great circle to the NDB from the aircraft ,\nat the aircraft , is 101.5. The magnetic bearing of the NDB from the aircraft is ;\n",
        "answer": "112.5\n",
        "choiceone": "114.5\n",
        "choicetwo": "110.5\n",
        "choicethree": "108.5\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Waypoints can be entered in an INS memory in different formats. In which of the following formats can waypoints be\nentered into all INSs ?\n",
        "answer": "geographic coordinates.\n",
        "choiceone": "hexadecimal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "bearing and distance.\n",
        "choicethree": "by waypoints name.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What additional information is required to be input to an Inertial Navigation System ( INS ) in order to obtain an W/V\nreadout ?\n",
        "answer": "TAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mach Number.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "Altitude and OAT.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are , in order of highest priority followed by lowest , the two levels of message produced by the CDU of the B737-400\nElectronic Flight Instrument System ?\n",
        "answer": "Alerting and Advisory.\n",
        "choiceone": "Priority and Alerting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Urgent and Routine.\n",
        "choicethree": "Urgent and Advisory.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What feature is shown on the chart at position N5211 W00931 ?\n",
        "answer": "KERRY/Farranfore aerodrome\n",
        "choiceone": "Connemara aerodrome\n",
        "choicetwo": "Punchestown aerodrome\n",
        "choicethree": "Waterford NDB\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What feature is shown on the chart at position N5212 W00612 ?\n",
        "answer": "TUSKAR ROCK LT.H. NDB\n",
        "choiceone": "KERRY/Farranfore aerodrome\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clonbullogue aerodrome\n",
        "choicethree": "WTD NDB\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What feature is shown on the chart at position N5311 W00637 ?\n",
        "answer": "Punchestown aerodrome\n",
        "choiceone": "Clonbullogue aerodrome\n",
        "choicetwo": "Connemara aerodrome\n",
        "choicethree": "KERRY/Farranfore aerodrome\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What feature is shown on the chart at position N5351 W00917 ?\n",
        "answer": "Castlebar aerodrome\n",
        "choiceone": "Brittas Bay aerodrome\n",
        "choicetwo": "Connaught aerodrome\n",
        "choicethree": "Connemara aerodrome\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What feature is shown on the chart at position N5417 W01005 ?\n",
        "answer": "EAGLE ISLAND LT.H. NDB\n",
        "choiceone": "Belmullet aerodrome\n",
        "choicetwo": "Clonbullogue aerodrome\n",
        "choicethree": "Carnmore aerodrome\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is meant by \u201cAphelion\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "The point of the earth\u2019s orbit furthest away from the sun.\n",
        "choiceone": "The point of the earth\u2019s orbit closest to the sun.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The point of the sun\u2019s orbit closest to the earth.\n",
        "choicethree": "The point of the sun\u2019s orbit furthest away from the earth.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0M ) and distance between BAL VOR ( N5318.0 W00626.9 ) and SLG NDB ( N5416.7\nW00836.0 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "316\u00b0 - 96 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "308\u00b0 - 98 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "262\u00b0 - 86 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "128\u00b0 - 99 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0M ) and distance between CRK VOR ( N5150.4 W00829.7 ) and CRN NDB ( N5318.1\nW00856.5 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "357\u00b0 - 89 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "169\u00b0 - 91 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "177\u00b0 - 92 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "349\u00b0 - 90 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0M ) and distance between CRN NDB ( N5318.1 W00856.5 ) and BEL VOR ( N5439.7\nW00613.8 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "058\u00b0 - 128 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "238\u00b0 - 130 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "229\u00b0 - 125 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "089\u00b0 - 95 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0M ) and distance between CRN NDB ( N5318.1 W00856.5 ) and WTD NDB ( N5211.3\nW00705.0 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "142\u00b0 - 95 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "315\u00b0 - 94 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "322\u00b0 - 95 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "135\u00b0 - 96 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0M ) and distance between KER NDB ( N5210.9 W00931.5 ) and CRN NDB ( N5318.1\nW00856.5 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "025\u00b0 - 70 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "197\u00b0 - 71 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "017\u00b0 - 70 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "205\u00b0 - 71 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0M ) and distance between WTD NDB ( N5211.3 W00705.0 ) and BAL VOR ( N5318.0\nW00626.9 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "026\u00b0 - 71 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "018\u00b0 - 153 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "206\u00b0 - 71 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "198\u00b0 - 72 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0M ) and distance between WTD NDB ( N5211.3 W00705.0 ) and KER NDB ( N5210.9\nW00931.5 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "278\u00b0 - 90 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "090\u00b0 - 91 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "098\u00b0 - 90 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "270\u00b0 - 89 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0T ) and distance between BAL VOR ( N5318.0 W00626.9 ) and CFN NDB ( N5502.6\nW00820.4 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "327\u00b0 - 124 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "325\u00b0 - 128 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "320\u00b0 - 127 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "335\u00b0 - 128 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0T ) and distance between BAL VOR ( N5318.0 W00626.9 ) and CRN NDB ( N5318.1\nW00856.5 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "270\u00b0 - 90 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "278\u00b0 - 89 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "272\u00b0 - 89 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "268\u00b0 - 91 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0T ) and distance between CON VOR ( N5354.8 W00849.1 ) and BEL VOR ( N5439.7\nW00613.8 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "063\u00b0 - 101 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "293\u00b0 - 98 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "113\u00b0 - 97 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "071\u00b0 - 100 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0T ) and distance between CRN NDB ( N5318.1 W00856.5 ) and EKN NDB ( N5423.6\nW00738.7 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "035\u00b0 - 80 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "031\u00b0 - 81 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "044\u00b0 - 82 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "042\u00b0 - 83 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0T ) and distance between SHA VOR ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) and CON VOR ( N5354.8\nW00849.1 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "002\u00b0 - 72 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "010\u00b0 - 71 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "006\u00b0 - 71 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "358\u00b0 - 72 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0T ) and distance between SLG NDB ( N5416.7 W00836.0 ) and CFN NDB ( N5502.6\nW00820.4 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "011\u00b0 - 47 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "348\u00b0 - 46 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "191\u00b0 - 45 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "020\u00b0 - 46 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0T ) and distance between WTD NDB ( N5211.3 W00705.0 ) and FOY NDB ( N5234.0\nW00911.7 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "286\u00b0 - 81 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "294\u00b0 - 80 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "075\u00b0 - 81 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "277\u00b0 - 83 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the average track ( \u00b0T ) and distance between WTD NDB ( N5211.3 W00705.0 ) and SLG NDB ( N5416.7\nW00836.0 ) ?\n",
        "answer": "336\u00b0 - 137 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "156\u00b0 - 136 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "344\u00b0 - 139 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "164\u00b0 - 138 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the chart distance between longitudes 179\u00b0E and 175\u00b0W on a direct Mercator chart with a scale of 1 : 5 000 000 at\nthe equator ?\n",
        "answer": "133 mm\n",
        "choiceone": "106 mm\n",
        "choicetwo": "167 mm\n",
        "choicethree": "72 mm\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the constant of the cone for a Lambert conic projection whose standard parallels are at 50\u00b0N and 70\u00b0N ?\n",
        "answer": "0.866\n",
        "choiceone": "0.766\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.500\n",
        "choicethree": "0.941\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the correct definition of latitude of a position on the earth ?\n",
        "answer": "Latitude is the angle between the plane of the equator and the line from the centre of the earth to the position.\n",
        "choiceone": "Latitude is the angle between the plane of the Prime Meridian and the plane of the meridian of the position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Latitude is the angle between the plane of the ecliptic and the parallel of the position.\n",
        "choicethree": "Latitude is the angle between the earth\u2019s rotational axis and the line from the centre of the earth to the\n position.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 6 )\n Image 6\n What is the duration of morning Civil Twilight at ( 66\u00ba48'N , 095\u00ba26'W ) on 27th of January ?\n",
        "answer": "01 h 13 m\n",
        "choiceone": "01 h 02 m\n",
        "choicetwo": "08 h 14 m\n",
        "choicethree": "09 h 27 m\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect on the Mach number and TAS in an aircraft that is climbing with constant CAS ?\n",
        "answer": "Mach number increases , TAS increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mach number increases , TAS remains constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mach number decreases , TAS decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "Mach number remains constant , TAS increases.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the final position after the following rhumb line tracks and distances have been followed from position 60\u00b000'N\n030\u00b000'W ?\n South for 3600 NM , East for 3600 NM , North for 3600 NM , West for 3600 NM\n The final position of the aircraft is ;\n",
        "answer": "60\u00b000'N 090\u00b000'W\n",
        "choiceone": "59\u00b000'N 090\u00b000'W\n",
        "choicetwo": "59\u00b000'N 060\u00b000'W\n",
        "choicethree": "60\u00b000'N 030\u00b000'E\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the highest latitude listed below at which the sun will reach an altitude of 90\u00b0 above the horizon at some time during\nthe year ?\n",
        "answer": "23.5\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "45\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "0\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "66\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the ISA temperature value at FL 330 ?\n",
        "answer": "\u201351\u00b0C\n",
        "choiceone": "\u201356\u00b0C\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u201381\u00b0C\n",
        "choicethree": "\u201366\u00b0C\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the length of one degree of longitude at latitude 60\u00b0 South ?\n",
        "answer": "30 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "52 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "90 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "60 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the local mean time , position 65\u00b025'N 123\u00b075'W at 2200 UTC ?\n",
        "answer": "1345\n",
        "choiceone": "0615\n",
        "choicetwo": "0815\n",
        "choicethree": "2200\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the longitude of a position 6 NM to the east of 58\u00b042'N 094\u00b000'W ?\n",
        "answer": "093\u00b048.5'W\n",
        "choiceone": "093\u00b054.0'W\n",
        "choicetwo": "094\u00b012.0'W\n",
        "choicethree": "093\u00b053.1'W\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n What is the meaning of aeronautical chart symbol No.15 ?\n",
        "answer": "Aeronautical ground light\n",
        "choiceone": "Visual reference point\n",
        "choicetwo": "Hazard to aerial navigation\n",
        "choicethree": "Lighthouse\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12621A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n What is the meaning of aeronautical chart symbol No.16 ?\n",
        "answer": "Lightship\n",
        "choiceone": "Off-shore helicopter landing platform\n",
        "choicetwo": "Off-shore lighthouse\n",
        "choicethree": "Shipwreck showing above the surface at low tide\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the meaning of the term \u201cstandard time\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "It is the time set by the legal authorities for a country or part of a country.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is another term for UTC.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is an expression for local mean time.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is the time zone system applicable only in the USA.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name given to an Inertial Reference System ( IRS ) which has the gyros and accelerometers as part of the unit\u2019s\nfixture to the aircraft structure ?\n",
        "answer": "Strapdown\n",
        "choiceone": "Solid state\n",
        "choicetwo": "Rigid\n",
        "choicethree": "Ring laser\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from BEL VOR/DME ( N5439.7 W00613.8 ) to position N5410 W00710 ?\n",
        "answer": "236\u00b0 - 44 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "320\u00b0 - 44 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "223\u00b0 - 36 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "333\u00b0 - 36 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from BEL VOR/DME ( N5439.7 W00613.8 ) to position N5440 W00730 ?\n",
        "answer": "278\u00b0 - 44 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "090\u00b0 - 46 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "098\u00b0 - 45 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "278\u00b0 - 10 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from BEL VOR/DME ( N5439.7 W00613.8 ) to position N5500 W00700 ?\n",
        "answer": "315\u00b0 - 34 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "296\u00b0 - 65 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "222\u00b0 - 48 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "126\u00b0 - 33 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from CON VOR/DME ( N5354.8 W00849.1 ) to position N5330 W00930 ?\n",
        "answer": "233\u00b0 - 35 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "165\u00b0 - 27 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "025\u00b0 - 38 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "335\u00b0 - 43 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from CON VOR/DME ( N5354.8 W00849.1 ) to position N5340 W00820 ?\n",
        "answer": "140\u00b0 - 23 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "119\u00b0 - 42 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "311\u00b0 - 22 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "240\u00b0 - 24 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from CON VOR/DME ( N5354.8 W00849.1 ) to position N5400 W00800 ?\n",
        "answer": "088\u00b0 - 29 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "094\u00b0 - 64 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "320\u00b0 - 8 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "260\u00b0 - 30 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from CON VOR/DME ( N5354.8 W00849.1 ) to position N5430 W00900 ?\n",
        "answer": "358\u00b0 - 36 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "049\u00b0 - 45 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "214\u00b0 - 26 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "169\u00b0 - 35 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from CRK VOR/DME ( N5150.4 W00829.7 ) to position N5140 W00730 ?\n",
        "answer": "113\u00b0 - 38 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "104\u00b0 - 76 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "106\u00b0 - 38 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "293\u00b0 - 39 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from CRK VOR/DME ( N5150.4 W00829.7 ) to position N5210 W00920 ?\n",
        "answer": "311\u00b0 - 38 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "295\u00b0 - 38 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "170\u00b0 - 22 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "350\u00b0 - 22 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from CRK VOR/DME ( N5150.4 W00829.7 ) to position N5220 W00810 ?\n",
        "answer": "030\u00b0 - 33 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "014\u00b0 - 33 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "220\u00b0 - 40 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "048\u00b0 - 40 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from CRK VOR/DME ( N5150.4 W00829.7 ) to position N5230 W00750 ?\n",
        "answer": "039\u00b0 - 48 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "023\u00b0 - 48 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "017\u00b0 - 43 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "024\u00b0 - 43 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from SHA VOR/DME ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) to position N5210 W00920 ?\n",
        "answer": "214\u00b0 - 37 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "354\u00b0 - 34 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "346\u00b0 - 34 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "198\u00b0 - 37 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from SHA VOR/DME ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) to position N5220 W00810 ?\n",
        "answer": "139\u00b0 - 35 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "129\u00b0 - 46 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "212\u00b0 - 26 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "132\u00b0 - 36 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from SHA VOR/DME ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) to position N5300 W00940 ?\n",
        "answer": "309\u00b0 - 33 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "057\u00b0 - 27 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "293\u00b0 - 33 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "324\u00b0 - 17 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n What is the radial and DME distance from SHA VOR/DME ( N5243.3 W00853.1 ) to position N5310 W00830 ?\n",
        "answer": "035\u00b0 - 30 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "207\u00b0 - 31 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "070\u00b0 - 58 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "019\u00b0 - 31 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the ratio between the litre and the US-GAL ?\n",
        "answer": "1 US-GAL equals 3.78 litres.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 litre equals 4.55 US-GAL.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 US-GAL equals 4.55 litres.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 litre equals 3.78 US-GAL.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the rhumb line distance , in nautical miles , between two positions on latitude 60\u00b0N , that are separated by 10\u00b0 of\nlongitude ?\n",
        "answer": "300 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "520 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "866 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "600 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the source of magnetic variation information in a Flight Management System ( FMS ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Magnetic variation information is stored in each IRS memory , it is applied to the true heading calculated by\n the respective IRS.\n",
        "choiceone": "The main directional gyro which is coupled to the magnetic sensor ( flux valve ) positioned in the wingtip.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Magnetic variation is calculated by each IRS based on the respective IRS position and the aircraft magnetic\n heading.\n",
        "choicethree": "The FMS calculates MH and MT from the FMC position.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the time required to travel along the parallel of latitude 60\u00b0 N between meridians 010\u00b0E and 030\u00b0W at a groundspeed\nof 480 kt ?\n",
        "answer": "2 HR 30 MIN\n",
        "choiceone": "1 HR 45 MIN\n",
        "choicetwo": "5 HR 00 MIN\n",
        "choicethree": "1 HR 15 MIN\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the validity period of the \u201cpermanent\u201d data base of aeronautical information stored in the FMC In the B737-400\nFlight Management System ?\n",
        "answer": "28 days.\n",
        "choiceone": "3 calendar months.\n",
        "choicetwo": "one calendar month.\n",
        "choicethree": "14 days.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the value of the convergence factor on a Polar Stereographic chart ?\n",
        "answer": "1.0\n",
        "choiceone": "0.0\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.866\n",
        "choicethree": "0.5\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the value of the magnetic dip at the magnetic south pole ?\n",
        "answer": "90\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "60\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "0\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "45\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What may cause a difference between a DR-position and a Fix ?\n",
        "answer": "The difference between the actual wind and forecasted wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "The difference between no-wind and the actual wind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The difference between no-wind and the forecasted wind.\n",
        "choicethree": "The difference between the magnetic and the true wind direction.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When accelerating on a westerly heading in the northern hemisphere , the compass card of a direct reading magnetic compass\nwill turn ;\n",
        "answer": "anti-clockwise giving an apparent turn towards the north.\n",
        "choiceone": "clockwise giving an apparent turn towards the north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "anti-clockwise giving an apparent turn towards the south.\n",
        "choicethree": "clockwise giving an apparent turn towards the south.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When accelerating on an easterly heading in the Northern hemisphere , the compass card of a direct reading magnetic\ncompass will turn ;\n",
        "answer": "clockwise giving an apparent turn toward the north.\n",
        "choiceone": "anti-clockwise giving an apparent turn toward the north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "anti-clockwise giving an apparent turn toward the south.\n",
        "choicethree": "clockwise giving an apparent turn toward the south.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aircraft on a westerly heading on the northern hemisphere accelerates , the effect of the acceleration error causes the\nmagnetic compass to ;\n",
        "answer": "indicate a turn towards the north.\n",
        "choiceone": "indicate a turn towards the south.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to turn faster than the actual turning rate of the aircraft.\n",
        "choicethree": "lag behind the turning rate of the aircraft.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When crossing the International Date Line , which of the following statements can be considered correct ?\n",
        "answer": "the date will increase crossing on a westerly heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "the date will increase crossing on a easterly heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "when crossing from a west to east longitude the date will stay the same.\n",
        "choicethree": "there will be no change to the date.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When decelerating on a westerly heading in the Northern hemisphere , the compass card of a direct reading magnetic\ncompass will turn ;\n",
        "answer": "clockwise giving an apparent turn toward the south.\n",
        "choiceone": "clockwise giving an apparent turn towards the north.\n",
        "choicetwo": "anti-clockwise giving an apparent turn towards the south.\n",
        "choicethree": "anti-clockwise giving an apparent turn towards the north.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flying on a westerly great circle track in the Southern Hemisphere you will ;\n",
        "answer": "experience an increase in the value of true track.\n",
        "choiceone": "always have the rhumb line track between the departure point and the destination to the left of your great\n circle track.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fly a spiral and finally end up at the south pole.\n",
        "choicethree": "experience a decrease in the value of true track.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the magnetic compass most effective ?\n",
        "answer": "About midway between the magnetic poles.\n",
        "choiceone": "In the region of the magnetic North Pole.\n",
        "choicetwo": "On the geographic equator.\n",
        "choicethree": "In the region of the magnetic South Pole.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annexes 061-2305A and 061-2305B )\n Annex 061-2305A , 061-2305B\n When it is 0600 Standard Time in Queensland ( Australia ) the Standard Time in Hawaii ( USA ) is ;\n",
        "answer": "1000\n",
        "choiceone": "1200\n",
        "choicetwo": "0600\n",
        "choicethree": "0200\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annexes 061-2305A and 061-2305B )\n Annex 061-2305A , 061-2305B\n When it is 1000 Standard Time in Kuwait , the Standard Time in Algeria is ;\n",
        "answer": "0800\n",
        "choiceone": "0700\n",
        "choicetwo": "1200\n",
        "choicethree": "1300\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When proceeding , on a given date , along a parallel towards the East , the moment of sunrise will occur one hour earlier\nevery 15\u00b0 difference in longitude when it is expressed in ;\n",
        "answer": "UTC.\n",
        "choiceone": "LAT ( local apparent time ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "LMT.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stadard Time.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the time is 1400 LMT at 90\u00b0 West , it is ;\n",
        "answer": "1200 LMT at 120\u00b0 West. \u00c7\u00f6z\u00fcm ;\n",
        "choiceone": "0600 LMT at the Prime meridian. 90\u00b0W ile 120\u00b0W aras\u0131nda 30\u00b0lik boylam fark\u0131 vard\u0131r. G\u00fcne\u015f her 4\n",
        "choicetwo": "1400 LMT at 90\u00b0 East. dakikada 1 boylam tarayaca\u011f\u0131ndan ; 30 x 4 = 120 dakika = 2 saat ,\n",
        "choicethree": "1000 LMT at 60\u00b0 West. 120\u00b0W daha bat\u0131da olan bir boylam oldu\u011fundan 2 saat geride olacakt\u0131r.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the time is 2000 UTC , it is ;\n",
        "answer": "1400 LMT at 90\u00b0 West. 90\u00b0W bat\u0131da olan bir boylam oldu\u011fundan LMT de\u011feri UTC \u2013 6\n",
        "choiceone": "0800 LMT at the Prime meridian. \u00c7\u00f6z\u00fcm ;\n",
        "choicetwo": "2400 LMT at 120\u00b0 West. 90\u00b0W ile 000\u00b0E/W aras\u0131nda 90\u00b0lik boylam fark\u0131 vard\u0131r. G\u00fcne\u015f her 4\n",
        "choicethree": "1200 LMT at 60\u00b0 East. dakikada 1 boylam tarayaca\u011f\u0131ndan ; 90 x 4 = 360 dakika = 6 saat ,\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When turning right from 330\u00b0 ( C ) to 040\u00b0 ( C ) in the northern hemisphere , the reading of a direct reading magnetic\ncompass will ;\n",
        "answer": "under-indicate the turn and liquid swirl will increase the effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "under-indicate the turn and liquid swirl will decrease the effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "over-indicate the turn and liquid swirl will increase the effect.\n",
        "choicethree": "over-indicate the turn and liquid swirl will decrease the effect.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where and when are the IRS positions updated ?\n",
        "answer": "Only on the ground during the alignment procedure.\n",
        "choiceone": "IRS positions are updated by pressing the \u201cTake-off/ Go-around\u201d button at the start of the take-off roll.\n",
        "choicetwo": "During flight IRS positions are automatically updated by the FMC.\n",
        "choicethree": "Updating is normally carried out by the crew when over-flying a known position ( VOR station or NDB ).\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where on a Direct Mercator projection is the chart convergency correct compared to the earth convergency ?\n",
        "answer": "At the equator.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the two parallels of tangency.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At the poles.\n",
        "choicethree": "All over the chart.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12621A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12621A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a compulsory reporting point ?\n",
        "answer": "7\n",
        "choiceone": "15\n",
        "choicetwo": "6\n",
        "choicethree": "8\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12621A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12621A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a Control Zone boundary ?\n",
        "answer": "2\n",
        "choiceone": "3\n",
        "choicetwo": "5\n",
        "choicethree": "4\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12621A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12621A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a Flight Information Region ( FIR ) boundary ?\n",
        "answer": "1\n",
        "choiceone": "3\n",
        "choicetwo": "5\n",
        "choicethree": "4\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a group of lighted obstacles ?\n",
        "answer": "11\n",
        "choiceone": "12\n",
        "choicetwo": "10\n",
        "choicethree": "9\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a group of unlighted obstacles ?\n",
        "answer": "10\n",
        "choiceone": "9\n",
        "choicetwo": "12\n",
        "choicethree": "13\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a lighted obstacle ?\n",
        "answer": "9\n",
        "choiceone": "11\n",
        "choicetwo": "10\n",
        "choicethree": "12\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a lightship ?\n",
        "answer": "16\n",
        "choiceone": "10\n",
        "choicetwo": "14\n",
        "choicethree": "12\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12621A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12621A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a non-compulsory reporting point ?\n",
        "answer": "6\n",
        "choiceone": "7\n",
        "choicetwo": "8\n",
        "choicethree": "15\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12621A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12621A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a Way-point ?\n",
        "answer": "8\n",
        "choiceone": "6\n",
        "choicetwo": "15\n",
        "choicethree": "7\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates an aeronautical ground light ?\n",
        "answer": "15\n",
        "choiceone": "10\n",
        "choicetwo": "14\n",
        "choicethree": "16\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates an exceptionally high lighted obstacle ?\n",
        "answer": "13\n",
        "choiceone": "14\n",
        "choicetwo": "10\n",
        "choicethree": "12\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates an exceptionally high unlighted obstacle?\n",
        "answer": "12\n",
        "choiceone": "11\n",
        "choicetwo": "9\n",
        "choicethree": "10\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12621A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12621A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates an uncontrolled route ?\n",
        "answer": "4\n",
        "choiceone": "5\n",
        "choicetwo": "2\n",
        "choicethree": "3\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates an unlighted obstacle ?\n",
        "answer": "8\n",
        "choiceone": "10\n",
        "choicetwo": "12\n",
        "choicethree": "11\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12621A to 061-12638A )\n Annex 061-12621A\n Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates the boundary of advisory airspace ?\n",
        "answer": "5\n",
        "choiceone": "4\n",
        "choicetwo": "3\n",
        "choicethree": "2\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which component of the B737-400 Flight Management System ( FMS ) is used to enter flight plan routeing and performance\nparameters ?\n",
        "answer": "Multi-Function Control Display Unit.\n",
        "choiceone": "Inertial Reference System.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight Director System.\n",
        "choicethree": "Flight Management Computer.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which definition describes best the notion \u201cPoles\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "The Poles are the points of intersection between the earth\u2019s axis and the surface of the earth.\n",
        "choiceone": "The Poles are the points on the surface of the earth where gravity acts under an angle of exactly 90\u00ba.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The Poles are the points on the surface of the earth which have the same distance to all points of the ecliptic.\n",
        "choicethree": "The Poles are the points of intersection between the surface of the earth and the extended line joining the star\n Polaris with the centre of the earth.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which definition of the equator is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The equator is a great circle with its plane perpendicular to the earth rotational axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "The equator is a great circle with its plane parallel to the earth rotational axis.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The equator is a small circle with its plane perpendicular to the earth rotational axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "The equator is a small circle , the plan is parallel to the earth rotational axis.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 12 )\n Image 12\n Which figure in the Appendix represents the geocentric latitude of position P , which is situated above the surface of the\nellipsoid ?\n",
        "answer": "figure B.\n",
        "choiceone": "figure A.\n",
        "choicetwo": "figure D.\n",
        "choicethree": "figure C.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 13 )\n Image 13\n Which figure in the Appendix represents the geographic latitude of position P , which is situated above the surface of the\nellipsoid ?\n",
        "answer": "figure A.\n",
        "choiceone": "figure B.\n",
        "choicetwo": "figure D.\n",
        "choicethree": "figure C.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which FMC/CDU page normally appears on initial power application to the B737-400 Electronic Flight Instrument System ?\n",
        "answer": "IDENT\n",
        "choiceone": "PERF INIT\n",
        "choicetwo": "INITIAL\n",
        "choicethree": "POS INIT\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the highest latitude listed below at which the sun will rise above the horizon and set every day ?\n",
        "answer": "62\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "68\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "66\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "72\u00b0\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12620A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n Which of the aeronautical chart symbols indicates a basic , non-specified , navigation aid ?\n",
        "answer": "1\n",
        "choiceone": "6\n",
        "choicetwo": "2\n",
        "choicethree": "3\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12620A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n Which of the aeronautical chart symbols indicates a TACAN ?\n",
        "answer": "6\n",
        "choiceone": "7\n",
        "choicetwo": "2\n",
        "choicethree": "1\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12620A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n Which of the aeronautical chart symbols indicates a VOR ?\n",
        "answer": "3\n",
        "choiceone": "2\n",
        "choicetwo": "5\n",
        "choicethree": "6\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12620A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n Which of the aeronautical chart symbols indicates a VOR/DME ?\n",
        "answer": "5\n",
        "choiceone": "2\n",
        "choicetwo": "7\n",
        "choicethree": "6\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12620A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n Which of the aeronautical chart symbols indicates a VORTAC ?\n",
        "answer": "7\n",
        "choiceone": "1\n",
        "choicetwo": "3\n",
        "choicethree": "6\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question refer to annex 061-12614A to 061-12620A )\n Annex 061-12614A\n Which of the aeronautical chart symbols indicates an NDB ?\n",
        "answer": "2\n",
        "choiceone": "4\n",
        "choicetwo": "3\n",
        "choicethree": "6\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following alternatives is correct when you cross the international date line ?\n",
        "answer": "The date will increase if you are crossing on a westerly heading.\n",
        "choiceone": "The date will increase if you are crossing on a easterly heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "If you are crossing from westerly longitude to easterly longitude the date will remain the same.\n",
        "choicethree": "The date will always be the same.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following correctly lists the order of available selections of the Mode Selector switches of an inertial reference\nsystem ( IRS ) mode panel ?\n",
        "answer": "OFF - ALIGN - NAV - ATT\n",
        "choiceone": "OFF - STBY - ALIGN - NAV\n",
        "choicetwo": "OFF - ALIGN - ATT - NAV\n",
        "choicethree": "OFF - ON - ALIGN - NAV\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is an occasion for carrying out a compass swing on a Direct Reading Compass ?\n",
        "answer": "After an aircraft has passed through a severe electrical storm , or has been struck by lightning.\n",
        "choiceone": "Before an aircraft goes on any flight that involves a large change of magnetic latitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Whenever an aircraft carries a large freight load regardless of its content.\n",
        "choicethree": "After any of the aircraft radio equipment has been changed due to unserviceability.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Which of the following lists all the aeronautical chart symbols shown at position N5150.4 W00829.7 ?\n",
        "answer": "civil airport , VOR , DME , compulsory reporting point\n",
        "choiceone": "VOR , DME , NDB , ILS\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR , DME , NDB , compulsory reporting point\n",
        "choicethree": "civil airport , VOR , non-compulsory reporting point\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Which of the following lists all the aeronautical chart symbols shown at position N5211 W00705 ?\n",
        "answer": "civil airport , NDB\n",
        "choiceone": "civil airport , ILS\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR , NDB\n",
        "choicethree": "NDB , ILS\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Which of the following lists all the aeronautical chart symbols shown at position N5318.0 W00626.9 ?\n",
        "answer": "military airport , VOR , DME\n",
        "choiceone": "military airport , VOR , NDB\n",
        "choicetwo": "civil airport , VOR , DME\n",
        "choicethree": "VOR: DME , danger area\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Which of the following lists all the aeronautical chart symbols shown at position N5318.1 W00856.5 ?\n",
        "answer": "civil airport , NDB , DME , non-compulsory reporting point\n",
        "choiceone": "civil airport , VOR , DME , non-compulsory reporting point\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR , DME , NDB , compulsory reporting point\n",
        "choicethree": "VOR , DME , NDB , compulsory reporting point\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A )\n Annex 061-12549A to 061-12613A\n Which of the following lists all the aeronautical chart symbols shown at position N5416.7 W00836.0 ?\n",
        "answer": "civil airport , NDB , DME , compulsory reporting point\n",
        "choiceone": "civil airport , VOR , DME , non-compulsory reporting point\n",
        "choicetwo": "VOR: DME , NDB , non-compulsory reporting point\n",
        "choicethree": "VOR: DME , NDB , compulsory reporting point\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following lists the first three pages of the FMC/CDU normally used on initial start-up of the B737-400\nElectronic Flight Instrument System ?\n",
        "answer": "IDENT - POS INIT - RTE\n",
        "choiceone": "POS INIT - RTE - IDENT\n",
        "choicetwo": "IDENT - RTE - DEPARTURE\n",
        "choicethree": "POS INIT - RTE - DEPARTURE\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following lists the order of available selections on the Mode Selector switches of a 737-400 Inertial Reference\nSystem ?\n",
        "answer": "OFF - ALIGN - NAV - ATT\n",
        "choiceone": "OFF - STBY - ALIGN - NAV\n",
        "choicetwo": "OFF - ON - ALIGN - NAV\n",
        "choicethree": "OFF - ALIGN - ATT - NAV\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following lists , which compares an Inertial Reference System that utilises Ring Laser Gyroscopes ( RLG )\ninstead of conventional gyroscopes , is completely correct ?\n",
        "answer": "There is little or no \u201cspin up\u201d time and it is insensitive to gravitational ( g ) forces.\n",
        "choiceone": "There is little or no \u201cspin up\u201d time and it does not suffer from \u201clock in\u201d error.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It does not suffer from \u201clock in\u201d error and it is insensitive to gravitational ( g ) forces.\n",
        "choicethree": "The platform is kept stable relative to the earth mathematically rather than mechanically but it has a longer\n \u201cspin up\u201d time.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about hard and soft iron in relation to magnetism is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Hard iron magnetism is of a permanent nature and soft iron is a non-permanent nature.\n",
        "choiceone": "Both hard and soft iron are of a non-permanent nature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Hard iron magnetism is of a non-permanent nature and soft iron is a permanent nature.\n",
        "choicethree": "Both hard and soft iron are of a permanent nature.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the aircraft positions indicated on a triple fit Inertial Navigation System\n( INS ) / Inertial Reference System ( IRS ) on the CDU is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The positions are likely to differ because they are calculated from different sources.\n",
        "choiceone": "The positions will only differ if an error has been made when inputting the present position at the departure\n airport.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The positions will be the same because they are an average of three different positions.\n",
        "choicethree": "The positions will only differ if one of the systems has been decoupled because of a detected malfunction.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the alignment procedure for Inertial Navigation Systems ( INS ) / Inertial\nReference Systems ( IRS ) at mid-latitudes is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "INS/IRS can be aligned in either the ALIGN or NAV mode.\n",
        "choiceone": "INS/IRS can only be aligned in NAV mode.\n",
        "choicetwo": "INS/IRS can be aligned in either the ALIGN or ATT mode.\n",
        "choicethree": "INS/IRS can only be aligned in the ALIGN mode.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the loss of alignment by an Inertial Reference System ( IRS ) in flight is\ncorrect ?\n",
        "answer": "The navigation mode , including present position and ground speed outputs , is inoperative for the remainder\n of the flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is not usable in any mode and must be shut down for the rest of the flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The IRS has to be coupled to the remaining serviceable system and a realignment carried out in flight.\n",
        "choicethree": "The mode selector has to be rotated to ATT then back through ALIGN to NAV in order to obtain an in-flight\n realignment.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the operation of an Inertial Navigation System ( INS ) / Inertial Reference\nSystem ( IRS ) is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "NAV mode must be selected prior to movement of the aircraft off the gate.\n",
        "choiceone": "NAV mode must be selected on the runway just prior to take-off.\n",
        "choicetwo": "NAV mode must be selected prior to the loading of passengers and/or freight.\n",
        "choicethree": "NAV mode must be selected when the alignment procedure is commenced.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the position indicated on the Inertial Reference System ( IRS ) display is\ncorrect ?\n",
        "answer": "It is not updated once the IRS mode is set to NAV.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is updated when \u201cgo-around\u201d is selected on take-off.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The positions from the two IRSs are compared to obtain a \u201cbest position\u201d which is displayed on the IRS.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is constantly updated from information obtained by the FMC.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct concerning gyro-compassing of an inertial navigation system ( INS ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Gyro-compassing of an INS is not possible in flight because it cannot differentiate between movement\n induced and misalignment induced accelerations.\n",
        "choiceone": "Gyro-compassing of an INS is possible in flight because it can differentiate between movement induced and\n misalignment induced accelerations.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Gyro-compassing of an INS is possible in flight because it cannot differentiate between movement induced\n and misalignment induced accelerations.\n",
        "choicethree": "Gyro-compassing of an INS is not possible in flight because it can differentiate between movement induced\n and misalignment induced accelerations.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct concerning the effect of turning errors on a direct reading compass ?\n",
        "answer": "Turning errors are greatest on north/south headings , and are greatest at high latitudes.\n",
        "choiceone": "Turning errors are greatest on east/west headings , and are greatest at high latitudes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Turning errors are greatest on north/south headings , and are least at high latitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "Turning errors are greatest on east/west headings , and are least at high latitudes.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following variables affect deviation ?\n 1. magnetic latitude\n 2. aircraft heading\n 3. aircraft altitude\n 4. aircraft electronic equipment\n",
        "answer": "1 , 2 and 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 , 2 and 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 and 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 and 3.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following , concerning great circles on a Direct Mercator chart , is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "With the exception of meridians and the equator , they are curves concave to the equator.\n",
        "choiceone": "They are all curves concave to the equator.\n",
        "choicetwo": "They approximate to straight lines between the standard parallels.\n",
        "choicethree": "They are all curves convex to the equator.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following describes the appearance of rhumb lines , except meridians , on a Polar Stereographic chart ?\n",
        "answer": "Curves concave to the Pole.\n",
        "choiceone": "Straight lines.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Curves convex to the Pole.\n",
        "choicethree": "Ellipses around the Pole.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following statements is correct concerning the appearance of great circles , with the exception of meridians\n, on a Polar Stereographic chart whose tangency is at the pole ?\n",
        "answer": "The higher the latitude the closer they approximate to a straight line.\n",
        "choiceone": "Any straight line is a great circle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "They are curves convex to the Pole.\n",
        "choicethree": "They are complex curves that can be convex and/or concave to the Pole.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about meridians is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "A meridian and its anti-meridian form a complete great circle.\n",
        "choiceone": "All meridians are parallel to the Meridian of Greenwhich.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The plane of a meridian is parallel to the equator.\n",
        "choicethree": "A meridian is a complete great circle of 360\u00ba.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about ST is true ?\n",
        "answer": "Standard time is determined by the goverment of the appropriate state and does not necessarily follow the\n borders of 15\u00ba wide longitude zones.\n",
        "choiceone": "The standard time at 125\u00baW is UTC 8 h 20 m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Standard time is the time that is determinedby division of the longitude by 15 and rounding off the answer to\n the nearest integer.\n",
        "choicethree": "In all cases the standard times at Western longitudes are slow on and at Eastern longitudes fast on UTC.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about the duration of daylight is true ?\n",
        "answer": "Close to the equinoxes the influence of latitude on the duration of daylight is at its smallest.\n",
        "choiceone": "On September 10th the duration of daylight is longer on the Southern Hemisphere than on the Northern\n Hemisphere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In summer the length of the period of daylight decreases with increasing latitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "Close to the solstices the influence of latitude on the duration of daylight is at its smallest.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about the orbit of the earth is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The orbit of the earth around the sun is an ellipse with the sun at one of the foci.\n",
        "choiceone": "The orbit of the earth around the sun is an ellipse with the sun at a point halfway between the two foci.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The orbit of the earth is a circle with the sun at a point next to its centre.\n",
        "choicethree": "The orbit of the earth around the sun is a circle with the sun at its centre.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The earth is one of the planets which are all moving in elliptical orbit around the sun.\n",
        "choiceone": "The Solar System consists of the sun , planets and stars.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The sun moves in an elliptical orbit around the Earth.\n",
        "choicethree": "The planets move around the sun like all stars of the Solar System.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct about the apparent solar day ?\n",
        "answer": "The apparent solar day is the period between two successive transits of the true sun through the same\n meridian.\n",
        "choiceone": "The duration of the apparent solar day is constant throughout a year due to the constant velocity of the earth\n in its orbit around the sun.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The duration of the apparent solar day is constant throughout a year due to the constant rotational speed of\n the earth around its axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "The apparent solar day is the period between two successive transits of the mean sun through the same\n meridian.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct about the scale of a Lambert projection ?\n",
        "answer": "The scale reaches its minimum value at the parallel of origin.\n",
        "choiceone": "The scale reaches its minimum value at the standard parallels.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The scale reaches its maximum value at the parallel of origin.\n",
        "choicethree": "The scale reaches its maximum value at the standard parallels.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct about the scale of a Polar Stereographic projection of the Northern polar area ?\n",
        "answer": "The scale reaches its minimum value at the North pole.\n",
        "choiceone": "The scale reaches its maximum value at the 45\u00baN.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The scale reaches its minimum value at the equator.\n",
        "choicethree": "The scale reaches its maximum value at the North pole.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true ?\n",
        "answer": "The declination of the sun and the latitude of the observer will affect the duration of civil twilight.\n",
        "choiceone": "Civil twilight at the equator lasts longer than at 60\u00baN or 60\u00baS because the radius of the equator is larger than\n the radius of the 60\u00ba parallel.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Only the declination of the sun will affect the duration of civil twilight.\n",
        "choicethree": "The duration of the civil twilight on 21st of March and on 23rd of September is equal at all places on Earth\n independent of latitude.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is true about the parallel of origin of a conformal chart ?\n",
        "answer": "The parallel of origin is the parallel at which the scale reaches its minimum value.\n",
        "choiceone": "The parallel of origin together with the standard parallel(s) , are the only parallels at which the chart is\n conformal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The parallel of origin is the only parallel at which the chart is conformal.\n",
        "choicethree": "The parallel of origin is the parallel at which the scale reaches its maximum value.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement regarding the apparent sun and the mean sun is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The apparent sun is the visible sun , the mean sun is a fictitious sun.\n",
        "choiceone": "The apparent sun is a fictitious sun coupled to UTC , the mean sun is related to the local mean time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The mean sun moves along the ecliptic , the apparent sun along the celestial equator.\n",
        "choicethree": "The apparent sun is not important for naviation as difference in time with the mean sun is maximal 4 seconds.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With an increase in magnetic latitude there will be a decrease in the ;\n",
        "answer": "directive force.\n",
        "choiceone": "vetical component of the Earth\u2019s magnetic field.\n",
        "choicetwo": "total magnetic force of the Earth\u2019s magnetic field.\n",
        "choicethree": "angle of dip.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to an inertial navigation system ( INS ) , the initial great circle track between computer inserted waypoints\nwill be displayed when the control display unit ( CDU ) is selected to ;\n",
        "answer": "DSRTK/STS\n",
        "choiceone": "XTK/TKE\n",
        "choicetwo": "TK/GS\n",
        "choicethree": "HDG/DA\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to inertial navigation systems , a TAS input is ;\n",
        "answer": "required to provide a W/V read out.\n",
        "choiceone": "not required.\n",
        "choicetwo": "required for Polar navigation.\n",
        "choicethree": "required for rhumb line navigation.\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are departing from an airport which has an elevation of 1500 ft. The QNH is 1003 hPa. 15 NM away there is a\nwaypoint you are required to pass at an altitude of 7500 ft. Given a groundspeed of 120 kt , what is the minimum rate of climb ?\n",
        "answer": "800 ft/min\n",
        "choiceone": "530 ft/min\n",
        "choicetwo": "730 ft/min\n",
        "choicethree": "870 ft/min\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft. The QNH is 1013 hPa. 10 NM away there is a waypoint\nyou are required to pass at an altitude of 7500 ft. Given a groundspeed of 100 kt , what is the minimum rate of climb ?\n",
        "answer": "920 ft/min\n",
        "choiceone": "1080 ft/min\n",
        "choicetwo": "750 ft/min\n",
        "choicethree": "590 ft/min\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "You are tracking the 200\u00b0 radial inbound to a VOR and your true heading is 010\u00b0. At the VOR you then track the 090\u00b0 radial\noutbound and are showing a heading of 080\u00b0M The variation is +5\u00b0 and the TAS is 240 kts. What is the wind ( \u00b0T ) has affected the\naircraft ?\n",
        "answer": "310\u00ba / 65\n",
        "choiceone": "300\u00ba / 50\n",
        "choicetwo": "330\u00ba / 50\n",
        "choicethree": "320\u00ba / 55\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Your on an airfield elevation 2000 ft , QNH 1003. You want to climb to FL50 , your rate of climb is 1000 ft/min , your TAS\nis 100 and you have a headwind of 20. What is the distance it takes to get to FL50 ?\n",
        "answer": "3.6 NM\n",
        "choiceone": "4.0 NM\n",
        "choicetwo": "4.4 NM\n",
        "choicethree": "4.8 NM\n",
        "source": "061-general-navigation-696-soru_compress-2.txt"
    }
]